<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/team/</link><description>Recent content in Team on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Happy 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2023-happy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2023-happy/</guid><description>As we enter a new year, I want to reflect on the role that software has played in my life. From the early days of my career to now, software has been a constant presence and something that I have dedicated countless hours to as both an engineer and project manager. I have put in over 10,000 hours of work in this field, and it has become an integral part of my existence.</description></item><item><title>2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</guid><description>Successfully went through 2022, a year that we might say - a new record: team reached highest growth record, kickstarted community engagement, home, compliance training &amp;amp; individual development are speeding up, and a whole new place to call Dwarves.
We’ve achieved to this year’s resolution: A team that cares about how to build software right and can teach others on that.
TEAM GROWTH 30 New Team Members 2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of The Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-of-the-year/</guid><description>Dwarves of The Year 2022 - Wins to Celebrate It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, but we&amp;rsquo;ve finally made it to 2022 and what a year it&amp;rsquo;s been for our team of Dwarves. Countless hours of hard work and it&amp;rsquo;s all paid off with our big wins of the year. Honored for all and huge congratulations for our Dwarves of 2022.
A total of ~$18,000 awarded and rewarded by $ICY - Dwarves official token, with a few names appearing several times.</description></item><item><title>The Inner Circle</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</guid><description>The concept of an &amp;ldquo;inner circle&amp;rdquo; within a company is not a new one, and at Dwarves, a software company founded by a group of engineers, this idea holds a significant value. Starting from scratch, the company has always placed emphasis on being surrounded by individuals who can efficiently ship software and don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on unimportant tasks. These individuals are highly respected and valued within the company, as they play a crucial role in the development and success of projects.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-summit-engineering-a-good-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-summit-engineering-a-good-time/</guid><description>Dwarves Summit 2022: Engineering a good time We don’t treat team bonding the common way, because we understand our engineers. Most of our engineers don’t want running and getting sweaty on the beach for “team-building” activities, or pretending to smile in front of the travel agent’s camera.
This was our first company get-together after 2 years of COVID. It was organized in ways that we can all look back to the progress we’ve made, pat ourselves on the back, have a blast together, and look forward to an even better 2023.</description></item><item><title>Road To 100</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</guid><description>2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves. A notable highlight, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to have more. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to find people that has the same value. It takes true &amp;amp; solid seeks.
On our way to meet the 81th and onward, we&amp;rsquo;re launching a mechanism to help us find like-minded DNAs, and co-create our future using tech.
The Dwarves Referral Program We usually hire and keep the quality bar. The Dwarves are encouraged to recommend friends they think might be a good match for the team.</description></item><item><title>The Next Leading Chairs</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</guid><description>OUR VISION FOR GROWTH Last Jan 2020, we got the chance to celebrate our first milestone - Dwarves Foundation reached 5 years old. The remarkable moment contained the proudest thing we delivered.
**Remote Culture - **That enables us to make things work without any physical constraints. We were able to focus on what we value: Knowledge and People. To name a few: The Handbook** **- To demonstrate our culture, the future we pursue and what portrays the Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>May 2022 All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-may-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-may-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>FOUNDATION Project Allocation We concluded the partnership with Relay and Eklipse. It has been a fun (and wild) ride for some of you. New resources are being allocated to help balance the current workload of active projects. If you need to discuss your workload or seek more room for project work, please help ping Giang or Nikki.
Our view on Blockchain Got a quick chat with Ngoc Thanh, our Sr.</description></item><item><title>December All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-december-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-december-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>Moving with Blockchain We shift our focus to real deals.
Meanwhile, #blockchain #web3 channels are there for the Dwarves to learn &amp;amp; exchange their knowns. Grab your seat.
The teammates also propose to join blockchain projects. We’re happy onboard Hien, Tu and Ngoc Mai on Spike Inu and Eklipse - and actively seek more chances for our teammates.
Selective in Project Decision It’s a promise of bigger clients &amp;amp; better team deployment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of 2021</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-dwarves-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-dwarves-of-the-year/</guid><description>Dwarves of 2021 - We met at last ♡ Apart from the voting result from the team of each title, we also have the Honorable Mention and Client Endorsed - selected by the team leads, as we want to honor all of the hard work.
You can find the voting details here. The final result was close, since you’re all awesome!
Let’s all welcome our Dwarves of 2021 🛠</description></item></channel></rss>