<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Changelog on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/</link><description>Recent content in Changelog on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community Changelog \#162 - Feb</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/162-xxxx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/162-xxxx/</guid><description>Community Changelog #162 - Feb - Latest Findings, Tech Market Report, Partner network, Research Topics, and Dwarves’ Reward System in. Another month has passed, it&amp;rsquo;s time for another monthly recap of what we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Hope everyone is ready for all the cool things below.
title section sub-section Intro Stay ahead in tech Road to an even greater knowledge base. With around 40 topics covering the most promising technologies to grow our expertise.</description></item><item><title>What's New in February 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</guid><description>Reporting tech signals - Latest findings on Serverless Computing, AI &amp;amp; ML, FinOps and CyberSecurity Research Topics 2024 - 40 topics on the most promising technologies. Dwarves&amp;rsquo; Reward System - Developing our community reward system Calling for Partners - One of the rare event where Dwarves and community members gather. Reporting tech signals Every month we watch tech trends closely to depict which ones have high potential, and can be part of our growing tech stack.</description></item><item><title>What's New in January 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In this first month of 2024, we kept tap of what&amp;rsquo;s brewing in the tech market, while reviewing what we went through in 2023.
Reporting tech signals - Updates on the stage of React, Rust, AI, Cybersecurity, Rust.</description></item><item><title>2023 Dec + title</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-december-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-december-2023/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In December, we launched our Consulting Team, released our finding on tech trends, and last but not least, got everyone ready to wrap up 2023.
Reporting tech signals - We stay ahead by monitoring high-potential trends in tech.</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-november-2023/</guid><description>Last November, we kicked off the Labs team, introduced Salary Advance for the Dwarves, upgraded note.d.foundation, supported Golang meetup, and demonstrated craftsmanship through various case studies and demos.
Launching Labs team - Dwarves R&amp;amp;D team is officially in operation. Monthly top performers - The top 5 high-performing members get rewards and NFT badges. NFT badges can be staked to earn shares of the company. Salary Advance - Dwarves&amp;rsquo; team members now can get an advance of their monthly salary in case of emergency.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>2023 Happy xxx</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/happy-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/happy-2023/</guid><description>As we enter a new year, I want to reflect on the role that software has played in my life. From the early days of my career to now, software has been a constant presence and something that I have dedicated countless hours to as both an engineer and project manager. I have put in over 10,000 hours of work in this field, and it has become an integral part of my existence.</description></item><item><title>2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</guid><description>Successfully went through 2022, a year that we might say - a new record: team reached highest growth record, kickstarted community engagement, home, compliance training &amp;amp; individual development are speeding up, and a whole new place to call Dwarves.
We’ve achieved to this year’s resolution: A team that cares about how to build software right and can teach others on that.
TEAM GROWTH 30 New Team Members **[2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves](https://github.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of The Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</guid><description>Dwarves of The Year 2022 - Wins to Celebrate It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, but we&amp;rsquo;ve finally made it to 2022 and what a year it&amp;rsquo;s been for our team of Dwarves. Countless hours of hard work and it&amp;rsquo;s all paid off with our big wins of the year. Honored for all and huge congratulations for our Dwarves of 2022.
A total of ~$18,000 awarded and rewarded by ****$ICY - Dwarves official token, with a few names appearing several times.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</guid><description>Dwarves Summit 2022: Engineering a good time. We don’t treat team bonding the common way, because we understand our engineers. Most of our engineers don’t want running and getting sweaty on the beach for “team-building” activities, or pretending to smile in front of the travel agent’s camera.
This was our first company get-together after 2 years of COVID. It was organized in ways that we can all look back to the progress we’ve made, pat ourselves on the back, have a blast together, and look forward to an even better 2023.</description></item><item><title>Road To 100</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</guid><description>2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves. A notable highlight, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to have more. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to find people that has the same value. It takes true &amp;amp; solid seeks.
On our way to meet the 81th and onward, we&amp;rsquo;re launching a mechanism to help us find like-minded DNAs, and co-create our future using tech.
The Dwarves Referral Program We usually hire and keep the quality bar. The Dwarves are encouraged to recommend friends they think might be a good match for the team.</description></item><item><title>May 2022 All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>FOUNDATION Project Allocation
We concluded the partnership with Relay and Eklipse. It has been a fun (and wild) ride for some of you. New resources are being allocated to help balance the current workload of active projects. If you need to discuss your workload or seek more room for project work, please help ping Giang or Nikki.
Our view on Blockchain
Got a quick chat with Ngoc Thanh, our Sr.</description></item><item><title>January Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/january-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/january-updates/</guid><description>Project Highlights MStation as our latest blockchain-based project
It’s the first BSCS Metaverse blockchain game on Binance Smart Chain (BSC). Players can summon characters, complete daily mining missions, protect the MStation, loot rare items to play and earn.
We get to deploy a full team for this project, consist of 6 people, with Khai Le as part time PM and Ngọc Thành as Team Lead.
In general, we’re getting multiple upselling requests which means we need more people to join our team.</description></item><item><title>December All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/december-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/december-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>Moving with Blockchain We shift our focus to real deals.
Meanwhile, #blockchain #web3 channels are there for the Dwarves to learn &amp;amp; exchange their knowns. Grab your seat.
The teammates also propose to join blockchain projects. We’re happy onboard Hien, Tu and Ngoc Mai on Spike Inu and Eklipse - and actively seek more chances for our teammates.
Selective in Project Decision It’s a promise of bigger clients &amp;amp; better team deployment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of 2021</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-2021/</guid><description>Dwarves of 2021 - We met at last ♡ Apart from the voting result from the team of each title, we also have the Honorable Mention and Client Endorsed - selected by the team leads, as we want to honor all of the hard work.
You can find the voting details here. The final result was close, since you’re all awesome!
Let’s all welcome our Dwarves of 2021 🛠</description></item><item><title>2021 July Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-july-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-july-updates/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re closing July with some notable highlights. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through them ✌️
🚨 *Note: Covid situation is getting worse. Stay safe. 🦠
*The pandemic is going stronger than ever. There has been over 100k internal cases over the country til now. Take good care of you and your beloved ones. We hope everyone can stay safe.
Finish the shipment for our WFH station We&amp;rsquo;ve finished the shipment for all the WFH gears.</description></item><item><title>2020 In A Flashback</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2020-in-a-flashback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2020-in-a-flashback/</guid><description>Wrapping up 2019 with the first 5th-year milestone, many ideas popped up for the next steps. Heading to a new decade means we get to wrap up the old and in with the new. For us, the utmost target is to focus on territory expansion and team bootstrapping. Reinvest on the current foundation. Make it stable and make it impactful.
It handed us the chance to come up with more cool stuff.</description></item><item><title>Looking Back 2019</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/looking-back-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/looking-back-2019/</guid><description>Another year has gone by. And we just celebrated the 5th year that we survived all the challenges. Everyone was facing their own, but I have seen many of you reaching new stages and achieve new targets.
We have been growing up together. As for your recall, end of 2018, we were about 30s. End of this year, we are about 50s. End of 2018, we were young and inexperienced. End of this year, we are just inexperienced (j/k).</description></item><item><title>2018 Wrapping Up</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2018-wrapping-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2018-wrapping-up/</guid><description>2018 was the memorable year with lots of achievements.
We adapted the new team structure.
We defined things we value and live that culture tediously.
We moved to new office. We welcomed the new dwarves to join us.
We scaled up from 15 to 30ish with all the smart people gathering around and commit to the dream of building our first global software company.
We learned how to do things right and started using it to help deliver quality software.</description></item></channel></rss>