<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>people on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/people/</link><description>Recent content in people on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Growth Is Our Universal Language</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</guid><description>At Dwarves, the core team live and breathe growth. We believe that growth is our universal language, and we&amp;rsquo;re always striving to improve ourselves, both personally and professionally. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a job for us; it&amp;rsquo;s a way of life. We&amp;rsquo;re hustlers with an extra hat, always pushing ourselves to be better and earn more.
Every time we hire, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for like-minded individuals who share our growth mindset. We want to be with people who are willing to challenge themselves and reach new heights.</description></item><item><title>Red Flags</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</guid><description>These red flags are things we don’t want to see in our peeps. Even when you think they are improper, don’t waste your time with a wrong group of people.
Negative attitude The employee may exhibit a negative attitude towards their work, colleagues, or the company. They may also show signs of disengagement, lack of motivation, lack of integrity or unwillingness to learn.
Incompatibility** **The employee may not fit in with the company culture or may have a personality clash with other team members.</description></item><item><title>Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</guid><description>Getting Started This is a part from our study how to recognize people traits at the first sight. This guide is made to help HRs or Project Lead have a quick view of potential candidates and/or new teammates personality. Working with nature is more productive than working against it.
No personality type is inherently better or more desirable than another in general. This reference is applied to the tech industry only.</description></item><item><title>A Tips Of Hiring Dont</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</guid><description>Many companies out there get lured by the vision of &amp;ldquo;scaling up&amp;rdquo;. An unwritten rule of &amp;rsquo;the more man we have, the better output we create&amp;rsquo;. But no, hiring with no motivation only leads to one thing: A waste of resource.
Hire without plan bored talent people out. There&amp;rsquo;s no good to put people in a place where they can&amp;rsquo;t create any impact. And we? We tend to fall for creating unnecessary job, which results in a waste of money and training resource.</description></item><item><title>How People Matter Should Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-people-matter-should-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-people-matter-should-work/</guid><description>We get to read many articles these days that states &amp;lsquo;People are the Core of the Business&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;Why People are the Key to Success&amp;rsquo;, or something like that. Something that polishes the importance of human to the company. Something that emphasizes how HR should do their best to nurture the talents.
But here&amp;rsquo;s the funny thing. Most of those talks drive the audience back to tips. How to make people happy.</description></item><item><title>Hiring For Operations Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</guid><description>Operations is a very sensitive area of the company, so be very picky. A great ops person can dramatically improve the way your company works and make your life a lot easier
Operations is operations, no matter the industry
Operations problems are almost the same everywhere (in ultra-specialized and regulated industries we just surround ourselves with specialists and attorneys). Industry experience is helpful, but not as much as you think</description></item><item><title>Traits To Assess During An Interview</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/traits-to-assess-during-an-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/traits-to-assess-during-an-interview/</guid><description>GRIT: Look for a time the candidate wanted something so badly, they were unstoppable in pursuing it. Or a time they overcame an obstacle. RIGOR: Ask candidates to tell you about a time they used data to make a decision. Look for details about the complexity of the data and how the thinking happened, rather than focusing on the right answer IMPACT: Have your candidate tell you about a time they had a measurable (read: quantitative) impact on a job or an organization.</description></item><item><title>Types Of Employees</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/types-of-employees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/types-of-employees/</guid><description>There are 2 types of employees:
There are employees who think of the company like a job. They come in, they work hard, and they do their job. Some excel at doing their job. But ultimately, it’s a job. They want to make sure they’re fairly compensated for their work, and have interesting projects to work on. As long as they believe those things are in balance and the compensation arbitrage they can get by going to another company is within a certain bound, they’re stable and stay.</description></item><item><title>Hiring Approach</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-approach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-approach/</guid><description>Philosophy Hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. Company culture is who you Hire, Fire &amp;amp; Promote. Short term vs. long term evaluation Values fit &amp;amp; culture fit Principles Hiring means we failed to execute and need help Startup employee effectiveness follows a power law False Positives are ok, False Negatives are not Culture is defined by who we hire The best thing you can do for employees — a perk better than foosball or free sushi — is hire only “A” players to work alongside them.</description></item><item><title>Qc Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</guid><description>1. GENERAL WORKFLOW Click on attached URL below to get more details about our general workflow:
https://www.draw.io/?lightbox=1&amp;amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;amp;edit=_blank&amp;amp;layers=1&amp;amp;nav=1#G1jtKnGw5mpmGt31dFIoDOcGxVQrqxexF7
2. ACCESS TO TESTING RESOURCES After you have a permission on Team&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive.
Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents to get resource files including:
Test Planning Template Test Cases Template Defect Summary Report Template 3. Task Assigning Flows 4. Tools Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents/Tools to get gitlab-issues-tools file
After that, Run this command in your terminal to get help:</description></item><item><title>Our Metrics For Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</guid><description>$$ P = f(r, t, c, r) $$
Performance - P Performance is a final value that will be calculated from other metrics. This value will help to indicate how good all the activities we&amp;rsquo;ve done to make the company could grow.
Metrics will be marked from the scale from 1 to 5:
1 is bad 3 is normal 5 is outstanding 1 ---- 2 ---- 3 ---- 4 ---- 5 bad good outstand Context of example</description></item><item><title>Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</guid><description>Fire quickly False positives: people who you thought fit your values, but don’t once they’re hired False negatives: people who you thought would not fit your values, but would have if you had hired them If you get some false positives anyway, the solution is to fire quickly. To follow the &amp;ldquo;No Asshole Rule&amp;rdquo;, we need to strictly apply this despite the common excuses:
for that one bad trait, he has four good traits going for him.</description></item></channel></rss>