<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bounty on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/bounty/</link><description>Recent content in bounty on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/bounty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Bounties</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</guid><description>The Dwarves bounty program is the means through which both company peeps and the community can contribute to our daily activities. This includes tasks like building internal tools, engaging in new technology research and development, or sharing knowledge session.
→ Apply for research team: open ticket in our Discord
→ To contribute: open ticket in our Discord and give @hnh a ping
Title 💰 Bounty Status PIC Function Move internal notes to note.</description></item><item><title>Community Bounty</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</guid><description>As you may know, Dwarves Discord network is where we connect with our friends, alumni, and like-minded people.
Bounties are rewards (in ICY - Dwarves’ token) given out to community members for work that encourages community developers to get more involved in the development outside of their core skills.
Who can join
We offer a platform for those seeking development work and a dynamic environment to connect with skilled developers capable of building new tools, new features.</description></item><item><title>Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</guid><description>I had my fair share of interviews. Most of them are &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; QnA sessions, and unpaid take-home projects, and coding assessments. Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s paid project is different and left a good impression on me.
The Beginning At the time, I had been looking for a new job for a while, and somehow found Dwarves, which is a rare functional programming (Elixir) shop in Vietnam. Skimming the site and what people wrote, I found the organization fascinating: they value learning and craftsmanship.</description></item></channel></rss>