<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Leadership on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/leadership/</link><description>Recent content in Leadership on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Inner Circle</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</guid><description>The concept of an &amp;ldquo;inner circle&amp;rdquo; within a company is not a new one, and at Dwarves, a software company founded by a group of engineers, this idea holds a significant value. Starting from scratch, the company has always placed emphasis on being surrounded by individuals who can efficiently ship software and don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on unimportant tasks. These individuals are highly respected and valued within the company, as they play a crucial role in the development and success of projects.</description></item><item><title>Delegation And Believe It Will Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t always make things (or everything) on our own. If that somehow truly happens, then Inc, Corp, Enterprise or Group won&amp;rsquo;t stand a chance with Freelancers.
So why delegating? At least, in business, delegation means having extra people to help distribute the stress, provides a gathered source of information, and a couple of extra hands to slap when our thought goes wrong. Delegation also gives delegator more time &amp;amp; effort to focus on other things, or sometimes just a perfect excuse to grab a beer instead of burying their heads in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Building A Solid High Performing Team</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</guid><description>Sustainable growth companies are built by teams of shining constellations rather than just several bright stars
It all starts with recruiting. Many successes and disasters start with recruiting. Recruiting is the most important job for any real leader in the company
The second step is all about the right placement of the stars in your constellation. No matter what bullshit motivational book you may have read, people do not change. Yes, people do evolve, and yes, those not capable of evolution should never become a part of your team, but for Pete’s sake, do not confuse skill evolution with personality change.</description></item><item><title>Delegate Work Not Responsibility</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</guid><description>We can bring in all the technology in the world, but if we can’t delegate properly, our companies have no chance of scaling well
Delegating work does not absolve you of responsibility. In the case of a failure, the blame is all yours. Investors will go after the CEO, even if an intern made the mistake that hurt the company. If a failure occurs due to person you delegated work to lacking skills, it is your fault you delegated work to the wrong person.</description></item></channel></rss>