<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Frontend on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/frontend/</link><description>Recent content in Frontend on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partners Network</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</guid><description>We seek for Partners, individuals and companies likewise, to develop a co-creation system driven by mutual purposes and interests.
With our average deal size at $30,000, a partner can generate at least $2,400 per project. Commission is paid from project start, every month until project end.
Partner perks Partnering with Dwarves is not just a collaboration, it’s a strategic investment in trust, network and business growth. Being our partners mean sharing opportunities, resources, connections and scaling up together.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item></channel></rss>