<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Frontend on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/frontend/</link><description>Recent content in Frontend on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partners Network</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</guid><description>We seek for Partners, individuals and companies likewise, to develop a co-creation system driven by mutual purposes and interests.
With our average deal size at $30,000, a partner can generate at least $2,400 per project. Commission is paid from project start, every month until project end.
Partner perks Partnering with Dwarves is not just a collaboration, it’s a strategic investment in trust, network and business growth. Being our partners mean sharing opportunities, resources, connections and scaling up together.</description></item><item><title>Market Report Jan 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/market-report-jan-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/market-report-jan-2024/</guid><description>Trends on our Radar Here are some of the few trends we are seeing across the industry, in our projects, as well as our community. This market report isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive, at least just yet, with certain trends not yet listed such as Design, DevEx, etc. We see a lot of promising trends and we hope that understanding what engineers and firms are becoming more passionate about that it will help us create a foundation of ideas and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Adoption Of Pnpm</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share that the Dwarves team has officially decided to switch to pnpm as our primary package management tool. After careful evaluation, we found that pnpm is widely embraced by the development community and has been successfully used by great teams at Vercel, Nx, and Chakra UI.
Previously, we were using Yarn V1 classic, but as our projects grew, we faced challenges with disk space and slow installations.</description></item><item><title>Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</guid><description>Selecting the ideal JavaScript framework can be a daunting task, particularly when faced with an abundance of highly resourceful and capable options. To make an informed decision that caters to specific project requirements, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to possess a deep understanding of various critical aspects. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll shed light on some of these essential points by conducting a comprehensive comparison of Angular, React, and Vue.
We’ve had our fair share of decision fatigue keeping up with new frameworks and choosing the right ones for the job.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</guid><description>Accelerate Project Initiation with Advanced NextJS-Boilerplate &amp;amp; React-Toolkit In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world of software development, project initiation can often be a challenging and time-consuming process, with teams facing issues such as inconsistent code quality, slow setup times, and suboptimal workflows. To address these obstacles and streamline the project initiation process, we&amp;rsquo;ve developed two powerful libraries, NextJS-Boilerplate and React-Toolkit, that can help teams get started quickly and efficiently.
Challenges in Project Initiation Software development teams often face several challenges during project initiation, including:</description></item><item><title>I18n Frontend Guideline</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</guid><description>In a front-end web application, locales are used to determine the language and geographic location of the user and to display the appropriate content to them.
When a user visits a web page, the application will first detect their locale, then use this information to determine which version of the content to display.
To support multiple languages and locales, the application needs to have the necessary content available for each locale.</description></item><item><title>React Native New Architecture</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</guid><description>📖 Introducing react-native&amp;rsquo;s new architecture changes that boost performance, bringing react-native back into the race with Flutter
Introduction of react-native 📱 React Native is a JavaScript framework for writing high-performance mobile apps that leverage iOS and Android native components. It is based on React, and is very accessible to React Web developers
After a long announcement, planned from 2018, appeared in 2020, merged in 2021 and officially published in April 2022, react-native has a new architecture that improves performance dramatically.</description></item><item><title>React 18</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</guid><description>React 18 was released in March 2022. This release focuses on performance improvements and updating the rendering engine.
React 18 Feature Quick Guide Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these updates in more detail.
Concurrency in React Concurrency is not a feature, per se. It’s a new behind-the-scenes mechanism that enables React to prepare multiple versions of your UI at the same time. A key property of Concurrent React is that rendering is interruptible.</description></item><item><title>Remix Versus Nextjs</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</guid><description>📖 A brief comparison between Remix and Next.js frameworks
Introduction of Remix Remix describes itself as:
Remix is an edge native, full-stack JavaScript framework for building modern, fast, and resilient user experiences. It unifies the client and server with web standards so you can think less about code and more about your product.
Compared to Next.js, which is one of the most React frameworks used for server-side rendering and has been there for a significant time, Remix appears as a new strong competitor.</description></item><item><title>Jotai</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/jotai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/jotai/</guid><description>Description Jotai takes an atomic approach to global React state management with a model inspired by Recoil.
What’s better about this method or library Build state by combining atoms and renders are automatically optimized based on atom dependency. This solves the extra re-render issue of React context and eliminates the need for memoization.
It scales from a simple useState replacement to an enterprise TypeScript application with complex requirements. Plus there are plenty of utilities and integrations to help you along the way!</description></item><item><title>Remix</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/remix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/remix/</guid><description>Description Remix is a full stack web framework that lets you focus on the user interface and work back through web standards to deliver a fast, slick, and resilient user experience.
What’s better about this method or library ?
What can we do with it ?
How should we adopt it ?</description></item><item><title>Zustand</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/zustand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/radar/zustand/</guid><description>Description A small, fast and scalable bearbones state-management solution using simplified flux principles. Has a comfy API based on hooks, isn&amp;rsquo;t boilerplatey or opinionated.
What’s better about this method or library It’s one of the smallest state management library. It’s 100 percent unopinionated. It’s not only for React. For example, we can combine the state of different applications no matter what framework they use (micro frontends). It can deal with common pitfalls, like the dreaded zombie child problem, react concurrency, and context loss.</description></item></channel></rss>