<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Careers on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><description>Recent content in Careers on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>穢 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/hiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Development</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Business Development talents to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
 **Apply now** (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Culture Handbook</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</guid><description>Towards growth Keep learning and growing. We started this team out of software practice advancement.
The continuous study lays the foundation for the future growth. Just like software, knowledge must evolve and be useful. We collect the lesson learned and input into our team knowledge base.
Purpose-built Everything we do comes with the purpose behind. Good software is software that works and provide actual value. Effort is count when it&amp;rsquo;s placed on things that matter.</description></item><item><title>Executive Assistant</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for an Executive Assistant to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
 **Apply now** (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Technical Recruiter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</guid><description>## We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a Technical Recruiter to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
 **Apply now** (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>The Manifesto</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</guid><description>Aim for Quality Quality exists in every piece of work. We thrive to deliver the best because we can.
Well-crafted Software
We humbly imply our expertise and experience into well-crafted software. We take pride in high quality products and perfect solution. We can&amp;rsquo;t stand preventable defects. Quality Pays
Quality outweighs everything else. Once it isn&amp;rsquo;t managed, the entire project goes down as well. Crafting solid software requires time, efforts, disciplines and proper methods.</description></item><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>React Native Developer</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for talented developer with experience in React Native to join Dwarves and work remotely, on a fast-growing US startup.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
 As an engineer at Dwarves, you will be working closely with a team of talented, kind people and working directly with our clients. There is a lot of freedom to contribute to the quality of the project and improve, or prove yourself.</description></item><item><title>Life at Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re like-minded teammates who pursue ambitious goals with tech culture and codes of conduct.
Build a place we love to work at We build this company like we build a product. There are roadmaps for growth; there are phases; there are iterations. There might also be bugs, places where the company crashes because of bad organizational design, or cultural oversights.
That means we advocate for changes. Changes always start with making our people better.</description></item></channel></rss>