<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>We Are Hiring on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><description>Recent content in We Are Hiring on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/hiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</guid><description>Android Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN ANDROID DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Knowledge in Dart fundamentals and Flutter framework Passionate about programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Android Development in Java/Kotlin is a plus You own the Android platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Apprentice</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/apprentice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/apprentice/</guid><description>Apprenticeship Program About the program Apprenticeship is a six-month earn-and-learn training program; it&amp;rsquo;s a way to learn about being a professional software developer. Specifically, it is a way to learn to be like the most skilled software developers you can find. It involves seeking out good teachers and taking opportunities to learn by working alongside them.
Apprenticeship is designed for the individuals who
are looking for the zen way to ship quality software or haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out the clear path to a job in the tech industry or with non-traditional work and educational background to find full-time roles The program provides a real-world experience where you will</description></item><item><title>Benefits And Perks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Since the majority of Dwarves Foundation employees work in Saigon, this section is written with that as the default. Some benefits don’t make sense in other countries. We will try our best to provide comparable benefits and perks as it makes sense, though.
Continuing Education Allowance You will always grow by learning and playing with new and cool technologies. From books to conferences, you’ll get a yearly budget for your individual learning and development goals.</description></item><item><title>Frontend</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/frontend/</guid><description>Frontend Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A FRONTEND ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Passionate about coding and programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Strong knowledge in JavaScript fundamentals Well versed in various browser technologies Your HTML/CSS have to be good enough to create world-class UI (hint: we don&amp;rsquo;t use float) Knowledge of techniques like BEM, CSS modules, inline styles, .</description></item><item><title>Golang</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/golang/</guid><description>Gopher WE ARE LOOKING FOR A GOPHER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Experience with Golang Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test and integration test Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Growth</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/growth/</guid><description>Marketing We are open to a marketing position!
If you are looking for a tech-savvy company to contribute to and make your career, this may be your opportunity to put in your spirit and ideal setup.
Purpose Dwarves are a group of software engineers, designers, and innovation advocates. We are one of the most tech-savvy teams out there. We build this team together six years ago from a corner of Saigon and Toronto.</description></item><item><title>How We Hire</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</guid><description>How we hire Hiring means we need help. We only hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. We always look for long-term teammates that why we want to ensure the new hire is a value fit and culture fit.
Rounds Several Dwarves will talk to the candidates to walk them through 4 rounds
Pre-assessment: We evaluate the logic, English, and the personalities in non-interrupted 30 minutes online test.</description></item><item><title>How We Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</guid><description>How we work We do Agile We build software. The way we see it is a collaboration between multiple people in the team with sufficient knowledge on the domain and clearly understand the project vision that they can quickly adapt to the changes in the market. We adopt the Agile philosophy at this level.
Also, based on that philosophy, we apply the Scrum framework, which we find out a good fit for us.</description></item><item><title>Intern</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/intern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/intern/</guid><description>The Program In 2018, we launched the first Summer Internship Program for students with or without Engineering background from top universities. The program was designed with the purpose to give an opportunity for candidates to experience the real world projects. No coffee runs here. We love watching talented people learn and explore their skills.
We strive to create a generation of new tech enthusiasts who possess the same DNA with us, to generate a solid groundwork and go along with the company’s triumph.</description></item><item><title>IOS</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/ios/</guid><description>iOS Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN iOS DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Strong knowledge in Swift fundamentals and its framework Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Objective-C is a plus You own the iOS platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Making A Career</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</guid><description>Making a Career The average tenure of employees working at many technology companies today is shockingly low. At both Amazon, Google and other companies, it’s just around one year. At Dwarves Foundation, it’s just around three years as of late 2018. That’s something to be proud of, and something to ensure endures. When you work at Dwarves Foundation, it should be feasible to think about this as the place for making a life-long career.</description></item><item><title>QA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/qa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/qa/</guid><description>QA Engineer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A QA ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements CAREFULNESS is our first prerequisite A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp.</description></item><item><title>What We Stand For</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</guid><description>What we stand for Empower Innovation with Software Craftsmanship Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.
Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time.</description></item><item><title>What We Value</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</guid><description>What we value Before anything else, values come first. The value is important to us. They are what we proud of. They help guide us when we are facing a difficult decision. They will be the things you like about what we do at Dwarves Foundation and how we do it.
Our core values guide our strategies and individual actions so that we create a company whose character is as radical as our work.</description></item><item><title>Where We Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</guid><description>Where we work Office The Dwarves HQ is in Saigon, Vietnam. Thirty people and two cats have desk space in the Saigon office, but those people also work from home regularly. We expand the office space when the old one is full and people want the new office. Anyone is welcome to visit Saigon and work from the office at any time.
From home A few people at Dwarves Foundation are based in other countries and they work from home most of the time.</description></item></channel></rss>