<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond The Title</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/beyond-the-title/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/beyond-the-title/</guid><description>The Common Dilemma You&amp;rsquo;re only paid that much to do that much We only pay you that much if you can do only that much It&amp;rsquo;s the scenario that people measure and expect their effort should be traded into paychecks. Employers issue fixed rates for labors, while employees refuse to do things that are not in the job description. It gradually forms a mindset where people decide to work &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to get paid and miss out on the chance to discover their self-limitation.</description></item><item><title>Go The Extra Mile</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/go-the-extra-mile/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/go-the-extra-mile/</guid><description>A couple days ago, I was asked if I were ever a product person, what would I do to make the best out of it.
It took me a while. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;ve never walked in this shoe before. Wth is a product person? I wondered. And I started digging. Here it is, &amp;ldquo;Making sure your product/ thing shipped out flawlessly.&amp;rdquo; A perfectionist mindset.
Sounds a bit crazy, yet a lil intrigued.</description></item><item><title>A Tips Of Hiring - Do &amp; Don't</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</guid><description>Many companies out there get lured by the vision of &amp;ldquo;scaling up&amp;rdquo;. An unwritten rule of &amp;rsquo;the more man we have, the better output we create&amp;rsquo;. But no, hiring with no motivation only leads to one thing: A waste of resource.
Hire without plan bored talent people out. There&amp;rsquo;s no good to put people in a place where they can&amp;rsquo;t create any impact. And we? We tend to fall for creating unnecessary job, which results in a waste of money and training resource.</description></item><item><title>Delegation And Believe It Will Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t always make things (or everything) on our own. If that somehow truly happens, then Inc, Corp, Enterprise or Group won&amp;rsquo;t stand a chance with Freelancers.
So why delegating? At least, in business, delegation means having extra people to help distribute the stress, provides a gathered source of information, and a couple of extra hands to slap when our thought goes wrong. Delegation also gives delegator more time &amp;amp; effort to focus on other things, or sometimes just a perfect excuse to grab a beer instead of burying their heads in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Constructive Feedback</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/constructive-feedback/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/constructive-feedback/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s in human nature to instantly lose their mind when things get hard, and somehow they split nasty things that can&amp;rsquo;t be undone. So, to reduce the ratio of unnecessary conflicts, let&amp;rsquo;s make the feedback great again.
Know the Time Define the frame for listening and for questioning. Talk blocking isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to express how you feel. If you don&amp;rsquo;t respect other&amp;rsquo;s time of present, they have no reason to give a shit about what you think on their idea.</description></item><item><title>Transparency</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/transparency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/transparency/</guid><description>***How much do you know about this woodland?*** → is the question we all get during the first interview. Sure, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to nail the final offer; you&amp;rsquo;re likely to get a better chance on gradually discovering the company&amp;rsquo;s essential information.
But then what?
You step on the project. You get swiped away in work. You check up the daily to-do. And you have no idea what&amp;rsquo;s happening in other places.</description></item><item><title>Avoid Burn Out</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/avoid-burn-out/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/avoid-burn-out/</guid><description>Just to be clear, this term has nothing to compare with the emotional crisis you go through daily - stress. No, burn-out isn&amp;rsquo;t stress.
It describes the state of physical and emotional exhaustion. Burnout reduces and sucks out your productivity. As it develops, it beats every single reason that once was your working motto. The interest, the creativity and motivation gets faded away. Your job might be done, but you no longer feel satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Writing Management Objectives In Smart</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</guid><description>S.M.A.R.T. goals are a relatively new idea. In 1981, George T. Doran, a consultant and former director of corporate planning for Washington Water Power Company, published a paper called, “There’s a S.M.A.R.T. Way to Write Management’s Goals and Objectives.” In the document, he introduces S.M.A.R.T. goals as a tool to create criteria to help improve the chances of succeeding in accomplishing a goal
S – Specific When setting a goal, be specific about what you want to accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Delegate Work Not Responsibility</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</guid><description>We can bring in all the technology in the world, but if we can’t delegate properly, our companies have no chance of scaling well
Delegating work does not absolve you of responsibility. In the case of a failure, the blame is all yours. Investors will go after the CEO, even if an intern made the mistake that hurt the company. If a failure occurs due to person you delegated work to lacking skills, it is your fault you delegated work to the wrong person.</description></item><item><title>Conduct A Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/conduct-a-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/conduct-a-meeting/</guid><description>Meeting has always played an integral part in every corporate office. To optimize a productive meeting, it is vital to conduct individuals gathering without wasting time and directly get to the point, to deliver new information or discuss crucial issues.
And that begins with a smooth collaboration between these following essential aspects.
1. Timeline Announce meeting time at least one day before the meeting happens. Create Google Meet link Sync on Basecamp schedule Notify all related participants.</description></item></channel></rss>