<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Pipeline Design Framework</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/data-pipeline-design-framework/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/data-pipeline-design-framework/</guid><description>Motivation of Designing Data Pipeline Framework To improve and strongly go-live the data pipeline, besides apply best practices and pillar for Data Pipeline Native Solution, a design framework and pattern are robustly help us in:
Follow typical data pipeline Organize pipeline and adopt market Refer the other people use besides yours Its easy to follow if we will discuss the pattern and solution with SWAT and pros/cons analysis and aks ourself for initiative questions such as: when to use and when not to use.</description></item><item><title>Quick Learning Vector Database</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/quick-learning-vector-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/quick-learning-vector-database/</guid><description>Motivation of Vector Database The motivation of this thoughts that trying to discover the LLMs and Generative AI In order to create or build, train any models there are multiple factors will need to be considered: lakes of data, metadata, data management, infrastructure, etc. Vector Databases are used like underlying of Gen AI Where everything are tokenized, vectorized and serialized into a single language Explored blog posts, articles from What is a AWS Vector Database?</description></item><item><title>Community Changelog \#162 - Feb</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/162-xxxx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/162-xxxx/</guid><description>Community Changelog #162 - Feb - Latest Findings, Tech Market Report, Partner network, Research Topics, and Dwarves’ Reward System in. Another month has passed, it&amp;rsquo;s time for another monthly recap of what we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Hope everyone is ready for all the cool things below.
title section sub-section Intro Stay ahead in tech Road to an even greater knowledge base. With around 40 topics covering the most promising technologies to grow our expertise.</description></item><item><title>How to withdraw ICY</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/how-to-withdraw-icy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/how-to-withdraw-icy/</guid><description>A. Set up: Create an on-chain crypto wallet Install the extension on your browser
Go to https://metamask.io/download/ and Click “Install Metamask for Chromium” Add the wallet extension to the Chrome on Firefox Browser (DO NOT use Safari) Follow guideline to create a wallet
Click to the Metamask Icon to use the wallet For those who haven’t had any wallet, please click “Create a new wallet” Enter the password for the wallet Read the instruction of Wallet security and Choose “Secure my wallet” Reveal and copy the seed phrase, the save it at a safe place.</description></item><item><title>Starting your journey at Dwarves Discord</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/starting-your-journey-at-dwarves-discord/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/starting-your-journey-at-dwarves-discord/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Network,
We&amp;rsquo;ve grown a lot since launching our Discord server since the first day we made this network grow based on developers-centric.
That’s why Dwarves Discord is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Discord is where we:
Share our software know-how through seminars, discussion channels &amp;amp; tech talks Connect with our friends, alumni, and like-minded people Build an open software network that people love to be a part of.</description></item><item><title>Stock Option Plan</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/stock-option-plan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/stock-option-plan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What's New in February 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</guid><description>Reporting tech signals - Latest findings on Serverless Computing, AI &amp;amp; ML, FinOps and CyberSecurity Research Topics 2024 - 40 topics on the most promising technologies. Dwarves&amp;rsquo; Reward System - Developing our community reward system Calling for Partners - One of the rare event where Dwarves and community members gather. Reporting tech signals Every month we watch tech trends closely to depict which ones have high potential, and can be part of our growing tech stack.</description></item><item><title>Partners Network</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</guid><description>We seek for Partners, individuals and companies likewise, to develop a co-creation system driven by mutual purposes and interests.
With our average deal size at $30,000, a partner can generate at least $2,400 per project. Commission is paid from project start, every month until project end.
Partner perks Partnering with Dwarves is not just a collaboration, it’s a strategic investment in trust, network and business growth. Being our partners mean sharing opportunities, resources, connections and scaling up together.</description></item><item><title>Marketing and Communications Specialist</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Specialists to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will have a passion for technology, a strong understanding of the software development industry, and excellent communication skills.
This role will involve developing and implementing marketing strategies, creating compelling content, managing social media presence, and maintaining effective communication with both internal and external stakeholders.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>What's New in January 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In this first month of 2024, we kept tap of what&amp;rsquo;s brewing in the tech market, while reviewing what we went through in 2023.
Reporting tech signals - Updates on the stage of React, Rust, AI, Cybersecurity, Rust.</description></item><item><title>Submit a Bounty</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/submit-a-bounty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/submit-a-bounty/</guid><description/></item><item><title>2023 Dec + title</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-december-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-december-2023/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In December, we launched our Consulting Team, released our finding on tech trends, and last but not least, got everyone ready to wrap up 2023.
Reporting tech signals - We stay ahead by monitoring high-potential trends in tech.</description></item><item><title>Archive</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/archive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/archive/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</guid><description>Industry
E-Commerce
Location
Vietnam and SEA
Business Context
Need for an advanced e-commerce platform to streamline drop shipping operations
Solution
Revamped and technologically advanced online system development by Dwarves Foundation
Outcome
Launch of Droppii for Business v3.0, providing a scalable, user-friendly platform for business clients and enhancing customer interaction
Our Service
Full-Stack Development / Agile Project Management
In brief Droppii, in collaboration with Dwarves Foundation, revamps its e-commerce platform, enhancing dropshipping operations with the launch of Droppii for Business v3.</description></item><item><title>Consultant Growth Track</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</guid><description>While there is no fixed path in the consulting field, we do have a structured growth guidance for career development, skill enhancement, and professional advancement.
Tier 1: Associate Consultant What you do Participate in client engagements, assisting senior consultants Gain exposure to various projects and technologies Learn company methodologies, tools, and best practices Perform research, analysis, and contribute to project documentation Skills needed Expert technical skills Client needs and project requirements gathering Project management basics Communication and presentation skills Reward Project lead bonus Tier 2: Consultant What you do Lead projects or work streams Communicate directly with clients, understanding business objectives Analyze complex problems and provide technical solutions Develop and present proposals, contributing to business development Mentor junior team members and contribute to knowledge sharing Skills needed Specialization in specific tech stacks / domains Advanced project management and leadership skills Client relationship management Deep understanding of industry-specific challenges / solutions Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Tier 3: Lead Consultant What you do Oversee multiple projects or departments Act as a subject matter expert in specialized areas Provide thought leadership, guide strategy, and drive innovation Represent the company at industry events and conferences Skills needed Strategic thinking and business acumen Thought leadership through publications or public speaking Mentorship and coaching of consultants Advanced problem-solving and critical thinking skills Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Tier 4: Partner What you do Set strategic direction and drive business growth Establish and maintain key client relationships Contribute to company-wide decision-making and management Skills needed Leadership and organizational management Business development, sales, and negotiation skills Operational efficiency and financial management Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Company shares dfg</description></item><item><title>Data processing and visual infographics (through DuckDB-WASM)</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/data-processing-and-visual-infographics-through-duckdb-wasm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/data-processing-and-visual-infographics-through-duckdb-wasm/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Realtime memory knowledge updates (RAG updates)</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/realtime-memory-knowledge-updates-rag-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/realtime-memory-knowledge-updates-rag-updates/</guid><description> Implement a memory storage system Allow realtime context updates for the LLM Refresh the context and LLM knowledge in realtime Add to cycle fine-tuning</description></item><item><title>Self-host AI model on the browser</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/self-host-ai-model-on-the-browser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/self-host-ai-model-on-the-browser/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Consulting - How we work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---how-we-work/</guid><description>Our Approach: Collaborative Expertise Team of Specialists: we favor collective expertise, encouraging knowledge sharing and collaboration, to craft innovative solutions that exceed expectations. Innovative Mindset: we encourage out-of-the-box thinking, experimentation, and creative problem-solving Transparent Communication: we lay everything out on the open, fostering a collaborative environment that promotes trust, clarity, and alignment Because we function based on real life demands, we recommend at least the following appointments
Weekly note: written record consists of 3 main components; current project health &amp;amp; issues, potential project / deal, market signal report Monthly report: wins, losses &amp;amp; lessons learned collected from weekly notes Monthly planning / retro: conducted by Consulting team to reflect on our performance metrics, planning for the next period Monthly demo/showcase: team-wise event to show off what we built / learned Monthly calibration: a joint appointment between Consulting, Labs and Ops to review individual / team performance Information Flow</description></item><item><title>Consulting - Who should join us</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---who-should-join-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---who-should-join-us/</guid><description>Consulting teams consists of anyone who&amp;rsquo;s hungry for more than just coding; those who are curious about the trends, the market, who can introduce new projects / challenges, who care about providing sensible solutions, and who take great care of projects.
When assessing new members, we have a few qualities that we look for. Those qualities can be something that you have already possess, or can be something you are growing toward.</description></item><item><title>Consulting - Who We Are</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consulting---who-we-are/</guid><description>Who we are Dwarves Consulting is team of individuals who possess a combination of technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and strong communication abilities.
Our culture Ahead of the market: we continuously learn and discover about the market and technology so we can participate in new, cool challenges, strive for high-quality deliverables and maintaining high standards Tech to solve problems: first we understand the problems, we provide solutions before any hard coding Network matters: we welcome collaborations with everyone who has the same goals and believe as we do Main functions of Consulting team We monitor the market to stay informed about industry trends, advancements, emerging technologies, and market dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Move internal notes to note.d.foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/obsidian-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/obsidian-fork/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Business Development</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/business-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/business-development/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Business Development talents to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Culture Handbook</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/culture-handbook/</guid><description>Towards growth Keep learning and growing. We started this team out of software practice advancement. The continuous study lays the foundation for the future growth. Just like software, knowledge must evolve and be useful. We collect the lesson learned and input into our team knowledge base.
Purpose-built Everything we do comes with the purpose behind. Good software is software that works and provide actual value. Effort is count when it&amp;rsquo;s placed on things that matter.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Community</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/dwarves-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/dwarves-community/</guid><description>Dwarves Community is melting pot for software engineers, thinkers, learners and techies who are to explore, learn and master the latest advancements in technology.
Technology is moving at the speed of light, and we want to stay at the forefront. Background or experience doesn’t matter to us, we are more keen on the mindset of always being curious about what’s next in tech, collaborating for the better, learning profusely and sharing unconditionally.</description></item><item><title>Executive Assistant</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/executive-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/executive-assistant/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for an Executive Assistant to join Dwarves and work remotely. We are seeking a highly organized, proactive, and experienced Executive Assistant to provide support to our senior executives. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Technical Recruiter</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a Technical Recruiter to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will play a pivotal role in sourcing, attracting, and hiring top-tier talents and take care of our team members&amp;rsquo; growth.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>The Manifesto</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/the-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/the-manifesto/</guid><description>Aim for Quality Quality exists in every piece of work. We thrive to deliver the best because we can.
Well-crafted Software
We humbly imply our expertise and experience into well-crafted software. We take pride in high quality products and perfect solution. We can&amp;rsquo;t stand preventable defects. Quality Pays
Quality outweighs everything else. Once it isn&amp;rsquo;t managed, the entire project goes down as well. Crafting solid software requires time, efforts, disciplines and proper methods.</description></item><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/home/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This note repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges, new tech, hiring, bounty, etc.</description></item><item><title>React Native Developer</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/open-positions/react-native-developer/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for talented developer with experience in React Native to join Dwarves and work remotely, on a fast-growing US startup.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
🤝 As an engineer at Dwarves, you will be working closely with a team of talented, kind people and working directly with our clients. There is a lot of freedom to contribute to the quality of the project and improve, or prove yourself.</description></item><item><title>Estimation Guidelines</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/estimation-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/estimation-guidelines/</guid><description>When we conduct an estimation, it is recommended to abandon the transitional “exact hours” assessment method, instead, use the story point based on the Fibonacci number (1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21…). The number expresses an estimation of the overall effort required to fully implement a backlog item or any piece of work.
Below’s an example of an estimation table based on the matrix of complexity, uncertainty, and effort:</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-november-2023/</guid><description>Last November, we kicked off the Labs team, introduced Salary Advance for the Dwarves, upgraded note.d.foundation, supported Golang meetup, and demonstrated craftsmanship through various case studies and demos.
Launching Labs team - Dwarves R&amp;amp;D team is officially in operation. Monthly top performers - The top 5 high-performing members get rewards and NFT badges. NFT badges can be staked to earn shares of the company. Salary Advance - Dwarves&amp;rsquo; team members now can get an advance of their monthly salary in case of emergency.</description></item><item><title>Careers</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/hiring/202403121185/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/hiring/202403121185/</guid><description>When we put Foundation in our name, we mean it. We want to put in place a team of go-getters who solve real-world problems, build big platforms, and spread goodwill across communities.
Join us. Let&amp;rsquo;s create the next big things together. At Dwarves, you will be working with an experienced, talented team who loves technology and knows how to use technology to better life on a global level.
Apply: Marketing and Communications Specialist How we work at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/life-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/life-at-dwarves/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re like-minded teammates who pursue ambitious goals with tech culture and codes of conduct.
Build a place we love to work at We build this company like we build a product. There are roadmaps for growth; there are phases; there are iterations. There might also be bugs, places where the company crashes because of bad organizational design, or cultural oversights.
That means we advocate for changes. Changes always start with making our people better.</description></item><item><title>Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation Team&amp;rsquo;s guide on our project delivery process. This post will serve as your go-to resource for understanding our weekly, bi-weekly, and monthly activities, ensuring that we stay on track and excel in our deliveries.
Weekly Activities 1. Weekly Points/Effort Report Every Friday
Action: Fill out the weekly points/effort report. Link: Weekly Report Spreadsheet. Deadline for Data Sync: Data is sync by EOD next Tuesday. Outcome: Weekly leaderboard on delivery.</description></item><item><title>$icy staking</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-staking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-staking/</guid><description/></item><item><title>$icy store</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-store/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-store/</guid><description/></item><item><title>$icy utility commands</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-utility-command/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/icy-utility-command/</guid><description>?icy accounting &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; smod command or above + head channel only
current fund in contract
icy in market
offset usd
unpaid salary advance
?icy &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; show info
address
conversion rate
fund in contract
how many you have earned
last 5 tx</description></item><item><title>$icy withdrawal</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/withdrawl-icy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/withdrawl-icy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>November Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-november-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>Rework Fortress Command</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/rework-fortress-command/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/rework-fortress-command/</guid><description>remove:
?event ?staff ?updates rework UI &amp;amp; function (mostly move to note.d)
?digest ?memos ?earn</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/mochi-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/mochi-ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Applying MPC for authentication for web3 Console</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</guid><description>Use Multi-Party Computation for secure authentication in a Web3 console environment:
Research and implement MPC protocols suitable for authentication. Integrate MPC into the Console app for secure user authentication</description></item><item><title>Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection)</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</guid><description>Implement biometric authentication for web applications via external devices:
Research and select appropriate biometric hardware compatible with web applications. Develop a secure method for connecting and communicating with the external device. Integrate biometric authentication into the web authentication flow.</description></item><item><title>Demo: Magic Links</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-magic-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-magic-links/</guid><description>Implement a &amp;lsquo;Magic Link&amp;rsquo; system for passwordless authentication:
Develop an email-based authentication system where users receive a unique, time-sensitive link to log in. Ensure the security of the magic link generation and verification process.</description></item><item><title>Demo: QR Code based Login</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</guid><description>Create a QR code-based login system for easy and secure access to web applications:
Design the QR code generation and scanning process. Implement a secure system for QR code validation and user authentication.</description></item><item><title>Implement a rust game through WASM</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</guid><description> Design a simple game concept suitable for implementation in Rust. Develop the game logic and user interface in Rust. Compile and optimize the Rust code for WASM. Test game performance and compatibility across various browsers.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a game server on Rust</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</guid><description>Develop a robust and efficient game server using Rust.
Design the server architecture with a focus on scalability and performance. Implement core server functionalities like player management, real-time communication, and game logic. Test for concurrency and load handling.</description></item><item><title>$icy in 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/icy-in-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/icy-in-2024/</guid><description>Follow up on our recent post df protocol, $icy and $dfg.
Since 2020, $icy has been a part of our workflow. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap.
2020: we introduced ICY as our first community experiment. 2021: we launched icy.so, a site to redeem $icy. 2022: $icy became our primary reward method, starting with summit-2022 and doty where we sent out about $20000 2023: we introduced vault as a reward avenue for our functional team.</description></item><item><title>💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s our draft internal map/v0 for 🧊 $icy play, based on our current activities at this borderless software firm.
Context:
Back in 2018, when i envisioned doing something unconventional with our setup, we introduced 💎 $dfg.
It came with a dream that everyone on the team can help build next generation software, stay cool making money and own something. I planned to step down and give more ownership to those who actually implement our projects by gradually distributing $dfg to our grind chads.</description></item><item><title>October Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-october-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of October, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been for the most part very exciting, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;Full-stack engineering’ Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is prolific and always true: Open-source.
Open-source has always been the foundation for many hobby projects, learning experiences, startups, and enterprises. It has stayed true to the idea for the rights to use, study, change, and distribute the software and its source code to anyone and for any purpose - originally helping to fix bugs and later accelerating state-of-the-art tech and AI.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IA</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</guid><description/></item><item><title>monitoring</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>nda</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>release</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aarrr</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</guid><description>AARRR framework We use the AARRR framework to measure and optimize every phase of a product by optimizing it through the insane focus on one metric at a time.
What is AARRR framework? The AARRR framework consists of five phases a customer goes through in order to achieve growth and each phase has its own set of metrics to focus on. AARRR stands for Acquisition, Activation, Retention, Referral, and Revenue.</description></item><item><title>business-playbook-outline</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</guid><description> BUSINESS PLAYBOOK Table of Contents
Introduction Who we are The Team Team chart Team members Portfolio Achievements Vision &amp;amp; mission
Strategy
Operating Process
Diagram Process workflows Sales Partnership process Commission model/tier Payment timeline FAQ</description></item><item><title>collaboration-guideline</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</guid><description>Collaboration Guideline Guidelines for project collaboration between DF and Clients.
Tools Project management &amp;amp; communication: Basecamp (invited as Client) Sprint planning &amp;amp; tracking: Jira/Basecamp Meeting: Google Meet Source control platform: Github/Gitlab (self-hosted) Design: Figma/Sketch Schedule Project kick-off meeting: 1 session Sprint length: 1 week/2 weeks Sprint planning meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint review &amp;amp; retrospective meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint daily standup meetings (can as well be done via communication channel or Basecamp’s check-ins) Project/team feedback meeting (with Account Manager): 1 per week or 1 every 2 weeks Meeting notes for Sprint planning and Sprint retrospective will be sent within 30 minutes after meeting.</description></item><item><title>design-sprint</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</guid><description>Design Sprint What is the design sprint? The sprint is a four-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping and testing ideas with customers.
Design sprint mostly applied to the Exploration phase.
Friday is usually Education event or Lab projects at Dwarves Design, learning and continuous professional and personal development are in the core of our DNA. No one wants to settle, everyone wants to take the next step forward.</description></item><item><title>df-workflow</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</guid><description>Monday:
Sprint Planning
End-of-day (EOD) check-in message
Tuesday:
EOD check-in message
Wednesday:
Sprint review message
EOD check-in message
Thursday:
EOD check-in message
Performance review (Account Manager, Team Lead, Project Owner, every 2 weeks)
Friday:
Investment time/Tech Radar
Sprint Review
Retrospective</description></item><item><title>fbsc</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</guid><description>Budget We do need to know clients&amp;rsquo; budgets. This is often uncomfortable for them but their budget helps determines what scope is possible. It saves time. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know their budget, we discuss different options.
We talk about breaking product rollout into stages and try to improve the product&amp;rsquo;s chances of success at each stage by:
Focusing on a small subset of features. Designing a valuable user experience. Developing a meaningful relationship with users.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</guid><description>TRAINING COURSE: HOW TO WORK WITH CLIENT What skills that an engineer should have in order to work with client effectively?
Strong technical skills: includes Basics of testing: Unit, Integration, System Software testing and debugging Attention to details
Communication skills: good English skills (both written and verbal)
-&amp;gt; require somewhere Intermediate - Upper Intermediate level
Problem solving and logical thinking
Work planning
Teamwork
Project Management
Consistency in delivering work result</description></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</guid><description>Lean Canvas Lean Canvas is an adaptation of Business Model Canvas by Alexander Osterwalder which Ash Maurya created in the Lean Startup spirit (Fast, Concise and Effective startup). Lean Canvas promises an actionable and entrepreneur-focused business plan. It focuses on problems, solutions, key metrics, and competitive advantages.
1. Problem What is the crucial problem faced by the product’s consumers? Capture their central frustration. The best way to describe the problem is in terms of the jobs customers need to do, what they are ultimately trying to achieve and what is the pain or frustration they currently feel.</description></item><item><title>prototype</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</guid><description>Low-fidelity prototype: UI Design Research 1. Understand prospect Understanding stakeholder, company, business model, goals and challenges of the product in order to set mindset, define style, color palette, and typography, iconography, illustration, and photography.
2. Define product Style Based on the target user and product’s requirement, we define layout style. Make references from Dribbble, Behance and other showcase sites to catch up with the current design trends.
Color Define primary and secondary based on the logo and branding of the product.</description></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</guid><description>GENERAL QUESTIONS FOR SERVICE FEEDBACKS Engineer performances
a. Communication
How did the engineer interact with your team? How was the communication between the engineer and your team? Was our engineer proactive in communicating with you? Did our engineer ask lots of questions? On which aspect our engineer should improve to provide better communication? b. Work ethic, delivery
Have our engineers “coming to work” on time? Have you ever had to wait too long to get a response from our engineer?</description></item><item><title>UI</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UX</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</guid><description>UX Research Framework 1. Gather Data In the first phase, we focus on gathering as much valuable data as humanly possible. It’s time for open-question asking, non-judgmental listening, and meticulous note-taking.
Stakeholder Interview In order to create successful products as a designer, it’s crucial to discover how the stakeholders think - what is the vision for the product (from each of the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; perspectives), and how can these be amalgamated?</description></item><item><title>wireframe</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</guid><description>Wireframe: Workflow Design Created on scraps of paper, a whiteboard, or in a software program, serve to establish relationships between elements in a project such as navigation, imagery, and calls to action.
Often, a wireframe has 3 core goals:
To show the content and functionality of the pages before any further designs. To help designers communicate with clients about the design concept. To establish the information hierarchy of the site.</description></item><item><title>Fortress Mma Score</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/fortress-mma-score/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/fortress-mma-score/</guid><description>Update fortress database Create a new table employee_mma_scores
including (but not limited):
employee_id mastery_score autonomy_score meaning_score rated_at Create a Discord command ?profile @member (smod or above perm)
data: latest mma score, basic info, project info
design: add later (hnh)
2.1 Specific Channel Permission
Create a scoped channel, same as scoped role permission
this command only run in defined channels
Discord command to export a template csv ?mma template (smod or above perm)</description></item><item><title>Fortress Shanky Data</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/fortress-shanky-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/fortress-shanky-data/</guid><description>generate &amp;amp; render something as above
with following syntax data:
source | amount | target
sample:
Wages [1500] Budget Other [250] Budget Budget [450] Taxes Budget [420] Housing Budget [400] Food Budget [295] Transportation Budget [25] Savings note: hnh i will provide a db view for data queries
https://sankeydiagram.net</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Index</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/site-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/site-index/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Konvoy X Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/konvoy-x-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/konvoy-x-dwarves/</guid><description>Industry:
Logistics, Supply Chain Management
Location:
Australia
Business Context:
An innovative company providing beverage industry with a unique keg rental solution, emphasizing sustainability and ease of use.
Solution:
A tech-driven rental system with real-time keg tracking and analytics ensuring security and transparency.
Outcome:
Increase the operational efficiency and profitability of breweries with a flexible, secure, and eco-friendly keg supply chain.
Our Service:
Product Consulting, Staff Augmentation
In brief Konvoy, a pioneering force in the keg management industry, first surfaced in Australia and New Zealand in October 2019.</description></item><item><title>The stage of Growth at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/growth-stages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/growth-stages/</guid><description>Hello, It’s Han &amp;amp; Nikki.
Since you last heard from us, we have been going through a lot of changes. There are both good changes and so-so changes. In this update, we are excited to share the real journey of growth and transformation that our team has embarked upon, as we continue to strive to become a more skilled and knowledgable software team.
Shifting focus towards techniques Going full-stack engineering Growing a support system for the community Building stronger bonds through collaboration Nurturing relationships for shared success Shifting focuses towards techniques It’s a bold decision the team has taken.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Trend Command</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/trend-command/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/earn/trend-command/</guid><description>Requirements ?trend command The idea is to create a ?trend Discord command that will list the top 15 trending repositories on GitHub.
We can reference https://github.com/trending to make our list. Otherwise, we will need to identify what should count as trending on our end (stars/day, commits/day, etc).
There are no particular design requirements for this command, but it should use an embed and look similar to the outputs of our other commands.</description></item><item><title>Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</guid><description>Industry
Fintech
Tech stack
MySQL, JAVA Spring Boot, and Angular
Location
South East Asia
Solution
Fast recruiting senior engineers to collaborate with CIMB’s tech team.
Deliver quality and collaboration control through out the project to hit targeted timeline.
Outcome
In charge of the backend foundation, we marked a milestone in CIMB&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation journey, with a streamlined, customer-focused experience contributed to CIMB&amp;rsquo;s forward-looking vision.
Our Service
Tech Consulting, Staff Augmentation</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Community Bounty</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/dwarves-community-bounty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/dwarves-community-bounty/</guid><description>As you may know, Dwarves Discord network is where we connect with our friends, alumni, and like-minded people.
Bounties are rewards (in ICY - Dwarves’ token) given out to community members for work that encourages community developers to get more involved in the development outside of their core skills.
Who can join
We offer a platform for those seeking development work and a dynamic environment to connect with skilled developers capable of building new tools, new features.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves Software Design Group</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</guid><description>The idea: A path to better software “Everything in software architecture is a trade-off, and the why is more important than how.&amp;quot; Neal Ford is a Director and software architect at ThoughtWorks
At Dwarves, we believe that growth is our universal language, and we always strive to improve ourselves, individual-wise and team-wise.
At the end of 2021, starting with engineering practices, the core idea behind creating a software design group is to enable engineers to develop the skills required to become software architects.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>Ogif</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/ogif/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/ogif/</guid><description>I would like to introduce to you our new initiative called OGIF — Oh God It&amp;rsquo;s Friday. Moving forward, our Friday Showcase will have a broader range of topics to discuss and share.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to reflect on our achievements from the past week, and look forward to the next with optimism and enthusiasm.
The tradition At Dwarves, we value work-life balance and believe that it comes after fulfilling our responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Red Flags</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/red-flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/red-flags/</guid><description>These red flags are things we don’t want to see in our peeps. Even when you think they are improper, don’t waste your time with a wrong group of people.
Negative attitude The employee may exhibit a negative attitude towards their work, colleagues, or the company. They may also show signs of disengagement, lack of motivation, lack of integrity or unwillingness to learn.
Incompatibility** **The employee may not fit in with the company culture or may have a personality clash with other team members.</description></item><item><title>Focus On Software Delivery</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/focus-on-software-delivery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/focus-on-software-delivery/</guid><description>Focus on shipping when you are struggling with what to do next to be better as a software engineer. When you ship something new, users will try out your build and give you feedback. It may contain bugs. It may ship with the wrong flow implemented. It may ship with known issues. You may feel bad but and frustrated but those emotions will save you ton of time. The point is: Users will let you know.</description></item><item><title>Are You Helping</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/are-you-helping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/are-you-helping/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive business environment, it is crucial for organizations to have a clear understanding of the value and performance of their employees. In a recent post I wrote, titled &amp;ldquo;Inner Circle&amp;rdquo;, I expounded on the importance of contribution and value in relation to a person&amp;rsquo;s work or performance. However, there is another key aspect to this topic that must be taken into consideration. One of the most effective ways to determine how well a person is performing is by asking the question, &amp;ldquo;Are you helping?</description></item><item><title>Discord Roles</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/discord-roles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/community/discord-roles/</guid><description>To organize our discord and make it fun to interact between community members, we setup those roles for specific purposes. They are ladder-based and function-based roles.
Moderating supporter: help with day-to-day activity, welcome new folks. moderator: organize events, tech talks, &amp;hellip; . smod: run community &amp;amp; company-wide operational works. Community members guest: it is a default role, you will gain this role joined discord. newbie: did an introduction within our network.</description></item><item><title>2023 Happy xxx</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/happy-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/happy-2023/</guid><description>As we enter a new year, I want to reflect on the role that software has played in my life. From the early days of my career to now, software has been a constant presence and something that I have dedicated countless hours to as both an engineer and project manager. I have put in over 10,000 hours of work in this field, and it has become an integral part of my existence.</description></item><item><title>2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</guid><description>Successfully went through 2022, a year that we might say - a new record: team reached highest growth record, kickstarted community engagement, home, compliance training &amp;amp; individual development are speeding up, and a whole new place to call Dwarves.
We’ve achieved to this year’s resolution: A team that cares about how to build software right and can teach others on that.
TEAM GROWTH 30 New Team Members **[2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves](https://github.</description></item><item><title>December Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-december-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-december-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of The Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</guid><description>Dwarves of The Year 2022 - Wins to Celebrate It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, but we&amp;rsquo;ve finally made it to 2022 and what a year it&amp;rsquo;s been for our team of Dwarves. Countless hours of hard work and it&amp;rsquo;s all paid off with our big wins of the year. Honored for all and huge congratulations for our Dwarves of 2022.
A total of ~$18,000 awarded and rewarded by ****$ICY - Dwarves official token, with a few names appearing several times.</description></item><item><title>The Inner Circle</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-inner-circle/</guid><description>The concept of an &amp;ldquo;inner circle&amp;rdquo; within a company is not a new one, and at Dwarves, a software company founded by a group of engineers, this idea holds a significant value. Starting from scratch, the company has always placed emphasis on being surrounded by individuals who can efficiently ship software and don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on unimportant tasks. These individuals are highly respected and valued within the company, as they play a crucial role in the development and success of projects.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</guid><description>Dwarves Summit 2022: Engineering a good time. We don’t treat team bonding the common way, because we understand our engineers. Most of our engineers don’t want running and getting sweaty on the beach for “team-building” activities, or pretending to smile in front of the travel agent’s camera.
This was our first company get-together after 2 years of COVID. It was organized in ways that we can all look back to the progress we’ve made, pat ourselves on the back, have a blast together, and look forward to an even better 2023.</description></item><item><title>MapReduce</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/mapreduce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/mapreduce/</guid><description>What is MapReduce? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with an example.
We are the head of census bureau for the state of California and tasked with finding the finding the population of all cities in California. All the resources we want are ready but we have only four months to finish the task. Calculating the population of all cities for a big state like california is not an easy task. The sensible thing to do is to divide the state by city and make individuals in charge of each city to calculate the population of each city where he is in charge of.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Radar Program</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/tech-radar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/tech-radar/</guid><description>Dwarves Radar Program The Dwarves have a spinning radar. This radar is how we assess and adopt new technology. Throughout the years, we observe the tech industry and pick out the most promising tech to put into the radar to begin the assessment process.
Our tech radar is highly motivated by ThoughtWork’s vision of the technology radar, which is a visual document of industry changes we find interesting as well as of what tech we have trialed and adopted in our company.</description></item><item><title>Open Fabric Set The Tech Foundation And Built An Mvp From Scratch</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</guid><description>Founded and led by veterans from fintech players like Paypal &amp;amp; Grab, Open Fabric is a BNPL platform, built to enable an open commerce network for customers and credit providers in South East Asia to radically simplify merchant integrations for digital payment methods.
With a team of 8 engineers, Dwarves helped set the tech foundation and together built an MVP from scratch. Within a year, Dwarves helped ship the system to onboard and configure payment methods for companies to the Open Fabric commerce network.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</guid><description>It’s our second attempt rolling out this program. But the motivation stays the same: Accelerating someone’s current software development skillset.
It’s neither for interns nor veterans. As stated in the beginning, our goal is to empower software engineers with at least 1 years of experience to rebuild their foundation through:
Software Development Practices Real-projects Scenarios Engineering Work Ethics &amp;amp; Principles The stats speak Although keeping the bar high might extend the searching time, but we maintain a solid standard for every batch.</description></item><item><title>Sharing</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/sharing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/sharing/</guid><description>Sharing At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that sharing is an important part of our culture. We share almost everything: every week, a lot of events are open to the public, and some of them are recorded so that anyone can watch the videos to learn. It may seem strange to share so much, but there are good reasons for it.
The goal of what is shared at Dwarves is not just to make more people learn new technology or knowledge, but to improve the ability of the presenter to communicate their understanding, which will in turn improve their ability to create new things.</description></item><item><title>Showcase</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/learning/showcase/</guid><description>Showcase Every Friday afternoon, everyone in the company is invited to gather on Discord for internal demos of projects teams have been working on. This tradition was founded by Engineering, but anyone (from Design, Product,&amp;hellip;) is welcome to participate.
We value the importance of sharing our work with other people at Dwarves. We hold demos and celebrate our craftsmanship, insight, and learning with others. And it&amp;rsquo;s a chance for people who don&amp;rsquo;t work directly on development to feel included in the process.</description></item><item><title>Road To 100</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/road-to-100/</guid><description>2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves. A notable highlight, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to have more. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to find people that has the same value. It takes true &amp;amp; solid seeks.
On our way to meet the 81th and onward, we&amp;rsquo;re launching a mechanism to help us find like-minded DNAs, and co-create our future using tech.
The Dwarves Referral Program We usually hire and keep the quality bar. The Dwarves are encouraged to recommend friends they think might be a good match for the team.</description></item><item><title>The Next Leading Chairs</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</guid><description>OUR VISION FOR GROWTH Last Jan 2020, we got the chance to celebrate our first milestone - Dwarves Foundation reached 5 years old. The remarkable moment contained the proudest thing we delivered.
**Remote Culture - **That enables us to make things work without any physical constraints. We were able to focus on what we value: Knowledge and People. To name a few: The Handbook** **- To demonstrate our culture, the future we pursue and what portrays the Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</guid><description>English below ↓ Life at Dwarves #6, là những chia sẻ của Hiếu Vũ về hành trình pick up và yêu thích Golang, quá trình gắn bó từ dự án đến con người tại Dwarves. Những trải nghiệm đó để lại cho Hiếu nhiều bài học và lời khuyên cho các bạn trẻ muốn theo đuổi công việc lập trình viên.
Hiếu Vũ từng là thực tập sinh ở tập đoàn công nghệ KMS, và hiện tại là Backend Engineer tại Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</guid><description>English below ↓
Life at Dwarves #5 là câu chuyện về Nam Nguyễn và hành trình hơn 5 năm gắn bó với Dwarves. Sau khi hoàn thành Cao Đẳng, Nam làm ở một công ty offshore của Nhật Bản với vị trí Fullstack Engineer. Sau khi quyết định nghỉ việc tại công ty cũ để tập trung cho tấm bằng Đại học, Nam gia nhập Dwarves, và trở thành một trong những contributor lâu nhất tại tech firm này.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</guid><description>“Anh nghiệm ra rằng trong hành trình trở thành Senior Software Engineer, càng thử thách bản thân, mọi thứ sẽ càng thú vị.”
Life at Dwarves lần này là một nhân vật khá kín tiếng ở Dwarves với đời sống lành mạnh và tính cách nhẹ nhàng. Anh An Trần, Senior Software Engineer với 7 năm kinh nghiệm làm nghề từ các start-up đến Project Lead tại Dwarves Foundation.</description></item><item><title>The future is blockchain and data</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/blockchain-and-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/blockchain-and-data/</guid><description>It’s Han and Nikki here,
Plus an extra fresh voice we’re bringing to Dwarves Updates, in hope we can offer you more engineering-related insights and thoughts.
If you’re a part of our Discord server, you probably have noticed #blockchain is our most busy channel. It’s partially because of all the fusses within the crypto scene, but mainly because we’re aggressively learning, experimenting, and evolving on our blockchain expertise.
The data study group is also getting exciting.</description></item><item><title>Spike Inu Engineering A Seamless Experience For Cross Chain Swap And Decentralized Exchange</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</guid><description>In brief When blockchain becomes the new tech blockbuster, worldwide blockchain networks such as Ethereum, Polygon, Avalanche, Fantom, or Binance Smart Chance started to develop their own tokens. They all possess the same vision: Empower crypto users to transfer their assets in multiple chains hassle-free and effective. The core engine of those products is building a secured bridging solution between chains, enabling tokens to move back and forth, and transferring tokens on the same network.</description></item><item><title>Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</guid><description>In brief Hedge Foundation is a powerful dashboard to support users in managing crypto account positions, balance, PNL and works on bulk orders for profit and loss tracking.
Move alongside the crypto era, Hedge Foundation works to be part of the industry by providing practical tools for crypto users in terms of automating, syncing &amp;amp; managing accounts by utilizing the most out of market database.
Technical Highlight
AG Grid to optimize big table with fast update real-time data.</description></item><item><title>May 2022 All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>FOUNDATION Project Allocation
We concluded the partnership with Relay and Eklipse. It has been a fun (and wild) ride for some of you. New resources are being allocated to help balance the current workload of active projects. If you need to discuss your workload or seek more room for project work, please help ping Giang or Nikki.
Our view on Blockchain
Got a quick chat with Ngoc Thanh, our Sr.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</guid><description>[DF APPRENTICESHIP 2022 - MEET THE MENTORS]
Dwarves Team is shifting our focus to blockchain technology. We offer study groups and blockchain-based projects for peeps to grow and catch up with this rising trend. Thanh is one of the vital elements of this team; and we know he’ll be more than happy to have you onboard.
What raises your interest for Dwarves?
“My path at Dwarves began with the zeal to develop web3 and blockchain products.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/apprentice/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</guid><description>Tuan Dao - Senior Frontend/ Blockchain Engineer
Tuan has 4+ years of experience under his belt, 2 out of those 4+ was spent at Dwarves Foundation. Tuan’s years of experience don’t quite do him justice though, for he’s skilled and knowledge beyond the year, and has took part in projects of various sizes and domains.
When asked what’s the force behind, Tuan shared it’s because of is very own principle of working: “To find joy in your profession”.</description></item><item><title>The stages of hiring at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/hiring-stages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/hiring-stages/</guid><description>Hey,
It’s Han and Nikki, back in your inbox for another Dwarves Updates.
First, we are delighted to share that Dwarves placed top 100 in the Financial Times’ Asia-Pacific High-Growth Company.
When we hustle daily, sometimes we forget to look back and pat ourselves in the back. This achievement serves as a reminder that we’re pretty darn good at what we’re doing.
Huge appreciation to our team, alongside our friends and partners, we’re lucky to have you move along with us.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</guid><description>A catch-up with Tom - our Data Lead, and hear how remote working has fit him perfectly. Tom is one of our core contributors of Dwarves Brainery, and he&amp;rsquo;ll be playing as a key mentor for our upcoming Apprenticeship.
Working remotely fits me well. It keeps me from distraction. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m always at home, so WFH is awesome. My previous workplace required people to be at the office and hang out for drinks afterward, and it was a bit overwhelmed in my pov.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</guid><description>Anh, in short, is the UI wizard behind most of our branding identity. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing her work of art on every Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s digital asset.
A person can take care of both UX and UI design if the project is small. As a product designer, you&amp;rsquo;re expected to know both. “I work for the graphic side, mainly on UI, app appearance, and app research to gain more insight for the team.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/life/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</guid><description>Been with us for nearly 5 years, Thanh has been taking care of the juniors and ensuring their progress goes alongside the company’s direction. He is also the co-host of Dwarves Radio Talk - our weekly tech training every Monday.
My job is to ensure a healthy environment for everyone to thrive. “I guide and train people if they are assigned to me. Dwarves Team has a 60-day Program to evaluate, and it usually is a 90-day plan, but based on the company size, the timeline can be adjusted to optimize its teammate growth.</description></item><item><title>January Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/january-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/january-updates/</guid><description>Project Highlights MStation as our latest blockchain-based project
It’s the first BSCS Metaverse blockchain game on Binance Smart Chain (BSC). Players can summon characters, complete daily mining missions, protect the MStation, loot rare items to play and earn.
We get to deploy a full team for this project, consist of 6 people, with Khai Le as part time PM and Ngọc Thành as Team Lead.
In general, we’re getting multiple upselling requests which means we need more people to join our team.</description></item><item><title>December All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/december-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/december-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>Moving with Blockchain We shift our focus to real deals.
Meanwhile, #blockchain #web3 channels are there for the Dwarves to learn &amp;amp; exchange their knowns. Grab your seat.
The teammates also propose to join blockchain projects. We’re happy onboard Hien, Tu and Ngoc Mai on Spike Inu and Eklipse - and actively seek more chances for our teammates.
Selective in Project Decision It’s a promise of bigger clients &amp;amp; better team deployment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of 2021</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/dwarves-of-2021/</guid><description>Dwarves of 2021 - We met at last ♡ Apart from the voting result from the team of each title, we also have the Honorable Mention and Client Endorsed - selected by the team leads, as we want to honor all of the hard work.
You can find the voting details here. The final result was close, since you’re all awesome!
Let’s all welcome our Dwarves of 2021 🛠</description></item><item><title>It’s a wrap: 2021 in Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/2021-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/2021-in-review/</guid><description>Hey, it’s Han and Nikki in your inbox again. On behalf of the entire Dwarves team, happy 2022!
For us 2021 is eventful, and memorable. It was full of changes and challenges, but our can-do mindset made us gritty. While we didn’t have all the answers, we decided to just try and do. As we state in our Agile Minifesto: fail fast, learn often, and it&amp;rsquo;s okay to start over.</description></item><item><title>Engineering organizational structure</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineering-org-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineering-org-structure/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. We&amp;rsquo;re almost at the end of this year. While we know everyone is busy wrapping up 2021, we hope you&amp;rsquo;re taking care of yourself and staying safe.
Remember last month when we mentioned refining our engineering ladder? Executing this one initiative was our main focus for the whole November. With this new way of looking at growth, we hope to be able to expand the team on top of a scalable foundation.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Ladder</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/engineering-ladder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/engineering-ladder/</guid><description>Engineering Ladder One of the biggest challenges in people management is determining whether your engineers are growing in their careers. While large companies have established career ladders, most companies sacrifice them to stay “flatter” and “more agile”. In reality, there’s no such thing as a “flat” organization—having one means that people don’t spend time talking about or thinking about levels and promotions because there are so many other things to do.</description></item><item><title>One on one meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/one-on-one-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/one-on-one-meeting/</guid><description>1 on 1 Our culture is founded upon the strong relationships between people. One-on-one meetings are the way to establish these relationships. Every manager has a 1-1 with each of their direct reports once a week, or whenever convenient for both parties involved. This page will take you through how we conduct a one-on-one at Dwarves Foundation as well as some tips to keep the meeting productive.
The first meeting The first one-on-one meeting is your chance to set a pattern and standard of how you and your manager feel good about the future and how you two want to interact.</description></item><item><title>The path to growth at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/path-to-growth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/path-to-growth/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. We&amp;rsquo;re here with the fifth edition of our Dwarves Updates. October has been a wild ride for us as a company. Most of our effort was spent on rethinking growth paths for our engineers.
The common scenarios with growth for engineers Growth is pretty easy during the first few years; conquer technical skills, discover tools and become proficient in using them, getting things done better and faster.</description></item><item><title>Engineer Performance Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineer-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineer-performance-review/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. Time does fly when we get to do something we love. As we keep working on building up the team and producing codes for our clients, we didn&amp;rsquo;t even notice it&amp;rsquo;s already the end of September. Here&amp;rsquo;s another update from Dwarves for you. Throughout September, we have completed our bi-annual performance review.
How we approach engineer performance review We all have our fair share of performance reviews, be it reviewing others or being reviewed.</description></item><item><title>Project Compliance</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/project-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/project-compliance/</guid><description>Hey,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han &amp;amp; Nikki from Team Dwarves. This email is the third month we share about our journey to Software Craftsmanship. The last two issues were in June and July. And we received quite a little feedback from our friends and past clients. Thanks for supporting.
This month, we share about how we do project delivery compliance.
How we do compliance If there&amp;rsquo;s something that we try to minimize at all costs, it&amp;rsquo;s risks.</description></item><item><title>Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 and reached a total seed funding of $4M by 2020, Search.io, formerly Sajari, is an AI-powered search and product discovery platform that helps eCommerce brands and retailers maximize their revenue and conversion rates through outcome-focused, real-time search result optimization. The Dwarves partnered with Search.io to help with their Console dashboard app, improve open-source packages quality and tailor the brand UI for plugin consumers. Search.io is one of those matured projects that requires stability over speed.</description></item><item><title>Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 as an innovation arm of INDODAX, Tokenomy is a crypto investment network through blockchain-enabled tokens. Currently reached the seed round funded by LazyLedger, Tokenomy aims to reach a broader customer segment through web platforms and mobile apps. We fully support a team of Senior Frontend Engineer, Android Mobile Engineer, and UX Designer to help them stay on track with the release timeline. Technical Highlight MVVM for mobile application architecture WebSocket for real-time trading support Reactivex to bind data and process asynchronous tasks Biometric authentication approach for data encryption Custom-built Android module to support different APIs Weekly product changelog apply for the team synergy The Context They came to us at first to refactor the frontend foundation.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Ventures Fund 1</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/fund/dwarves-ventures-fund-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/fund/dwarves-ventures-fund-1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Team Up With Basehq Us First Ever Platform Built For Assistants</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</guid><description>In brief Base launched in 2019 out of High Alpha Venture Studio, with a $2.6M funding round led by Matchstick Ventures with participation from Revolution&amp;rsquo;s Rise of the Rest Seed Fund, High Alpha Capital, and Slack Fund. Base is a software platform built specifically for executive assistants. Focus on smoothing out assistants&amp;rsquo; daily work. They demand a high integration between different platforms. We stepped in to make it happen. Through 2 years straight, they engaged with Dwarves to develop various new modules and features.</description></item><item><title>2021 July Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-july-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2021-july-updates/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re closing July with some notable highlights. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through them ✌️
🚨 *Note: Covid situation is getting worse. Stay safe. 🦠
*The pandemic is going stronger than ever. There has been over 100k internal cases over the country til now. Take good care of you and your beloved ones. We hope everyone can stay safe.
Finish the shipment for our WFH station We&amp;rsquo;ve finished the shipment for all the WFH gears.</description></item><item><title>Startupvn</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/startupvn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/startupvn/</guid><description>[startup.vn](http://startup.vn/) was founded 10 years ago, when the concept of "startups" was still fairly new in Vietnam. A handful of people from diverse backgrounds joined hands to create a homeland for Vietnamese who aim at building and growing their own businesses. 💡 **Fostering innovation and entrepreneurship in Vietnam since 2011.** What started out as a weekend passion project quickly progressed into a strong, proud, aspiring community. 10 years in, startup.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Intj</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-intj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-intj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Offers opportunities to work with people who are experts in their field Is on the cutting edge or innovative Provides opportunities to work on complex problems Is hard driving and achievement oriented Challenges people intellectually How Type Affects Career Exploration How you go about exploring career options will be influenced by your INTJ preferences. Your type will help you in your career exploration activities in distinct ways, just as it may present some distinct challenges for you.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Istp</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-istp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-istp/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Needs a more practical environment, where they can master skills and do things and see tangible results. Need variety and the opportunity to dip in and out of activities. The environment where their natural disregard for rules, authority and structures allows them to focus on and tackle the emergency at hand in the most effective way ISTP and Career Exploration An ISTP tends to find career satisfaction with careers that have the following characteristics:</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Estj</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-estj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-estj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Tasks Require thorough analysis Practical planning and organizational skills Process control and responsibility Preferred Work Environment Will fit best where the norms are clear The culture is performance driven. The place for everything and everything is in its place ESTJ prefer working with facts, details and the known, where the product or service is tangible rather than conceptual. Clear lines of responsibility and a planning process. Do not like to ‘wing it’ or take risks without being in possession of the facts and having thought things through.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Istj</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-istj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/mbti---type-istj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Company where the norms are clear The culture is performance driven and where there is a place for everything and everything is in its place. They prefer working with facts, details and the known, where the product or service is tangible rather than conceptual There are clear lines of responsibility and a planning process. They do not like to ‘wing it’ or take risks without being in possession of the facts and having thought things through so that they are clear.</description></item><item><title>Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</guid><description>Getting Started This is a part from our study how to recognize people traits at the first sight. This guide is made to help HRs or Project Lead have a quick view of potential candidates and/or new teammates personality. Working with nature is more productive than working against it.
No personality type is inherently better or more desirable than another in general. This reference is applied to the tech industry only.</description></item><item><title>The Four Preferences</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-four-preferences/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-four-preferences/</guid><description>The Four Preferences are:
Extraversion and Introversion When we talk about &amp;ldquo;extraversion&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;introversion&amp;rdquo;, we are distinguishing between the two worlds in which all of us live. There is a world inside ourselves, and a world outside ourselves. When we are dealing with the world outside of ourself, we are &amp;ldquo;extraverting&amp;rdquo;. When we are inside our own minds, we are &amp;ldquo;introverting&amp;rdquo;.
We are extraverting when we:
Talk to other people Listen to what someone is saying Cook dinner, or make a cup of coffee Work on a car We are introverting when we:</description></item><item><title>Making Decision As A Team Member</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</guid><description>Democracy in a Nutshell Sure we all heard of democracy. Mostly, this term appears in erhm, election?
However, from what I understand, democracy is maintained by giving decision-making power to the people. And not just &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; people. Your people.
We make sure they all feel respected. We all work in the same boat. It&amp;rsquo;s their benefit to care of, too. Letting people know the direction means sharing the responsibility, and sharing the responsibility equals reducing the risk.</description></item><item><title>Da Lat Office</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dalat-office/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dalat-office/</guid><description>Hey,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and the Dwarves team again. We work as a borderless software firm by crafting world-class products that bring great impacts for various industries.
Dwarves Updates notes down how we move toward that goal. You&amp;rsquo;re receiving this because we would love to have you as a part of the journey. It contains our lessons learned, our adoption, our investment in the team, and how we turn those experiences into our client&amp;rsquo;s success.</description></item><item><title>Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</guid><description>In brief
Momos is a pre-seed startup operating in Singapore, whose founder was an ex-Grab They look to ship the first MVP with a web platform to test the market and onboard promising users. Our team of 3 join them to bring development timeline up to speed as well as improving the core tech foundation to pave the way for a scalable, future-proof system. The collaboration happens remotely since March 2021.</description></item><item><title>Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</guid><description>In brief Attrace is a Netherland decentralized affiliate marketing network that audits action and bridges e-commerce websites to merchants. The core concept is applying referral for different blockchain product use cases They seek to launch MVP for market validation and early user acquisition Our team of 3 join them to contribute to Attrace&amp;rsquo;s core function with custom-made blockchain technology Highlight Blockchain solutions for multiples use-cases Golang for Backend system: Solidity and index blockchain data IPFS as files sharing system GDPR standard for data privacy Fraud detection &amp;amp; verification network The Context Attrace&amp;rsquo;s concept is a marketing platform that helps merchants feature and advertise their products.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dwarves-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dwarves-updates/</guid><description>Hi, this is Han, the CEO of Dwarves Foundation. This month the Dwarves score 40th client that we have the honor to serve. And for that, we decide to launch the Dwarves Updates.
As we build this company like we build a product, when we think about this approach, we ask different questions: Do people work here know how to use the company? Is it simple? Is it obvious how it works?</description></item><item><title>Supercharged Setel Malaysias First Pay Pump Go Super App</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</guid><description>In brief First introduced by PETRONAS in 2018, Setel is the first e-payment solution for fuel purchases directly from mobile devices. They head to unlock a bigger market by providing a super-app with on-the-go function and platform integration. Our team of 7 partners to involve in their engineering team in Unified Loyalty Platform, specialized in “Conversion” of new potential users. We focus on deals, vouchers, the front-landing page as well as Marketing tracking &amp;amp; integration.</description></item><item><title>Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2019, Para is a platform connecting hospitals with medical professionals. Continuing with Go microservices, we have shipped numerous features, markedly workshift management and candidate screening. We partnered and helped unburden Para from the financial stress during the early stage of their MVP development. Our Covid-19 program was launched in early 2020. We aim to provide software development, technical support for startups and businesses to help them stay stable during and progress forward despite the pandemic.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</guid><description>We started the 1st volume a year ago, mostly about assessing all the tech indexes we have adopted for 5 years. Then we moved to the 2nd volume, where we figured ways to simplify the workflow and complete our project toolkit.
And here we go again, another version of tech radar at Dwarves Foundation. 2021 has just gone through its first quarter, and we&amp;rsquo;ve left with some new toys to trial and see if they create any impact.</description></item><item><title>Support Relay In Shipping Their Mvp Product For Us Market Testing</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</guid><description>In brief Relay is an extension tool that decreases micromanagement by automating workflows. Relay&amp;rsquo;s first engagement with Dwarves aims to ship their MVP to market as quick as possible for early user acquisition. We dive in with 2 quickly adapt engineers. We keep a stable pace of feature shipment and adjust along with the requirements. Highlights
Slack app &amp;amp; Chrome extension. Custom semantic versioning for chrome extension. Combine flipper, sidekiq for A/B testing and gradually roll out new version.</description></item><item><title>Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</guid><description>Being in a remote team is dope. Manage your own stuff, remove the time and cost of commuting, select your work ambiance, and got equipped with all types of supporting tools.
Basecamp, for example.
Our path with Basecamp didn&amp;rsquo;t cross by accident. Years ago, we embarked on the Slack community and had it applied for internal communication. And project management on another tool, where documents &amp;amp; files are in G-suite. Every day is a short strip from one place to another.</description></item><item><title>Continuing Education Allowance</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/continuing-education-allowance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/continuing-education-allowance/</guid><description>Continuing Education Allowance You will always grow by learning and playing with new and cool technologies. From books to conferences, you’ll get a yearly budget for your learning and development goals.
If you’re interested in taking classes that you feel improve you professionally or personally, you have a $300 annual stipend to do so. Some people take courses directly related to their careers while taking photography lessons or learning a musical instrument.</description></item><item><title>Reimbursement</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/reimbursement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/reimbursement/</guid><description>Reimbursement Sometimes the situation calls for realtime payment. Team lunch, device purchase, house cleaning, monthly drinking water. Normally, we pay it forward and claim those expense later. The reimbursement will be included in your payroll of that month.
The request should follow this format in: Basecamp &amp;gt; Woodland &amp;gt; Request</description></item><item><title>Succeed Naru A Browser Focus Web Extension For Us Market</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</guid><description>In brief Being a digital designer who looks for inspiration and digital trends, Matt hopes for a productivity tool that could lend well to his browsing habit. Matt got in contact with us via a connection of a friend. We were surprised by the opportunity he provides: A browser extension for works management. We did explore web extension - but never had an opportunity for real trial. We take the chance to help bring it to market.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Ventures Fund 0</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/fund/dwarves-ventures-fund-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/fund/dwarves-ventures-fund-0/</guid><description>It all started when us, a couple of product people realized with our expertise in technology, our passion for outstanding software, we have the ability to uplift like-minded founders by helping them build and launch their startups. The idea became clearer when our network of makers, industry experts and investors broadened steadily.
We had every signal that a VC, by makers and for makers, would be the right path for us.</description></item><item><title>From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</guid><description>In brief
Mudah.my is a Malaysian 12-years-old online marketplace. A product derives from a partnership between Telenor ASA of Norway and 701Search Singapore. Currently holds 19.8% Internet share, Mudah meets the increase of customers demand, which led to an overload in the current system. We partnered to help migrating the monolithic architecture into microservices - Unlocking a scalable and feature-extendable platform We spent a month working on-site at Malaysia to directly participate in the work and speed up productivity Technical Highlight Massive migration from monolithic to microservice architecture.</description></item><item><title>Beyond The Title</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/beyond-the-title/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/beyond-the-title/</guid><description>The Common Dilemma You&amp;rsquo;re only paid that much to do that much We only pay you that much if you can do only that much It&amp;rsquo;s the scenario that people measure and expect their effort should be traded into paychecks. Employers issue fixed rates for labors, while employees refuse to do things that are not in the job description. It gradually forms a mindset where people decide to work &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to get paid and miss out on the chance to discover their self-limitation.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 1997 and has having 22 years in the market, Reapit is the largest CRM and Client Accounting software provider to the UK residential real estate sector. Reapit got acquired by Accel KKR in 2017 - which powered them to accelerate their growth and innovation potential in products and technology expansion Reapit wants to migrate the app from desktop-based to Cloud-based. They want to develop a PaaS to support an expandability for SME customer.</description></item><item><title>2020 In A Flashback</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2020-in-a-flashback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2020-in-a-flashback/</guid><description>Wrapping up 2019 with the first 5th-year milestone, many ideas popped up for the next steps. Heading to a new decade means we get to wrap up the old and in with the new. For us, the utmost target is to focus on territory expansion and team bootstrapping. Reinvest on the current foundation. Make it stable and make it impactful.
It handed us the chance to come up with more cool stuff.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</guid><description>Once every month, we gather for Radar update to round up the cool techs and assess if we should adopt that to the team. Road to a wider and more diversified rings, Dwarves Tech Radar v2 contains the practices to simplify the workflow, new techniques/ approach methods to upgrade our current standards, and **expand the domain knowledge. **
Trial Earthly: The combination Dockerfile + Makefile https://earthly.dev/
A repeatable syntax builds to untangle the debugging process between the local environment and the CI platform.</description></item><item><title>The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Aharooms wants to be a remarkable Vietnamese brand in franchised hotel chains. They look to enter the affordable hotel market to support business owners. Their vision was to build an MVP for market testing in no time. Aharooms&amp;rsquo;s system had almost 2 years in development. It demands high effort to balance new feature development with technical debt. We step in as product team and venture builder. We take on the development stage that supercharges their product development.</description></item><item><title>A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</guid><description>In brief CJC Ptd is a 20-year expert in providing market data consultancy &amp;amp; professional services for global financial sector. They want to make a new data ecosystem: Public and private cloud, containerization, software orchestration, AI to support the growth of DevOps We team up with them to develop Voconic - a cloud PaaS for CJC’s clients, aiming to make cloud deployment seamless across cloud providers and environment. Technical Highlight Backend, Frontend and CLI tools are built from scratch by engineers specialized in Cloud development Golang heavy backend integrated with Google Cloud Platform for 1-click deployment experience Deep integration with multiple cloud providers (Google &amp;amp; AWS) Complex system auto-deployment and configuration function CLI support for repetitive tasks and complex operation Separated services for file upload.</description></item><item><title>Setting The Budget</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/setting-the-budget/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/setting-the-budget/</guid><description>One of the most important questions at the start of a project is how much it will cost. It is vital to make sure that enough budget is available to allow for the development of a viable product.
The difficulty with setting a budget at the start of a project is that everyone is at the point of maximum ignorance. At the beginning of a project, all of the requirements have not matured.</description></item><item><title>Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</guid><description>In brief Founded by Desmond Goh - a Singaporean dental surgeon, Dental Marketplace is an online platform for dental professionals to stay active in dentistry and simplify operation process. Web and App development as MVP release for marketing testing and user feedback. We support them with tech solution and market-fit product design. We work according with Desmond to extract business problem and propose suitable solution. Technical Highlight Product-fit Design: Design Thinking Method &amp;amp; Design UX research for Golang-backend: Steady and microservices-extendable system Startup-centric: Scalable system &amp;amp; cost-efficient solution Microservice architecture Agile process and Scrum framework for product iteration The Context Singapore dentists faces bottlenecks to practice dentistry and operates dental clinic with SDC rules licensed regulated by MOH.</description></item><item><title>Go The Extra Mile</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/go-the-extra-mile/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/go-the-extra-mile/</guid><description>A couple days ago, I was asked if I were ever a product person, what would I do to make the best out of it.
It took me a while. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;ve never walked in this shoe before. Wth is a product person? I wondered. And I started digging. Here it is, &amp;ldquo;Making sure your product/ thing shipped out flawlessly.&amp;rdquo; A perfectionist mindset.
Sounds a bit crazy, yet a lil intrigued.</description></item><item><title>The Dwarves Runs By Ideas</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-dwarves-runs-by-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-dwarves-runs-by-ideas/</guid><description>Minimal human intervention Our operations runs on four branches: Account for client happiness arrangement - PeopleOps for resource allocation - Human Resource for recruitment and employee experience, &amp;amp; Communication for info transmission across the platforms.
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit different from other operations flows out there. But we do it on purpose.
We figure a small team is easier to share perspectives, update on what&amp;rsquo;s happening and discuss different work aspects.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</guid><description>The Dwarves have their tradition to explore the tech scene and learn new things. Dwarves Tech Radar kicked the initial step since January of 2020.
It is the first time we sit down and do it in written form. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard for the engineers at first, but we managed to complete the volume with ten reports.
Besides volume 01, we have an opportunity to sort out our current technology index and put it at https://d.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</guid><description>Our Perspective on Technology Technology is eating the world. The technology we used yesterday may be deprecated today. New technology has enabled us to create new things. With the existing set of problems, new solutions will emerge along with new technologies.
Over five years of working as an innovative software firm, other than the energetic tech-savvy workforce, we shape the team day by day with the core values that move towards the engineering culture.</description></item><item><title>Routine</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/routine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/routine/</guid><description>Work routine As stated in how we work, we keep the team small and follow the agile philosophy at scale.
We work in an 8-week cycle at Dwarves Foundation. There are typically six cycles to a year. This fixed cadence serves to give us an internal sense of urgency, work as a scope hammer to keep projects from ballooning and provide a regular interval to decide what we’re working on.</description></item><item><title>A Tips Of Hiring - Do &amp; Don't</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</guid><description>Many companies out there get lured by the vision of &amp;ldquo;scaling up&amp;rdquo;. An unwritten rule of &amp;rsquo;the more man we have, the better output we create&amp;rsquo;. But no, hiring with no motivation only leads to one thing: A waste of resource.
Hire without plan bored talent people out. There&amp;rsquo;s no good to put people in a place where they can&amp;rsquo;t create any impact. And we? We tend to fall for creating unnecessary job, which results in a waste of money and training resource.</description></item><item><title>The Dwarves Culture Handbook</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</guid><description>For the past 5 years, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have something called &amp;lsquo;Culture Book&amp;rsquo;. Whenever a newbie steps in, it&amp;rsquo;s natural to pick up the job and go with the flow. We hardly force them into other periodical office traps like team-bonding activities or late night drinks. It&amp;rsquo;s likely to be &amp;lsquo; Hey it&amp;rsquo;s your birthday give us a treat&amp;rsquo;; and next thing you know, 30 milk tea or coffee orders are on the way.</description></item><item><title>Fixed Budget Scope Controlled</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</guid><description>Fixed-Budget, Scope-Controlled (FBSC) is applied at Atomic Object. They build custom software for our customers. Because of the complexity involved in building a great software product, software development projects are always more difficult to price than a product.
As a result two different strategies for pricing services, such as building software, have traditionally been used by most companies. These are called “Fixed Price” and “Time And Materials”.
Fixed Price A Fixed Price strategy locks in the total price of the project upfront.</description></item><item><title>The Adjacent Possible</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/the-adjacent-possible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/business/the-adjacent-possible/</guid><description>During our study about innovation, we find the topic of adjacent possible. Innovation happens but not many people can point out clearly. Getting to know the foundation of innovation helps understanding its natures and could lead to further exploration. Enjoy your reading.
Innovation deepens our knowledge and understanding of the world, it extends our reach and access to resources. More importantly, innovation expands the realm of what we can do with all our knowledge and resources: deliver new goods and products, bring forward new types of organisations and services, and in more general terms develop new ideas and concepts.</description></item><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/purpose/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/purpose/</guid><description>Where we are heading We start with purpose. The mankind is here today because of 4 billion years of continuous evolution from a single cell to homo sapiens, through the stone age to bronze, iron, medieval to post-classical and renaissance. The nations and our civilization were built on production, on building.
Every time we look back at what we are as a race; in the beginning, we feel motivated by what the ancestors have done.</description></item><item><title>How People Matter Should Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/how-people-matter-should-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/how-people-matter-should-work/</guid><description>We get to read many articles these days that states &amp;lsquo;People are the Core of the Business&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;Why People are the Key to Success&amp;rsquo;, or something like that. Something that polishes the importance of human to the company. Something that emphasizes how HR should do their best to nurture the talents.
But here&amp;rsquo;s the funny thing. Most of those talks drive the audience back to tips. How to make people happy.</description></item><item><title>Delegation And Believe It Will Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t always make things (or everything) on our own. If that somehow truly happens, then Inc, Corp, Enterprise or Group won&amp;rsquo;t stand a chance with Freelancers.
So why delegating? At least, in business, delegation means having extra people to help distribute the stress, provides a gathered source of information, and a couple of extra hands to slap when our thought goes wrong. Delegation also gives delegator more time &amp;amp; effort to focus on other things, or sometimes just a perfect excuse to grab a beer instead of burying their heads in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Constructive Feedback</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/constructive-feedback/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/constructive-feedback/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s in human nature to instantly lose their mind when things get hard, and somehow they split nasty things that can&amp;rsquo;t be undone. So, to reduce the ratio of unnecessary conflicts, let&amp;rsquo;s make the feedback great again.
Know the Time Define the frame for listening and for questioning. Talk blocking isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to express how you feel. If you don&amp;rsquo;t respect other&amp;rsquo;s time of present, they have no reason to give a shit about what you think on their idea.</description></item><item><title>Transparency</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/transparency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/transparency/</guid><description>***How much do you know about this woodland?*** → is the question we all get during the first interview. Sure, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to nail the final offer; you&amp;rsquo;re likely to get a better chance on gradually discovering the company&amp;rsquo;s essential information.
But then what?
You step on the project. You get swiped away in work. You check up the daily to-do. And you have no idea what&amp;rsquo;s happening in other places.</description></item><item><title>Bric A Brac</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/bric-a-brac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/bric-a-brac/</guid><description> Outsource things which are super important but we are not excellent at. Spend time selecting a vendor and occasionally spend time reevaluating other vendors. Automate repetitive tasks. Give everyone &amp;ldquo;admin&amp;rdquo; access to as much as possible to avoid bottlenecks. Our problems are not unique. We will try manual processes first. When we do build something, it is usually after using other things for years</description></item><item><title>Account</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/account/</guid><description>Planning
Many people would say in order to have a good plan; you need to write out all vibrant details. A good plan needs lots of details, they said. But in real life, where nothing is certain and is filled with sudden surprises, a good plan should prioritize its flexibility and simplicity.
Start with the main goals of the week, then expand on the actual required actions to achieve those desired goals.</description></item><item><title>Avoid Burn Out</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/avoid-burn-out/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/avoid-burn-out/</guid><description>Just to be clear, this term has nothing to compare with the emotional crisis you go through daily - stress. No, burn-out isn&amp;rsquo;t stress.
It describes the state of physical and emotional exhaustion. Burnout reduces and sucks out your productivity. As it develops, it beats every single reason that once was your working motto. The interest, the creativity and motivation gets faded away. Your job might be done, but you no longer feel satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Writing Management Objectives In Smart</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</guid><description>S.M.A.R.T. goals are a relatively new idea. In 1981, George T. Doran, a consultant and former director of corporate planning for Washington Water Power Company, published a paper called, “There’s a S.M.A.R.T. Way to Write Management’s Goals and Objectives.” In the document, he introduces S.M.A.R.T. goals as a tool to create criteria to help improve the chances of succeeding in accomplishing a goal
S – Specific When setting a goal, be specific about what you want to accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Building A Solid High Performing Team</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</guid><description>Sustainable growth companies are built by teams of shining constellations rather than just several bright stars
It all starts with recruiting. Many successes and disasters start with recruiting. Recruiting is the most important job for any real leader in the company
The second step is all about the right placement of the stars in your constellation. No matter what bullshit motivational book you may have read, people do not change. Yes, people do evolve, and yes, those not capable of evolution should never become a part of your team, but for Pete’s sake, do not confuse skill evolution with personality change.</description></item><item><title>Hiring For Operations Team</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/hiring-for-operations-team/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/hiring-for-operations-team/</guid><description>Operations is a very sensitive area of the company, so be very picky. A great ops person can dramatically improve the way your company works and make your life a lot easier
Operations is operations, no matter the industry
Operations problems are almost the same everywhere (in ultra-specialized and regulated industries we just surround ourselves with specialists and attorneys). Industry experience is helpful, but not as much as you think</description></item><item><title>Looking Back 2019</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/looking-back-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/looking-back-2019/</guid><description>Another year has gone by. And we just celebrated the 5th year that we survived all the challenges. Everyone was facing their own, but I have seen many of you reaching new stages and achieve new targets.
We have been growing up together. As for your recall, end of 2018, we were about 30s. End of this year, we are about 50s. End of 2018, we were young and inexperienced. End of this year, we are just inexperienced (j/k).</description></item><item><title>Delegate Work Not Responsibility</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</guid><description>We can bring in all the technology in the world, but if we can’t delegate properly, our companies have no chance of scaling well
Delegating work does not absolve you of responsibility. In the case of a failure, the blame is all yours. Investors will go after the CEO, even if an intern made the mistake that hurt the company. If a failure occurs due to person you delegated work to lacking skills, it is your fault you delegated work to the wrong person.</description></item><item><title>Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</guid><description>In brief Getting the early funding for over 40M US dollar, beGroup focuses to roll out all 4 products by the end of 2018. By that time, there were only 6 months before the debut. beCorporate is a module to manage and optimize in-house business transports for employee.
They look to ship in short timeline. The current engineering team was working on the 1st release of ride-hailing app. Wrap-up beCorporate adds a step in perfecting their service.</description></item><item><title>Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</guid><description>In brief AirWatt is an IoT solution that integrates and monitors electricity usage using AI/ML. AirWatt&amp;rsquo;s vision is to help businesses track electric usage status of electrical equipment. Hence, they can save electricity and money, even avoid disaster. They seek for product development support, with insight on business to provide suitable product design The MVP must be done fast to prove the product&amp;rsquo;s concept. We built Airwatt system from zero with other teams: Business, Hardware, and AI.</description></item><item><title>Making a Career</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/making-a-career/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/making-a-career/</guid><description>Making a Career The average tenure of employees working at many technology companies today is shockingly low. At both Amazon, Google and other companies, it’s just around one year. At Dwarves Foundation, it’s just around three years as of late 2018. That’s something to be proud of, and something to ensure endures. When you work at Dwarves Foundation, it should be feasible to think about this as the place for making a life-long career.</description></item><item><title>Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</guid><description>Introduction BHD is one of the biggest cinema chains in Vietnam with hundreds of thousands tickets sold monthly. However, its mobile application is a complete drawback; users cannot book tickets online, it feels and looks outdated, inconsistent and cluttered.
Mission BHD’s new app covers all the basic needs of movie-goers, in an intuitive and pleasant way. Meaning, users can easily scan screening schedules, view movie details and book tickets online.</description></item><item><title>Email Communication and Use</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/email-communication-and-uses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/email-communication-and-uses/</guid><description>Email Communication and Use We use email as our formal tool for both internal and external communication.
Every email is utilized for a specific field, which comes along with different instructions.
We currently go with these:
Communication 1. team@d.foundation For external communication. Clients or people outside the company should only know this email to communicate with us.
Every email composed by team@d.foundation should be meant for external contacts, such as agreement or announcement.</description></item><item><title>How we keep things on track</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/compliance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/compliance/</guid><description>How we keep things on track Building an effective company is like building good software: First, we define the specs. Then we implement the specs. After that, we test and make sure everything works correctly. So, first we need to define the specs, in this case: Define standard for the company We already produced our playbook as the specs so that our company has a base to run on. It&amp;rsquo;s a place where the newcomer learns new stuff, the current members have a reference for the information that they needed.</description></item><item><title>Assets</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/assets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/assets/</guid><description>Asset Request Company assets equips us to get the job done. We are delighted to know if you can spend your time gnawing our library or using our devices, as long as it follows these protocols.
1. Borrowing We use Basecamp the team communication tool. Woodland is where public things happen. In the Request list in Todo, create a ticket with this format:
Your Name | Type - Name/Id of the asset | Borrowing date | Returning date</description></item><item><title>Benefits &amp; Perks</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/benefits-and-perks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/benefits-and-perks/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Since most Dwarves Foundation employees work in Saigon, this section is written with that as the default. Some benefits don&amp;rsquo;t make sense in other countries. We will try our best to provide comparable benefits and perks as it makes sense, though.
Team Growth Continuing Education Allowance (CEA) We encourage you to grow by learning and playing with new technologies. You&amp;rsquo;ll get a yearly budget for your learning and development goals, from books to conferences.</description></item><item><title>Effective Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/effective-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/effective-meeting/</guid><description>Effective Meeting To increase flexibility in how and where employees at Dwarves work, we agree on a shared set of constraints for group work and meetings.
Using the right Scheduling tool for meeting For meetings that only include internal recipients, it should be scheduled on Basecamp in the correct project/team and inform the people related. If it is all-hands meeting it should be schedule on Woodlands and inform the whole company.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/faq/</guid><description>FAQ How to pronounce the company name?
Dwarf is one of the hardest words to pronounce to the non-English speaker, but that’s what made we special. Checkout how to pronounce dwarf on YouTube
/dwɔːf/
It’s like ‘đ-ô-p’ with a ‘tr’ in between -&amp;gt; /đ-tr-ô-p/
Just in case people don’t get it?
We can give them the alias email @d.foundation
Do we have a theme song?
An intern randomly suggested not an official one but a theme song in 2017 DragonForce - Three Hammers</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/getting-started/</guid><description>Getting Started Expectation Welcome onboard. Getting started at Dwarves Foundation can be overwhelming. Different roles have different expectation. Get to know who does what to warm up. There are a lot of little details, a number of big tasks, you’re learning a new job and new coworkers, and you’re likely doing all these things while working remotely.
At the orientation meeting, we will let you know what we expect you during the probation period.</description></item><item><title>How We Hire</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-hire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-hire/</guid><description>How we hire Hiring means we need help. We only hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. We always look for long-term teammates that why we want to ensure the new hire is a value fit and culture fit.
We hire with goal That means we seek for teammate who matches our mutual personas: Independent - Teamwork - Problem-solving Mindset - Try hard.</description></item><item><title>How we spend money</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-spend-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-spend-money/</guid><description>How we spend money We do the business to provide engineering capabilities to help customers on their business. A part of the benefits package is the Stock Option Plan, and the money is the sensitive topic in most companies, but we want you to understand so you could commit your best to make Dwarves Foundation a right place to work.
Besides the paycheck that we agreed on the employment contract, the revenue split into a various portion</description></item><item><title>Leave Request</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/leave-request/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/guides/leave-request/</guid><description>Leave Request A consistent on leave process prevents a company from being accidentally disrupted when an employee request to be absent.
At our woodland, every time an employee submit a request for on leave or remote work, whether it is for half-shift or all day absence, the process shall be required to follow these following steps:
1. Request submission Employee must submit the request within double the time he or she is absent.</description></item><item><title>Marketing Assets</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/marketing-assets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/marketing-assets/</guid><description> Marketing Assets About: https://d.foundation/about Logo &amp;amp; Icon: https://d.foundation/presskit Company Vietnam Name: Dwarves Foundation Company Limited Office: 222 Vo Thi Sau, D3, Ho Chi Minh 700000 Phone: +84 28 2246 0246 US Name: Dwarves, LLC Address: 2035 Sunset Lake Road, Suite B-2 Newark, Delaware 19702 Phone: +1 (818) 408 6969</description></item><item><title>Moonlighting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/moonlighting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/moonlighting/</guid><description>Moonlighting Moonlighting means working other professional, paid jobs outside of your work at Dwarves Foundation. It’s not a black and white topic. There are one-time gigs, other pursuits, or opportunities that help you grow and make life interesting. We want to support that. However, we want to make sure professional endeavors outside of Dwarves Foundation don’t create conflicts of interest or affect your time, dedication, or performance at Dwarves Foundation.</description></item><item><title>Places to work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/places-to-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/places-to-work/</guid><description>Places to work Noise Levels If you’re doing creative work, research suggests you’ll want to be surrounded byambient noise. A café or co-working space is the perfect choice in this case.
If you need to focus on a specific task, however, you’re going to want silence as quiet spaces help us focus on straightforward tasks .
Coffitivity: https://coffitivity.com | https://soundcloud.com/coffitivity Noizio: http://noiz.io Rainy mood: http://rainymood.com In other studies, people has found that exposure to certain colors can play a role as well.</description></item><item><title>Security Rules</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/security-rules/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/security-rules/</guid><description>Basic Security Keeping laptops and phones secure is vitally important. We&amp;rsquo;re a software company and many of us have access to secure systems (both our own and our customers).
The following guidelines apply to how we physically secure our laptops and mobile devices that may contain customer or user data.
General Make a note of serial numbers, model information Two Factor Authentication and strong passwords Keep your operating system and applications up to date Lock your device when you are away from it.</description></item><item><title>Tools and Systems</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/tools-and-systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/tools-and-systems/</guid><description>Public-facing channel Website Foundation: dwarves.foundation Ventures: dwarves.ventures Careers: dwarves.careers Social Network Instagram: https://instagram.com/dwarves.foundation Facebook: https://facebook.com/dwarvesf Twitter: @dwarvesf Keybase: keybase.io/team/dwarvesf.alumni Tools &amp;amp; Systems Besides the customer-facing applications, like the different versions of the website, we have a number of internal systems that help us support, report, and operate the company. They are as follows:
1Password 1Password is where we store the credential to other cloud services. A different group of people has access to particular vaults.</description></item><item><title>What we stand for</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/what-we-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/what-we-stand-for/</guid><description>What we stand for Empower Innovation with Software Craftsmanship Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.
Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time.</description></item><item><title>what-we-value</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/what-we-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/what-we-value/</guid><description>What we value Before anything else, values come first. The value is important to us. They are what we proud of. They help guide us when we are facing a difficult decision. They will be the things you like about what we do at Dwarves Foundation and how we do it.
Our core values guide our strategies and individual actions so that we create a company whose character is as radical as our work.</description></item><item><title>Where we work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/where-we-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/where-we-work/</guid><description>Where we work Office The Dwarves HQ is in Saigon, Vietnam. Fifty-ish people and two cats have desk space in the Saigon office, but those people also work from home regularly. We expand the office space when the old one is full and people want the new office. Anyone is welcome to visit Saigon and work from the office at any time.
From home A few people at Dwarves Foundation are based in other countries and they work from home most of the time.</description></item><item><title>Who does what</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/who-does-what/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/who-does-what/</guid><description>Who does what Figuring out whom to bring a particular issue or question to shouldn’t be a guessing game. Most concerns fall pretty clearly within the responsibility of a specific team at Dwarves Foundation, and the head of that team should be the first point of contact. At the same time, every single person who works at Dwarves Foundation is approachable and friendly, more than willing to point you in the right direction.</description></item><item><title>You are Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/dwarves-foundation-is-you/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/dwarves-foundation-is-you/</guid><description>You are Dwarves Foundation Everyone working at Dwarves Foundation represents Dwarves Foundation. When a customer gets a response from Quang on support, Quang is Dwarves Foundation. When a customer reads a tweet by Huy that our systems are upgrading, Huy is Dwarves Foundation. When an engineer talks to you at a meetup, you are Dwarves Foundation. In those situations, all the other stuff we do to cultivate our best image is secondary.</description></item><item><title>2018 Wrapping Up</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2018-wrapping-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/2018-wrapping-up/</guid><description>2018 was the memorable year with lots of achievements.
We adapted the new team structure.
We defined things we value and live that culture tediously.
We moved to new office. We welcomed the new dwarves to join us.
We scaled up from 15 to 30ish with all the smart people gathering around and commit to the dream of building our first global software company.
We learned how to do things right and started using it to help deliver quality software.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 1</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</guid><description>Introduction The following case study is my first app design project. In this project, I have gone through the design process, including interviews, analysis, user flows, wireframes, prototyping, and user testing.
The mobile app Sol is a travel app focused on some highlight features: planning trips, managing members and expenses, and tracking/sharing location. In facts, when traveling by groups, we often face some troubles: getting lost, confusing with plans, hard-communicating and the most challenging thing: managing expenses.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 3</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</guid><description>Introduction Today we shall continue our series of designing “Sol-Travel Planning” app. As we mentioned our process on UX research and UI design in the last two articles, Sol’s target users are the young so keeping the app fun with interaction is a must.
Main Motions According to Issara Willenskomer from UxinMotion, motion implementation in UX design can greatly help improving usability in four noticeable ways: fulfilling expectation from the users, maintaining continuity among a set of scenes, inventing narrative — story-telling flow throughout the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 2</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</guid><description>Following the previous article on UX case study of Sol — Travel App, an app that was tailored to meet the needs of groups on traveling days. In this article, we will describe our creative process of the UI for it. We choose iOS as our platform to be presented, considering that it is the more favored devices being used.
As we have gone through the UX research tasks in the last article, we started brainstorming about how the mobile application should look.</description></item><item><title>Types Of Employees</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/types-of-employees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/types-of-employees/</guid><description>There are 2 types of employees:
There are employees who think of the company like a job. They come in, they work hard, and they do their job. Some excel at doing their job. But ultimately, it’s a job. They want to make sure they’re fairly compensated for their work, and have interesting projects to work on. As long as they believe those things are in balance and the compensation arbitrage they can get by going to another company is within a certain bound, they’re stable and stay.</description></item><item><title>Conduct A Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/conduct-a-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/conduct-a-meeting/</guid><description>Meeting has always played an integral part in every corporate office. To optimize a productive meeting, it is vital to conduct individuals gathering without wasting time and directly get to the point, to deliver new information or discuss crucial issues.
And that begins with a smooth collaboration between these following essential aspects.
1. Timeline Announce meeting time at least one day before the meeting happens. Create Google Meet link Sync on Basecamp schedule Notify all related participants.</description></item><item><title>Hiring Approach</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/hiring-approach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/hiring-approach/</guid><description>Philosophy Hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. Company culture is who you Hire, Fire &amp;amp; Promote. Short term vs. long term evaluation Values fit &amp;amp; culture fit Principles Hiring means we failed to execute and need help Startup employee effectiveness follows a power law False Positives are ok, False Negatives are not Culture is defined by who we hire The best thing you can do for employees — a perk better than foosball or free sushi — is hire only “A” players to work alongside them.</description></item><item><title>How We Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/handbook/how-we-work/</guid><description>How we work Hopefully, before joining us, you have discovered a bit about our activities here as a team. In the below sections, we won&amp;rsquo;t repeat what has been out in our public and try to keep it short.
We do Agile We build software. The way we see it is a collaboration between multiple people in the team with sufficient knowledge on the domain and clearly understand the project vision that they can quickly adapt to the changes in the market.</description></item><item><title>The Okr</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-okr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-okr/</guid><description>What is OKR OKR (Object and Key Result) is a management methodology, an outcome-driven tracking framework.
Object : is a goal we want to achieve
**Key Results : **are a set of explaination for how will we know we are getting there.
For example
In Q1/2018 DF&amp;rsquo;s objective is want to build a strong backend team, so &amp;ldquo;**build a strong backend team&amp;rdquo; **is an object, to accomplish that, we will hire 2 senior backend developers and **organize 1 training session per week, **each of them is a key result to let us know whether we are getting to our objective or not.</description></item><item><title>Our Metrics For Performance Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</guid><description>$$ P = f(r, t, c, r) $$
Performance - P Performance is a final value that will be calculated from other metrics. This value will help to indicate how good all the activities we&amp;rsquo;ve done to make the company could grow.
Metrics will be marked from the scale from 1 to 5:
1 is bad 3 is normal 5 is outstanding 1 ---- 2 ---- 3 ---- 4 ---- 5 bad good outstand Context of example</description></item><item><title>Make Remote Working Works</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/make-remote-working-works/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/make-remote-working-works/</guid><description>Being office-present keeps you effective. Firms lean on that. It explains why companies are down to invest a fortune on building creative office with other benefit packages. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about that. I&amp;rsquo;m just saying there are others ways to keep people excited without costing too much operation cost.
The Dwarves lives with some principles. First, we feel no need to manage your chairs. We have better things to do with our time.</description></item><item><title>Blocking Distraction</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/blocking-distraction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/blocking-distraction/</guid><description>Finding solitude in information overwhelming world
Nowadays, we are connected 247, every minute passes by there are new things happens, new notifications, endless distractions. Sometimes, it is too hard to focus and it affect our life quality a lot.
So there are couple things that we can do to avoid this problem.
Spend time to be alone everyday It can be 1–2 hours and you can truly focus on what ready matter.</description></item><item><title>Effective Meeting</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/effective-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/effective-meeting/</guid><description>To increase flexibility in how and where employees at Dwarves work, we agree on a shared set of constraints for group work and meetings.
Meeting Etiquette Meetings start on time
If you&amp;rsquo;re leading a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to start the meeting on time. If you&amp;rsquo;re attending a meeting, you are responsible for showing up on time.
Meetings happen in regular hours
All team members should make themselves available for face-to-face meetings between 10:30am - 1:00p, as long as they are scheduled at least 24 hours in advance.</description></item><item><title>Our Policy For Remote Working</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-policy-for-remote-working/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-policy-for-remote-working/</guid><description>Some useful practices we adopted to keep the remote working system goes smoothly.
This policy is written in the context of our current company setup. Specifically, this document addresses working from home on a regular basis. It goes valid for
A full-remote team. Individuals that manages and responsible for their work. Even when we aren&amp;rsquo;t in the office, our teammates are still counting on us and it is our responsibility to make sure we are exceeding their expectations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/common-component/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/common-component/</guid><description>Heading components section Heading 1 Heading 2 Heading 3 Heading 4 Heading 5 Heading 6 Alternate Syntax for Heading 1 and Heading 2 under Headings sections Heading 1 Heading level 2 Paragraph components section Paragraph example
Line Break components section Paragraph example
Line break paragraph example
Emphasis components section This is component Bold
Bold example
This is component Italic
Italic example
This is component Bold and Italic
Bold and Italic example</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/duy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/duy/</guid><description> duy contact - Contributed Notes The Manifesto Life at Dwarves Culture Handbook</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/han/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/han/</guid><description> han contact https://twitter.com/abaddeed
https://bsky.app/profile/han.bsky.social
https://github.com/tieubao Contributed Notes 💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions Partners Network The Manifesto</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/hnh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/hnh/</guid><description> hnh contact https://github.com/huynguyenh Contributed Notes $icy Salary Advance $icy in 2024 Starting your journey at Dwarves Discord $icy withdrawal Submit a Bounty Rework Fortress Command $icy utility commands $icy store Fortress Mma Score $icy staking Fortress Shanky Data Archive Open Bounties Home</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/huytq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/huytq/</guid><description> huytq contact https://twitter.com/0xLight Contributed Notes Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines Estimation Guidelines Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions Consulting Team</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/innno_/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/innno_/</guid><description> innno_ contact https://github.com/innnotruong Contributed Notes Starting your journey at Dwarves Discord</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/longddl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/longddl/</guid><description> longddl contact https://longdatadevlog.wordpress.com/
https://blogs.longdatadevlog.com/blog/
https://github.com/longbuivan Contributed Notes Quick Learning Vector Database Data Pipeline Design Framework</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/mickwan1234/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/mickwan1234/</guid><description> mickwan1234 contact https://github.com/mickwan1234 Contributed Notes Google Dataproc Google Data Fusion</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/minhcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/minhcloud/</guid><description> minhcloud contact https://github.com/minhcloud Contributed Notes How to push content on note.d.foundation How to withdraw ICY Home</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/monotykamary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/monotykamary/</guid><description>monotykamary contact https://www.linkedin.com/in/nguyenxuananh/
https://twitter.com/monotykamary Contributed Notes Labs Weekly Catchup #5 Labs Weekly Catchup #4 Labs Weekly Catchup #3 Labs Weekly Catchup #2 Labs Weekly Catchup #1 DuckDB demo and showcase Labs Team Market Report Jan 2024 Market Report Feb 2024 Market Report Dec 2023 Events Starting your journey at Dwarves Discord How to withdraw ICY Estimation Guidelines October Forward Engineering 2023 November Forward Engineering 2023 December Forward Engineering 2023 Forward Engineering August 2023 Contributors Consulting Team Changelog Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust Move internal notes to note.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/nikki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/nikki/</guid><description> nikki contact https://github.com/nikkingtr Contributed Notes Dwarves Community Partners Network Consulting - Who We Are Consulting - Who should join us Consulting - How we work Consultant Growth Track What&amp;rsquo;s New in October 2023 What&amp;rsquo;s New in November 2023 What&amp;rsquo;s New in January 2024 What&amp;rsquo;s New in February 2024 2023 Dec + title Changelog Technical Recruiter React Native Developer Marketing and Communications Specialist Executive Assistant Business Development Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust The Manifesto Life at Dwarves Culture Handbook</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/thanh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/thanh/</guid><description> thanh contact https://github.com/zlatanpham Contributed Notes Reward Model &amp;amp; Nomination Market Report Jan 2024 Market Report Feb 2024 Market Report Dec 2023 Labs x Consulting Workflow Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update) Labs - Who we are Labs - Topic proposal &amp;amp; progress tracking Labs - New Member Onboarding Knowledge Journey How R&amp;amp;D contributes to Performance Review October Forward Engineering 2023 November Forward Engineering 2023 December Forward Engineering 2023 Forward Engineering August 2023 Engineering Ladder Trend Command</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/vitran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/contributor/vitran/</guid><description> vitran contact https://github.com/tranthiaivi266 Contributed Notes Technical Recruiter Executive Assistant Business Development</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/events/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/links/</guid><description> Dwarves Index Website Home: d.foundation Brain: brain.d.foundation Note: note.d.foundation Discord: discord.gg/dwarvesv Console Labs: console.so Careers: careers.d.foundation Memo: memo.d.foundation Changelogs: log.d.foundation Shortcut Earn: https://note.d.foundation/earn Radar: https://radar.d.foundation/ Handbook: github.com/dwarvesf/handbook Playbook: github.com/dwarvesf/playbook Team Profiling: link.d.foundation/profiling Signature: sign.d.foundation Fortress: fortress.d.foundation Programming Github: github.com/dwarvesf Gitlab: git.d.foundation Mermaid: mermaid.d.foundation Vault: v.d.foundation Hashnode: https://dwarvesf.hashnode.dev/ Community LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/dwarvesf/ Facebook: facebook.com/dwarvesf Twitter: twitter.com/dwarvesf Instagram: instagram.com/dwarves.foundation Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/@dwarvesfoundation2350 Medium: https://medium.com/dwarves-foundation</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/12-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/12-factor-app/</guid><description>The 12-factor App The 12-factor apps let us write modern software as a service which is easy to deploy, scale up, maximize portability, and minimize time, the cost for new developers joining the project.
You can read more about the philosophy of the 12-factor app https://12factor.net. Here we only show how we apply those in real projects.
Codebase One codebase tracked in revision control, many deploys
A twelve-factor app is always tracked in a version control system.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/android/</guid><description>Best practices in Android development Avoid reinventing the wheel by following these guidelines.
Summary Use Gradle and its default project structure Put passwords and sensitive data in gradle.properties Use the Jackson library to parse JSON data Don&amp;rsquo;t write your own HTTP client, use OkHttp libraries Avoid Guava and use only a few libraries due to the 65k method limit Sail carefully when choosing between Activities and Fragments Layout XMLs are code, organize them well Use styles to avoid duplicate attributes in layout XMLs Use multiple style files to avoid a single huge one Keep your colors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/backend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/backend/</guid><description>Best practices in backend development N Commandments General points on guidelines Development environment setup in README.md Data persistence General considerations SaaS, cloud-hosted or self-hosted? Persistence solutions RDBMS NoSQL Document storage Key-value store Graph database Bill of Materials Security Docker Credentials Secrets Login Throttling User Password Storage Audit Log Suspicious Action Throttling and/or blocking Anonymized Data Temporary file storage Dedicated vs Shared server environment Checklists Responsibility checklist Release checklist General questions to consider Generally proven useful tools N Commandments README.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/basic-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/basic-security/</guid><description>Basic Security Devices Keeping laptops and phones secure is vitally important. We&amp;rsquo;re a software company and many of us have access to secure systems (both our own and our customers).
The following guidelines apply to how we physically secure our laptops and mobile devices that may contain customer or user data.
General Make a note of serial numbers, model information Two Factor Authentication and strong passwords Keep your operating system and applications up to date Lock your device when you are away from it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/</guid><description>Best practices in blockchain development N Commandments Encryption knowledge Basic concepts Digital signature extension Merkle tree Blockchain Basics [Learn the basics of Distributed Ledger Technology] Ethereum blockchain Elliptic Curve Cryptography Proof of Work Proof of Stake [Practical Byzantine Fault Tolerance] [Development environment setup in README.md] [Hardhat] [Anchor] [Blockchain data] [General considerations] [Introduction to Distributed Storage] [Persistence solutions] [IPFS] [SWARM] [Learn Solidity] [Solidity Smart contract basic] [Remix IDE] [Smart contract token] [Smart contract NFT] [Deploy and upgrade] [Learn Solana Rust] [Rust basic] [Anchor language] [Deploy and upgrade] [Token program] [Blockchain RPC] [EVM RPC] [Solana RPC] [IPC RPC] [NEAR RPC] [WEB3] [etherJS] [Web3JS] [Provider] [EIP] [General] [Most basics] [Security] [Private key] [Multisign wallet] [Secrets] [Audit checklist] Checklists Responsibility checklist Release checklist General questions to consider Generally proven useful tools N Commandments README.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/assert-require-revert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/assert-require-revert/</guid><description>Enforce invariants with assert() An assert guard triggers when an assertion fails - such as an invariant property changing. For
example, the token to ether issuance ratio, in a token issuance contract, may be fixed. You can
verify that this is the case at all times with an assert(). Assert guards should often be
combined with other techniques, such as pausing the contract and allowing upgrades. (Otherwise, you
may end up stuck, with an assertion that is always failing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/blockchain-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/blockchain-security/</guid><description>Blockchain Security Checklist Understanding the project CENTRALIZATION / PRIVILEGE Secure the function have access by owner Initial token distribution, should prefix receiver address Use multisign wallet for dev Unrestricted privilege function EVENT LOG Event for any set function Event for significant transactions Event name must clear and avoid misunderstand Favor capitalization and a prefix in front of events (we suggest Log) VOLATILE CODE Avoid Reentrancy Check the return value of external call such as transfer Avoid state change after call external function Math Operation Check insecure arithmetic, integer under/overflow Validity check Clear Code structure Don&amp;rsquo;t use transfer() or send() Handle errors in external call ( can use try/catch) Favor pull over push for external calls Don&amp;rsquo;t delegatecall to untrusted code Force-feeding Ether GAS OPTIMIZATION Don&amp;rsquo;t use recursive function Use appropriate type (uint8, map&amp;hellip;) Initial variable in constructor Use external function instead of public UNIT TEST Unit test for get/set function Unit test for overflow data Unit test for external call Run unit test before deploy CODING STYLE Language specific Store config of upgrade contract and push to git Check Reusable Code, use modifier Check for minimal source code Have note/status for deployed code LOGICAL ISSUE Check over minted token Don&amp;rsquo;t trust tx.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/documents/</guid><description>When launching a contract that will have substantial funds or is required to be mission critical, it is important to include proper documentation.
Contact Who to contact with issues Names of programmers and/or other important parties Chat room where questions can be asked History Testing (including usage stats, discovered bugs, length of testing) People who have reviewed code (and their key feedback) Known-issues Key risks with contract e.g., You can lose all your money, hacker can vote for certain outcomes All known bugs/limitations Potential attacks and mitigants Potential conflicts of interest (e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/external-calls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/external-calls/</guid><description>Use caution when making external calls Calls to untrusted contracts can introduce several unexpected risks or errors. External calls may
execute malicious code in that contract or any other contract that it depends upon. As such,
every external call should be treated as a potential security risk. When it is not possible, or
undesirable to remove external calls, use the recommendations in the rest of this section to
minimize the danger.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/general/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/general/</guid><description>1. Abstract-vs-interfaces Be aware of the tradeoffs between abstract contracts and interfaces.
Both interfaces and abstract contracts provide one with a customizable and re-usable approach for smart contracts. Interfaces, which were introduced in Solidity 0.4.11, are similar to abstract contracts but cannot have any functions implemented. Interfaces also have limitations such as not being able to access storage or inherit from other interfaces which generally makes abstract contracts more practical.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/precautions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/precautions/</guid><description>As we discussed in the General Philosophy section, it is not enough to protect yourself against the known attacks. Since the cost of failure on a blockchain can be very high, you must also adapt the way you write software, to account for that risk.
The approach we advocate is to &amp;ldquo;prepare for failure&amp;rdquo;. It is impossible to know in advance whether your code is secure. However, you can architect your contracts in a way that allows them to fail gracefully, and with minimal damage.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/token/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/blockchain/token/</guid><description>Frontrunning The EIP-20 token&amp;rsquo;s approve() function creates the potential for an approved spender to spend more
than the intended amount. A
front running attack can be
used, enabling an approved spender to call transferFrom() both before and after the call to
approve() is processed. More details are available on the
EIP, and in
this document.
Standardization Generally speaking, smart contracts of tokens should follow an accepted and stable standard.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/changelog/</guid><description>Writing a useful changelog Remember the last time you read over the changelog of your favorite app and found it sucks with useless information like they don&amp;rsquo;t care about the product that they sell out. Something like below
2.11.4
Some bugs fixed or
Fix bugs and improve UI/UX They are awkward, and the same thing happens for our end users. As a user, we care about what&amp;rsquo;s news in the software that we use every day.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/charter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/charter/</guid><description>Project Charter Definitions Project Charter is a formal, typically short document that describes your project in its entirety — including what the objectives are, how it will be carried out, and who the stakeholders are. It is a crucial ingredient in planning out the project because it is used throughout the project lifecycle.
Why is the Project Charter So Important? The benefits of Project Charters for the development team. Helps determine project value: help the team determine if it’s worthwhile to carry out or propose the project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ci-cd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ci-cd/</guid><description>Continuous Integration What Continuous Integration (CI) is a development practice where developers integrate code into a shared repository frequently, preferably several times a day. Each integration can then be verified by an automated build and automated tests. While automated testing is not strictly part of CI it is typically implied.
One of the key benefits of integrating regularly is that you can detect errors quickly and locate them more easily.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/code-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/code-review/</guid><description>Code Review How we do code review at Dwarves Foundation.
Every project member must have another team member or team leader to review his/her code, and every changes to the code must be achieved via a Pull request to the main development branch. On larger project (10 developers+) we may requires 2 reviewers. All of this is to ensure correctness, quality of the code and learning opportunities for both assignee (who develop) and reviewer.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/db-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/db-migration/</guid><description>Database migration Mobile macOS / iOS:
Use ObjectMapper cua CoreData de migrate: https://williamboles.me/step-by-step-core-data-migration/ Android
https://medium.com/flutter-community/migrating-a-mobile-database-in-flutter-sqlite-44ac618e4897 Backend Su dung migration tool tuy ngon ngu Go: sql-migrate Elixir: ecto Tips / Best practices checklist Luon viet migrate up / down back up before migration data validation &amp;amp; repair Prefer ORM migration tool Do not deploy the code first: Do not deploy the code first that write to new columns, and then run the migration.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/definition-of-done/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/definition-of-done/</guid><description>Definition of done also known as DoD is a list of criteria which must be met before a product increment (story) is considered &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;.
In software, Done means
coded to standards reviewed implemented with unit test well documented In a services context, Done means
every task under the User Story has been completed and any work created is attached to the User Story so the Product Owner can review it and it meets his or her expectations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/diagram/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/diagram/</guid><description>Diagram and Project Document Structure We have talked about SDLC before and have learned that with a lot of constraints, the project is easy to fail. We could have plenty of reasons why a software project fails: team politics, overdue payment,&amp;hellip; but three of them could be prevented easily with proper methodology, framework
Unclear/misleading project requirements Wrongly defined tech stacks The wrong approach, develop practices There is one secret sauce of a successful project: Artifacts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/editor/</guid><description>Code editors Right now our team is scattered between VSCode and Emacs (Spacemacs).
The VSCode gang enjoy pretty syntax themes, excellent auto-completion for most languages, fast integrated terminal and awesome Git integration.
The Spacemacs gang live far from the human realm, with all 10 fingers moving constantly to ramp through everything they open, writing Elisp to change editor&amp;rsquo;s behavior on-the-fly, switching projects or playing next Spotify song is just a keymap away.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/environment/</guid><description>Environments This section describes the environments you should have, at a minimum. It might sound like a lot, but there is a purpose for each one.
Local development Continuous integration Testing Staging Production We use docker and docker-compose to set up our environments. Before getting more profound, we suggest you install our dotfiles, where we share the configuration and setting.
Local development environment This is your device, where you write code.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/error/</guid><description>Error Message Convention We use the following structure for our error message. It helps our system stay consistent, easier to present between components and also better for error tracking.
To make it easy to build informative error messages. To make errors easy to understand for users. To make errors helpful as diagnostics for programmers. Library Go: https://github.com/dwarvesf/gerr Elixir: https://github.com/dwarvesf/error.ex Swift: https://github.com/dwarvesf/error.swift Error Structure - type: list of common or pre-defined error type - message: error message - errors: actual error value in details - trace_id: Type of error We classify the error into some type:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/code-style/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/code-style/</guid><description>Code style While the vast majority of base code style is enforced by ESLint and Prettier, please also where possible, stick to the contribution guidelines below. These rules should be kept in mind when reviewing Pull Requests:
Code should be functional in style rather than Object Orientated or Imperative unless there are no clean alternatives.
Use pure functions where possible to make them testable and modular. Avoid mutating variables and the let keyword.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/logging-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/logging-monitoring/</guid><description>Logging and Monitoring This document provides guidance on some key metrics to track when logging and monitoring a frontend application at Dwarves Foundation.
Errors tracing Frontend applications receive a lot of user interactions and unexpected errors can arise quickly. To help developers catch and resolve these errors easily, we need a tool can:
Integrate to the staging and dev environments in order to catch any new issues before they become production bugs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/tech-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/tech-ecosystem/</guid><description>Tech ecosystem This document is intended to give you a taste of how we build frontend applications at Dwarves, and more importantly, why we choose the technology. It still assumes basic knowledge of React and Next.js. If you&amp;rsquo;re completely new to React, please refer to https://github.com/petehunt/react-howto instead!
Tech stack Core React Next.js SWR React Hook Form Dwarves React Toolkit UI &amp;amp; styling TailwindCSS Headless UI Static type checking &amp;amp; linting TypeScript ESLint Prettier Testing Jest react-testing-library Cypress Core Building Blocks React When we choose a technology, the first question always is &amp;ldquo;did that technology achieve a certain level of stability and maturity?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/ui-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/ui-checklist/</guid><description>UI Checklist Frontend engineering is not just about producing high quality code but also attentive design. Whether you work on a design or transform a design to code, make sure the below checklist is done before you ship.
Is relative spacing to UI elements as base unit of 4? Does your relative spacing match the relative spacing of similar UI elements? Does it look good on desktop, tablet, and mobile?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/writing-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/frontend/writing-test/</guid><description>Writing test Testing your application is a vital part of serious development. For the front-end, you don&amp;rsquo;t need 100% code coverage, about 70% is probably good enough. Following are some principles:
Write tests. Not too many. Mostly integration. Tests should make you more productive not slow you down. Maintaining tests can slow you down. You get dimishing returns on adding more tests after a certain point. Your tests should always resemble the way your software is used.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/git/</guid><description>Source Version Control It&amp;rsquo;s like a time machine. We can save and reload anytime we want to, like in the old day of Game Boy Advance. We can work in parallel universes of our source code, experimenting without fear of losing work, and rolling back if something goes wrong.
We use git. Git is one of the most popular distributed source version control. We use Github to open source our works, playbook, and practices.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/handover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/handover/</guid><description>Handover This is the checklist for our handover process. When a new person joins a project, project members are changed, or project is moved to another team, a
handover should be thoroughly planned and executed.
Why? Reduce handover time. Make clear for everyone how handover will affect schedules/communication/budget. Reduce risks of post-handover work. Ensure good confidence for new members. Handover is not a task, and it is not instant. Handover is always a project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/incident-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/incident-management/</guid><description>Incident management is the practice of responding to an unplanned event, user disruption, or service interruption and involves restoring the service to an operational or acceptable state. There are 2 general labels for incidents:
Incident: An unplanned interruption to a service or reduction in the service quality. Major incident: An incident with significant business impact, requiring an immediate coordinated resolution. A problem or issue is a not-yet-known root cause behind one or more incidents.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ios-db-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ios-db-migration/</guid><description>Database migration in iOS development Database migration is one of the most important aspects of software development in general and of iOS development in specific. If we do not handle it correctly, it would cause some bad user experiences, such as data loss, app crashing, etc. And finally, lead to the bad reputation for the company. So, we MUST handle it correctly. And this post is a lighthouse which lead you to the right path.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/ios/</guid><description>Best practices in iOS development Avoid reinventing the wheel by following these guidelines.
Why? Getting on board with iOS can be intimidating. Neither Swift nor Objective-C are widely used elsewhere, the platform has its own names for almost everything, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bumpy road for your code to actually make it onto a physical device. This living document is here to help you, whether you&amp;rsquo;re taking your first steps in Cocoaland or you&amp;rsquo;re curious about doing things &amp;ldquo;the right way&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/license/</guid><description>Licensing Why license? By definition, license is a permit from an authority to own or use something. In software development, the term expanded to the permission to use the software as well as the source code itself.
Understanding licenses will help you to prevent a lot of painful situation in the future, including lawsuit involvement.
Copyright and Copyleft In general, copyright law is used by an author to prohibit recipients from reproducing, adapting, or distributing copies of their work.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/log/</guid><description>Logging system Logs are for auditing. There is a well-defined process for accessing and searching through logs. For every project that we worked with, a single server or multiple services, we always bring on our log stack to track what happens in the system.
We store the system log centralized and grant permission for each project member. We divide the log category into System and Business; with different levels for quick access.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/monitoring/</guid><description>Monitoring Monitoring Application monitoring Status page Status page format Plain format JSON format HTTP status codes Load balancer health checks Access control Application monitoring Monitoring the full status of a service requires that both OS-level and application-specific monitoring checks are performed. OS-level checks include, for example, CPU, disk or memory usage, running processes, open ports, etc. Application specific checks are, however, the most important from the point of view of the running service.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/production/</guid><description>Production Checklist Long-running processes such as email should delivery being run in background jobs? Are there redundant (at least two) web and background processes running? Are we using SSL? Never send credentials unencrypted over public network. Always use encryption (such as HTTPS, SSL, etc.). Are API requests being made via a separate subdomain (api.example.com)? Even if the same app, this gives us architectural flexibility in the future. Are we monitoring performance and uptime?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/defect-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/defect-template/</guid><description>Defect Report template Summary A summary of the bug should be no more than 60 words. A good summary should be able to answer the three following questions:
What? – What has happened with the application? How? – What did we click/do to produce the bug? Where? – Where exactly in the app did we find the bug? What is the webpage and/or server (environment)? Description A clear and concise description should contain following sections:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/qa-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/qa-best-practices/</guid><description>QA best practises This is a summary of best practices our QA engineers at Dwarves use and recommends to be used. It is not supposed to be a detailed description and sometimes cannot fully be used for all tasks but as an overview of the most important QA processes and a list of good practices that should be used.
QA practices Everyone in Dwarves has QA responsibilities, even if there is a named QA manager or QA specialists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/testing/</guid><description>Testing Testing materials Test Plan Make sure these items included in your test plan:
The components and functions to be tested. The components and functions NOT to be tested. The risks of the project that might impact the test plan. Resource planning and responsibilities. External testing team (For example: UAT). Communication method. Test Suite/ Test Case Test case should includes those information:
Name Pre-condition Test Steps Expected Result Requirement Ref Brief about TC Pre-condition steps before executing TC Test Case Steps Expected result for the step User Story # or requirement specification Ex: Login successfully with google User is at login page (https://staging.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/uat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/qa/uat/</guid><description>UAT Checklist User Acceptance Testing can be a daunting and frustrating experience. Too often, the exercise becomes an ordeal of tight deadlines, stress, and system issues. While UAT will always be a high-effort activity, good preparation, responsiveness, and follow-up will multiply your chances of success.
Before UAT All features are completed by the development team. All features are fully tested by (internal) QC. All features are fully deployed to staging or UAT environment.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/rdd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/rdd/</guid><description>README Driven Development A perfect implementation of the wrong specification is worthless By the same principle a beautifully crafted library with no documentation is also damn near worthless. If your software solves the wrong problem or nobody can figure out how to use it, there’s something very bad going on.
Write your Readme first.
First. As in, before you write any code or tests or behaviors or stories or ANYTHING.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/readme-how/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/readme-how/</guid><description>README A README is a text file that introduces and explains a project. It contains information that is commonly required to understand what the project is about.
Why we need readme? It&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to answer questions that your audience will likely have regarding how to install and use your project and also how to collaborate with you.
Who write readme? Anyone who is working on a programming project, especially if you want others to use it or contribute.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/readme-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/readme-template/</guid><description>Project Title One Paragraph of project description goes here
Getting Started These instructions will get you a copy of the project up and running on your local machine for development and testing purposes. See deployment for notes on how to deploy the project on a live system.
Prerequisites What things you need to install the software and how to install them
Give examples Installing A step by step series of examples that tell you how to get a development env running</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/release/</guid><description>Release Checklist When you are ready to release, remember to check off everything on your release checklist.
Just remember to not mess up with the end users. Our responsibility is to keep the system stable with seamless deployment.
Do NOT release on Friday or weekend. We can&amp;rsquo;t handle if any issue happens. The milestone was fully implemented. Git
The PRs contained context and information for tracing back. Git commits message was squashed up.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/restful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/restful/</guid><description>RESTful API An API is a user interface for developers. Put the effort in to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s not just functional but pleasant to use.
Terminologies The following are the most important terms related to REST APIs.
Resource is an object or representation of something, which has some associated data with it, and there can be a set of methods to operate on it. E.g., Animals, schools, and employees are resources, and delete, add, update are the operations to be performed on these resources.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/security/api-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/security/api-security/</guid><description>API Security Checklist Authentication Consider not using Basic Auth. Use standard authentication (e.g. JWT, OAuth). Don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel in Authentication, token generation, password storage. Use the standards. Use Max Retry and jail features in Login. Use encryption on all sensitive data. JWT (JSON Web Token) Use a random complicated key (JWT Secret) to make brute forcing the token very hard. Don&amp;rsquo;t extract the algorithm from the payload. Force the algorithm in the backend (HS256 or RS256).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/security/dev-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/security/dev-security/</guid><description>Development Security Checklist TRANSMITING INFORMATION Never send credentials unencrypted over public network. Always use encryption (such as HTTPS, SSL, etc.). Don&amp;rsquo;t accept passwords or session tokens over HTTP. Use HTTPS for all web traffic. Use HTTPS in the beginning; it&amp;rsquo;s harder to introduce later. Use HTTPS redirects for HTTP traffic. Use HSTS headers to enforce HTTPS
traffic. Use secure cookies. Avoid protocol-relative URLs. STORING INFORMATION Never store secrets (passwords, keys, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-laptop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-laptop/</guid><description>Dotfiles In UNIX, the files start with a dot “.” are hidden. If you list files in the directory, they don’t show up and keep them safe from the end users. Because of that reason, the developer usually uses it to store configurations of their tools.
Those files are so-called dotfiles. &amp;lsquo;Dotfile&amp;rsquo; become a generalized term for a UNIX configuration file, typically prefixed with a dot (e.g., .vimrc) and found in your home directory.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-project/</guid><description>Project Setup Following setup helps us maintain stability and increase the transparency among team members.
Agreement We use GDrive for file storage as specified in our Handbook. As the initiator, you will need to create a subfolder with the project name in the Sales &amp;gt; Agreement folder.
NDA, agreements and all kinds of paperwork between parties will be put there. You can ask the Ops or Business team for help if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the access.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-repository/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/setup-repository/</guid><description>Repository setup How we expect projects to be setup at Dwarves Foundation.
What we expect README.md in the root of the repo is the docs Single command run Single command deploy Repeatable and re-creatable builds Build artifacts bundle a &amp;ldquo;Bill of Materials&amp;rdquo; Technical Project setup must be self-contained, no &amp;ldquo;It works on my machine&amp;rdquo; bullshit. If its failed to run the setup script on your coworker&amp;rsquo;s machine, it needs a fix 🔧</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/stack/</guid><description>Technology Stack Our perspective on Technology New technology needs to provide actual value over existing solutions. Software is changing the world every day. Software moves fast. The technology you used yesterday may be deprecated today. New technology has enabled us to create new things.
The world is running by the goodwill of people who try to make it a better place. With the existing set of problems, new solutions will come out along with new technologies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/user-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/user-story/</guid><description>Agile requirement - User Story What is User Story? In the traditional software development method, requirements are noted as a handful of documentations, specifications&amp;hellip;
In Agile, they are User Story is requirement. User Story is:
A convenient format for expressing the desired business value Crafted in a way that makes them understandable to both business people and technical people Used to provide a great placeholder for a conversation Written at various levels of granularity and are easy to refine Often used with the template:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/versioning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/versioning/</guid><description>Versioning Larger applications consists of multiple components that reference each other and rely on compatibility of the interfaces of the components.
To achieve the goal of loosely coupled applications, each component should be versioned independently hence allowing developers to detect breaking changes or seamless updates just by looking at the version number.
Semantic Versioning SemVer or Semantic Versioning is a way of versioning software in the format of MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/workflow/</guid><description>The workflow we chose to adopt is a team agreement on why we should be a team player and how we should act to benefit as a whole, not just an individual.
tl;dr; We apply agile philosophy. A few notes to take before working on a project.
Agile is an adjective, not a fancy word. An agile team is about the team, not the tool. Get to know the team and their capability before making any assumption.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/working-together/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/working-together/</guid><description>Pair Programming We encourage pair programming between all levels of experience. Nobody is required to pair program for a certain amount of time, but it is a great tool to help solve complex problems quickly and more efficiently with an extra set of eyes.
Code that is written by two people who sit next to each other at the same computer is pair-programmed code. The best way to pair program is to just sit side by side in front of the monitor.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/android/</guid><description>Android Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN ANDROID DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Knowledge in Dart fundamentals and Flutter framework Passionate about programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Android Development in Java/Kotlin is a plus You own the Android platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Apprentice</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/apprentice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/apprentice/</guid><description>Apprenticeship Program About the program Apprenticeship is a six-month earn-and-learn training program; it&amp;rsquo;s a way to learn about being a professional software developer. Specifically, it is a way to learn to be like the most skilled software developers you can find. It involves seeking out good teachers and taking opportunities to learn by working alongside them.
Apprenticeship is designed for the individuals who
are looking for the zen way to ship quality software or haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out the clear path to a job in the tech industry or with non-traditional work and educational background to find full-time roles The program provides a real-world experience where you will</description></item><item><title>Benefits And Perks</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Since the majority of Dwarves Foundation employees work in Saigon, this section is written with that as the default. Some benefits don’t make sense in other countries. We will try our best to provide comparable benefits and perks as it makes sense, though.
Continuing Education Allowance You will always grow by learning and playing with new and cool technologies. From books to conferences, you’ll get a yearly budget for your individual learning and development goals.</description></item><item><title>Frontend</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/frontend/</guid><description>Frontend Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A FRONTEND ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Passionate about coding and programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Strong knowledge in JavaScript fundamentals Well versed in various browser technologies Your HTML/CSS have to be good enough to create world-class UI (hint: we don&amp;rsquo;t use float) Knowledge of techniques like BEM, CSS modules, inline styles, .</description></item><item><title>Golang</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/golang/</guid><description>Gopher WE ARE LOOKING FOR A GOPHER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Experience with Golang Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test and integration test Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Growth</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/growth/</guid><description>Marketing We are open to a marketing position!
If you are looking for a tech-savvy company to contribute to and make your career, this may be your opportunity to put in your spirit and ideal setup.
Purpose Dwarves are a group of software engineers, designers, and innovation advocates. We are one of the most tech-savvy teams out there. We build this team together six years ago from a corner of Saigon and Toronto.</description></item><item><title>How We Hire</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/how-we-hire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/how-we-hire/</guid><description>How we hire Hiring means we need help. We only hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. We always look for long-term teammates that why we want to ensure the new hire is a value fit and culture fit.
Rounds Several Dwarves will talk to the candidates to walk them through 4 rounds
Pre-assessment: We evaluate the logic, English, and the personalities in non-interrupted 30 minutes online test.</description></item><item><title>How We Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/how-we-work/</guid><description>How we work We do Agile We build software. The way we see it is a collaboration between multiple people in the team with sufficient knowledge on the domain and clearly understand the project vision that they can quickly adapt to the changes in the market. We adopt the Agile philosophy at this level.
Also, based on that philosophy, we apply the Scrum framework, which we find out a good fit for us.</description></item><item><title>Intern</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/intern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/intern/</guid><description>The Program In 2018, we launched the first Summer Internship Program for students with or without Engineering background from top universities. The program was designed with the purpose to give an opportunity for candidates to experience the real world projects. No coffee runs here. We love watching talented people learn and explore their skills.
We strive to create a generation of new tech enthusiasts who possess the same DNA with us, to generate a solid groundwork and go along with the company’s triumph.</description></item><item><title>IOS</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/ios/</guid><description>iOS Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN iOS DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Strong knowledge in Swift fundamentals and its framework Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Objective-C is a plus You own the iOS platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Making A Career</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/making-a-career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/making-a-career/</guid><description>Making a Career The average tenure of employees working at many technology companies today is shockingly low. At both Amazon, Google and other companies, it’s just around one year. At Dwarves Foundation, it’s just around three years as of late 2018. That’s something to be proud of, and something to ensure endures. When you work at Dwarves Foundation, it should be feasible to think about this as the place for making a life-long career.</description></item><item><title>QA</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/qa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/archived/qa/</guid><description>QA Engineer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A QA ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements CAREFULNESS is our first prerequisite A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp.</description></item><item><title>What We Stand For</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</guid><description>What we stand for Empower Innovation with Software Craftsmanship Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.
Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time.</description></item><item><title>What We Value</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/what-we-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/what-we-value/</guid><description>What we value Before anything else, values come first. The value is important to us. They are what we proud of. They help guide us when we are facing a difficult decision. They will be the things you like about what we do at Dwarves Foundation and how we do it.
Our core values guide our strategies and individual actions so that we create a company whose character is as radical as our work.</description></item><item><title>Where We Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/where-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/careers/additional-info/where-we-work/</guid><description>Where we work Office The Dwarves HQ is in Saigon, Vietnam. Thirty people and two cats have desk space in the Saigon office, but those people also work from home regularly. We expand the office space when the old one is full and people want the new office. Anyone is welcome to visit Saigon and work from the office at any time.
From home A few people at Dwarves Foundation are based in other countries and they work from home most of the time.</description></item></channel></rss>