<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Case on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/case/</link><description>Recent content in Case on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/case/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 and reached a total seed funding of $4M by 2020, Search.io, formerly Sajari, is an AI-powered search and product discovery platform that helps eCommerce brands and retailers maximize their revenue and conversion rates through outcome-focused, real-time search result optimization. The Dwarves partnered with Search.io to help with their Console dashboard app, improve open-source packages quality and tailor the brand UI for plugin consumers. Search.io is one of those matured projects that requires stability over speed.</description></item><item><title>Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 as an innovation arm of INDODAX, Tokenomy is a crypto investment network through blockchain-enabled tokens. Currently reached the seed round funded by LazyLedger, Tokenomy aims to reach a broader customer segment through web platforms and mobile apps. We fully support a team of Senior Frontend Engineer, Android Mobile Engineer, and UX Designer to help them stay on track with the release timeline. Technical Highlight MVVM for mobile application architecture WebSocket for real-time trading support Reactivex to bind data and process asynchronous tasks Biometric authentication approach for data encryption Custom-built Android module to support different APIs Weekly product changelog apply for the team synergy The Context They came to us at first to refactor the frontend foundation.</description></item><item><title>Team Up With Basehq Us First Ever Platform Built For Assistants</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</guid><description>In brief Base launched in 2019 out of High Alpha Venture Studio, with a $2.6M funding round led by Matchstick Ventures with participation from Revolution&amp;rsquo;s Rise of the Rest Seed Fund, High Alpha Capital, and Slack Fund. Base is a software platform built specifically for executive assistants. Focus on smoothing out assistants&amp;rsquo; daily work. They demand a high integration between different platforms. We stepped in to make it happen. Through 2 years straight, they engaged with Dwarves to develop various new modules and features.</description></item></channel></rss>