<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>elixir on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/elixir/</link><description>Recent content in elixir on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/elixir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #5</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-5/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 03/01/2024 🍎 apple Internal Our fifth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Auto pass reCAPTCHA by @Toan Ho Passkey demo by @Tay Github Trending Analyzer use-case discussion by @Hieu Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #5 - 03/01/2024:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #4</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 27/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our fourth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Broadway in elixir to handle million messages by @Hieu Using WebAuthn API to implement passkeys by @Vincent Labeling image using openAI vision and embedding flow by @Lap Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #4 - 27/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 20/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our third weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Rise on chatbot alternatives, LibreChat to use OpenAI and custom LLMs by @Tom Bypass reCaptcha using self-hosted AI model by @Toan Shared query processing through DuckDB WASM by @Tom Build desktop app with Tauri by @Vy Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #3 - 20/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 13/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item></channel></rss>