<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pm on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/pm/</link><description>Recent content in pm on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/pm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting The Budget</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setting-the-budget/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setting-the-budget/</guid><description>One of the most important questions at the start of a project is how much it will cost. It is vital to make sure that enough budget is available to allow for the development of a viable product.
The difficulty with setting a budget at the start of a project is that everyone is at the point of maximum ignorance. At the beginning of a project, all of the requirements have not matured.</description></item><item><title>Fixed Budget Scope Controlled</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</guid><description>Fixed-Budget, Scope-Controlled (FBSC) is applied at Atomic Object. They build custom software for our customers. Because of the complexity involved in building a great software product, software development projects are always more difficult to price than a product. ﻿ As a result two different strategies for pricing services, such as building software, have traditionally been used by most companies. These are called “Fixed Price” and “Time And Materials”.
Fixed Price A Fixed Price strategy locks in the total price of the project upfront.</description></item><item><title>An Alternative To Tm</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-alternative-to-tm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-alternative-to-tm/</guid><description>Vendors may use the phrase &amp;ldquo;time and materials&amp;rdquo; (T&amp;amp;M) to describe how they engage in projects and invoice their clients.
The phrase t&amp;amp;m has been laid to rest at Atomic for several reasons. First, the phrase doesn’t accurately describe how we engage with our clients. At Atomic, we certainly don’t work without profit. And we have an innate desire to be more efficient.
T&amp;amp;M is an inaccurate way of describing our business relationships and ignores a lot of other work we do.</description></item><item><title>Project Management</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</guid><description>A Project Manager (PM) job starts right after a new project has been sealed and assigned with a starting date, a deadline and a Team. As a PM it is absolutely fundamental you are an expert about our working methodologies, processes and communication
Be organised
Keep everything neat and things where they are supposed to be. Being organised and keeping track of everything will make your life much easier. Create tasks and document them straight away.</description></item></channel></rss>