<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Performance on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/performance/</link><description>Recent content in Performance on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New in February 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-february-2024/</guid><description>Reporting tech signals - Latest findings on Serverless Computing, AI &amp;amp; ML, FinOps and CyberSecurity Research Topics 2024 - 40 topics on the most promising technologies. Dwarves&amp;rsquo; Reward System - Developing our community reward system Calling for Partners - One of the rare event where Dwarves and community members gather. Reporting tech signals Every month we watch tech trends closely to depict which ones have high potential, and can be part of our growing tech stack.</description></item><item><title>What's New in January 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/changelog/whats-new-january-2024/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In this first month of 2024, we kept tap of what&amp;rsquo;s brewing in the tech market, while reviewing what we went through in 2023.
Reporting tech signals - Updates on the stage of React, Rust, AI, Cybersecurity, Rust.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>Red Flags</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/red-flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/red-flags/</guid><description>These red flags are things we don’t want to see in our peeps. Even when you think they are improper, don’t waste your time with a wrong group of people.
Negative attitude The employee may exhibit a negative attitude towards their work, colleagues, or the company. They may also show signs of disengagement, lack of motivation, lack of integrity or unwillingness to learn.
Incompatibility** **The employee may not fit in with the company culture or may have a personality clash with other team members.</description></item><item><title>Are You Helping</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/are-you-helping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/are-you-helping/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive business environment, it is crucial for organizations to have a clear understanding of the value and performance of their employees. In a recent post I wrote, titled &amp;ldquo;Inner Circle&amp;rdquo;, I expounded on the importance of contribution and value in relation to a person&amp;rsquo;s work or performance. However, there is another key aspect to this topic that must be taken into consideration. One of the most effective ways to determine how well a person is performing is by asking the question, &amp;ldquo;Are you helping?</description></item><item><title>The Okr</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-okr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/the-okr/</guid><description>What is OKR OKR (Object and Key Result) is a management methodology, an outcome-driven tracking framework.
Object : is a goal we want to achieve
**Key Results : **are a set of explaination for how will we know we are getting there.
For example
In Q1/2018 DF&amp;rsquo;s objective is want to build a strong backend team, so &amp;ldquo;**build a strong backend team&amp;rdquo; **is an object, to accomplish that, we will hire 2 senior backend developers and **organize 1 training session per week, **each of them is a key result to let us know whether we are getting to our objective or not.</description></item><item><title>Our Metrics For Performance Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</guid><description>$$ P = f(r, t, c, r) $$
Performance - P Performance is a final value that will be calculated from other metrics. This value will help to indicate how good all the activities we&amp;rsquo;ve done to make the company could grow.
Metrics will be marked from the scale from 1 to 5:
1 is bad 3 is normal 5 is outstanding 1 ---- 2 ---- 3 ---- 4 ---- 5 bad good outstand Context of example</description></item></channel></rss>