<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>performance on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/performance/</link><description>Recent content in performance on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, our team has always faced some bit of friction when deploying apps for our clients. We’ve known about blue-green deployments for a while and were recently given the chance to evaluate and demonstrate them for one of our Discord bot projects.
Applying Blue-green deployment for Mochi Bot Introducing Mochi Bot to the Web3 space, our team has developed a flexible and user-friendly product with features like NFT rarity queries, sales alerts on Discord and Twitter, and showing various tips.</description></item><item><title>I18n Frontend Guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</guid><description>In a front-end web application, locales are used to determine the language and geographic location of the user and to display the appropriate content to them.
When a user visits a web page, the application will first detect their locale, then use this information to determine which version of the content to display.
To support multiple languages and locales, the application needs to have the necessary content available for each locale.</description></item><item><title>Red Flags</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</guid><description>These red flags are things we don’t want to see in our peeps. Even when you think they are improper, don’t waste your time with a wrong group of people.
Negative attitude The employee may exhibit a negative attitude towards their work, colleagues, or the company. They may also show signs of disengagement, lack of motivation, lack of integrity or unwillingness to learn.
Incompatibility** **The employee may not fit in with the company culture or may have a personality clash with other team members.</description></item><item><title>Are You Helping</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-you-helping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-you-helping/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive business environment, it is crucial for organizations to have a clear understanding of the value and performance of their employees. In a recent post I wrote, titled &amp;ldquo;Inner Circle&amp;rdquo;, I expounded on the importance of contribution and value in relation to a person&amp;rsquo;s work or performance. However, there is another key aspect to this topic that must be taken into consideration. One of the most effective ways to determine how well a person is performing is by asking the question, &amp;ldquo;Are you helping?</description></item><item><title>The Okr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-okr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-okr/</guid><description>What is OKR OKR (Object and Key Result) is a management methodology, an outcome-driven tracking framework.
Object : is a goal we want to achieve
**Key Results : **are a set of explaination for how will we know we are getting there.
For example
In Q1/2018 DF&amp;rsquo;s objective is want to build a strong backend team, so &amp;ldquo;**build a strong backend team&amp;rdquo; **is an object, to accomplish that, we will hire 2 senior backend developers and **organize 1 training session per week, **each of them is a key result to let us know whether we are getting to our objective or not.</description></item><item><title>Our Metrics For Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</guid><description>$$ P = f(r, t, c, r) $$
Performance - P Performance is a final value that will be calculated from other metrics. This value will help to indicate how good all the activities we&amp;rsquo;ve done to make the company could grow.
Metrics will be marked from the scale from 1 to 5:
1 is bad 3 is normal 5 is outstanding 1 ---- 2 ---- 3 ---- 4 ---- 5 bad good outstand Context of example</description></item><item><title>Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</guid><description>Fire quickly False positives: people who you thought fit your values, but don’t once they’re hired False negatives: people who you thought would not fit your values, but would have if you had hired them If you get some false positives anyway, the solution is to fire quickly. To follow the &amp;ldquo;No Asshole Rule&amp;rdquo;, we need to strictly apply this despite the common excuses:
for that one bad trait, he has four good traits going for him.</description></item></channel></rss>