<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>operation on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/operation/</link><description>Recent content in operation on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/operation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bric A Brac</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bric-a-brac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bric-a-brac/</guid><description> Outsource things which are super important but we are not excellent at. Spend time selecting a vendor and occasionally spend time reevaluating other vendors. Automate repetitive tasks. Give everyone &amp;ldquo;admin&amp;rdquo; access to as much as possible to avoid bottlenecks. Our problems are not unique. We will try manual processes first. When we do build something, it is usually after using other things for years</description></item><item><title>Account</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/account/</guid><description>Planning
Many people would say in order to have a good plan; you need to write out all vibrant details. A good plan needs lots of details, they said. But in real life, where nothing is certain and is filled with sudden surprises, a good plan should prioritize its flexibility and simplicity.
Start with the main goals of the week, then expand on the actual required actions to achieve those desired goals.</description></item><item><title>Writing Management Objectives In Smart</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</guid><description>S.M.A.R.T. goals are a relatively new idea. In 1981, George T. Doran, a consultant and former director of corporate planning for Washington Water Power Company, published a paper called, “There’s a S.M.A.R.T. Way to Write Management’s Goals and Objectives.” In the document, he introduces S.M.A.R.T. goals as a tool to create criteria to help improve the chances of succeeding in accomplishing a goal
S – Specific When setting a goal, be specific about what you want to accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Building A Solid High Performing Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</guid><description>Sustainable growth companies are built by teams of shining constellations rather than just several bright stars
It all starts with recruiting. Many successes and disasters start with recruiting. Recruiting is the most important job for any real leader in the company
The second step is all about the right placement of the stars in your constellation. No matter what bullshit motivational book you may have read, people do not change. Yes, people do evolve, and yes, those not capable of evolution should never become a part of your team, but for Pete’s sake, do not confuse skill evolution with personality change.</description></item><item><title>Hiring For Operations Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</guid><description>Operations is a very sensitive area of the company, so be very picky. A great ops person can dramatically improve the way your company works and make your life a lot easier
Operations is operations, no matter the industry
Operations problems are almost the same everywhere (in ultra-specialized and regulated industries we just surround ourselves with specialists and attorneys). Industry experience is helpful, but not as much as you think</description></item><item><title>Objective</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/objective/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/objective/</guid><description>Operating a company is not much different from operating a machine or a system. The company has departments and people working together towards a goal as a car has many components connected by gears moving towards a destination.
The ultimate objective of operations is making sure the gears rolling smoothly and the car always move forward without any glitch.</description></item><item><title>Project Management</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</guid><description>A Project Manager (PM) job starts right after a new project has been sealed and assigned with a starting date, a deadline and a Team. As a PM it is absolutely fundamental you are an expert about our working methodologies, processes and communication
Be organised
Keep everything neat and things where they are supposed to be. Being organised and keeping track of everything will make your life much easier.
Create tasks and document them straight away.</description></item><item><title>Delegate Work Not Responsibility</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</guid><description>We can bring in all the technology in the world, but if we can’t delegate properly, our companies have no chance of scaling well
Delegating work does not absolve you of responsibility. In the case of a failure, the blame is all yours. Investors will go after the CEO, even if an intern made the mistake that hurt the company. If a failure occurs due to person you delegated work to lacking skills, it is your fault you delegated work to the wrong person.</description></item><item><title>Resource Assignment</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/resource-assignment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/resource-assignment/</guid><description>With the nature of consulting team, one member could be assigned to multiple projects at once or handle the work of a member in one project that take more than 100% of his/her time per week.
Based on the Quality Software Management book of Gerald Weinberg, the resource context switching cost is shown as below:
The column &amp;ldquo;Loss to Context Switching&amp;rdquo; is a total loss for your productivity. Therefore, one person should only be assigned to maximum 3 projects at the same time, and the total working hour of that person should NOT exceed 120% (meaning not more than 12 hours per day).</description></item></channel></rss>