<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Database Designs For Multilingual Apps</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</guid><description>This story comes from the necessity of multi-language support across our applications. Dwarves Foundation handles a lot of international clients and there is always some level of concern for supporting multiple languages for certain apps. This is a concern not just from our clients, but also from us, which motivated our research for multilingual support.
Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s globalized world, many applications need to support multiple languages to reach a broader audience.</description></item><item><title>An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</guid><description>How is the real estate market moving? When an industry begins this journey of digital transformation depends largely on the specific nature of its offering. As a rule of thumb, the more product-oriented and direct-to-customer an industry is, the sooner its digital transformation journey begins. The first important question is: why do industries go through this transformation process? What is the overall purpose? One common misconception is that fear is a major driver of transformation - the fear of being disrupted, the fear of becoming obsolete, the fear of losing out.</description></item></channel></rss>