<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>radar on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/radar/</link><description>Recent content in radar on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/radar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tech Radar</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</guid><description> ant-design apache-kafka argocd astro backstage blue-green-deployment browserstack carbon chatgpt-assistance chromatic clickhouse cloudflare-workers commitlint copilot cucumber cypress dapr detox deno devpod dora-metrics duckdb earthly elixir-umbrella-project erlang error-logging-convention eslint event-sourcing excalidraw expo figma formal-verification fullstack-tracing gestalt-principle github-actions golang grafana graylog headless-ui hoppscotch ipfs jotai k6 k9s kaniko kotlin kubeseal-sops ladle loki makefile micro-frontend monorepo msw n6n nestjs netlify newrelic nextjs nodejs nostrum nx orval page-object-model partytown phaser phoenix playwright pnpm progressive-delivery prometheus prompt-engineering qwik radix-ui react-hook-form react-llm react-native react-query react-server-component react-testing-library react remix replayio rust selenium semantic-release-auto-release sentry serverlessq solidity solidjs stern svelte swagger swift-ui swift swr tailwindcss tauri team-topologies live-view nghenhan-microservices urbox-backend-api timescaledb tla trunk-based-development turborepo type-safe-client-server typescript ui-documentation uno-css upptime v-model vector-database vercel vitejs volta wasm webdriverio webflow yup zod zustand elixir</description></item><item><title>Adoption Of Pnpm</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share that the Dwarves team has officially decided to switch to pnpm as our primary package management tool. After careful evaluation, we found that pnpm is widely embraced by the development community and has been successfully used by great teams at Vercel, Nx, and Chakra UI.
Previously, we were using Yarn V1 classic, but as our projects grew, we faced challenges with disk space and slow installations.</description></item><item><title>Radio Talk 60 Blue Green Deployment</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</guid><description>Blue-green deployment has become an important topic in modern software development, and this deployment strategy has become our focus on the tech radar. In a recent radio talk, Quang Le, one of our DevOps engineers, presented the significance of blue-green deployment and its benefits. This memo is a quick recap of the talk.
A brief Blue-green deployment is a software deployment strategy that involves creating two identical environments: one that is live and serving user traffic (blue) and one that is not (green).</description></item><item><title>Data Analyst In Retail Trading</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</guid><description>I am Bach Phuong and I work at Dwarves Foundation as a Data Analyst, helping partner companies realize insights and understand their business better.
What does a Data Analyst do? A Data Analyst is a gatekeeper for an organization’s data. They are tasked to explore, transform, aggregate data to create business insights from that data to then create reports to stakeholders. Thanks to these reports, companies can make more informed business decisions.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</guid><description>We started the 1st volume a year ago, mostly about assessing all the tech indexes we have adopted for 5 years. Then we moved to the 2nd volume, where we figured ways to simplify the workflow and complete our project toolkit.
And here we go again, another version of tech radar at Dwarves Foundation. 2021 has just gone through its first quarter, and we&amp;rsquo;ve left with some new toys to trial and see if they create any impact.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</guid><description>Once every month, we gather for Radar update to round up the cool techs and assess if we should adopt that to the team. Road to a wider and more diversified rings, Dwarves Tech Radar v2 contains the practices to simplify the workflow, new techniques/ approach methods to upgrade our current standards, and **expand the domain knowledge. **
Trial Earthly: The combination Dockerfile + Makefile https://earthly.dev/
A repeatable syntax builds to untangle the debugging process between the local environment and the CI platform.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</guid><description>The Dwarves have their tradition to explore the tech scene and learn new things. Dwarves Tech Radar kicked the initial step since January of 2020.
It is the first time we sit down and do it in written form. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard for the engineers at first, but we managed to complete the volume with ten reports.
Besides volume 01, we have an opportunity to sort out our current technology index and put it at https://d.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</guid><description>Our Perspective on Technology Technology is eating the world. The technology we used yesterday may be deprecated today. New technology has enabled us to create new things. With the existing set of problems, new solutions will emerge along with new technologies.
Over five years of working as an innovative software firm, other than the energetic tech-savvy workforce, we shape the team day by day with the core values that move towards the engineering culture.</description></item></channel></rss>