<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Untitled</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/brainery/google-data-fusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/brainery/google-data-fusion/</guid><description>Introduction Google Data Fusion is a fully managed, cloud-native data integration service that enables users to efficiently build and manage ETL/ELT data pipelines. It is designed to streamline data engineering tasks for enterprise users and is built on top of the open-source project CDAP
. Key features and benefits of Google Data Fusion include:
Graphical User Interface: Data Fusion offers a convenient drag-and-drop interface for building data pipelines, making it easier for users to focus on insights and actions rather than writing code.</description></item><item><title>How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, our team has always faced some bit of friction when deploying apps for our clients. We’ve known about blue-green deployments for a while and were recently given the chance to evaluate and demonstrate them for one of our Discord bot projects.
Applying Blue-green deployment for Mochi Bot Introducing Mochi Bot to the Web3 space, our team has developed a flexible and user-friendly product with features like NFT rarity queries, sales alerts on Discord and Twitter, and showing various tips.</description></item><item><title>Radio Talk 60 Blue Green Deployment</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</guid><description>Blue-green deployment has become an important topic in modern software development, and this deployment strategy has become our focus on the tech radar. In a recent radio talk, Quang Le, one of our DevOps engineers, presented the significance of blue-green deployment and its benefits. This memo is a quick recap of the talk.
A brief Blue-green deployment is a software deployment strategy that involves creating two identical environments: one that is live and serving user traffic (blue) and one that is not (green).</description></item><item><title>How We Setup Cicd</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-setup-cicd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-setup-cicd/</guid><description>Before we dig through a detailed process, let&amp;rsquo;s set some grounded knowledge about the CI/CD:
CI stands for continuous integration. It involves linting, testing, building, and merging developers&amp;rsquo; various code changes into a shared repository such as GitHub, Gitlab, or pushing software images to a container registry, usually multiple times per day.
On the other hand, CD refers to either continuous delivery or continuous deployment, which are sometimes used interchangeably. Either way, this typically refers to later stages of the software pipeline, and especially to how new code moves into production.</description></item><item><title>About Devops</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/about-devops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/about-devops/</guid><description>What is DevOps actually? DevOps is a culture with only one goal which is &amp;ldquo;improving the software lifecycle&amp;rdquo; (bug fixes, features, configurations) to end-users more frequently but still keep software&amp;rsquo;s reliable.
It is a continuous process and contains various stages such as :
Continuous Integration Continuous Development Continuous Testing Continuous Deployment Continuous Monitoring The main role of DevOps is to increase the quality of product to a great extent and to increase the collaboration of Development and Operation team as well so that the workflow within the organization becomes smoother.</description></item></channel></rss>