<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dwarves on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/dwarves/</link><description>Recent content in dwarves on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/dwarves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We Are Hiring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</guid><description>We Are Hiring IOS QA Intern Growth Golang Frontend Apprentice Android Where We Work What We Value What We Stand For Making A Career How We Work How We Hire Benefits And Perks WeAreHiring Marketing Marketing Lead Engineering Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust Web Developer, React.js App Developer, Apple Platform QA Engineer, Automation QA Engineer, Manual Data Engineer AI/ML Engineer Engineering Manager Design UX Designer (Blockchain/Fintech) UX Designer (Productivity/Dev Tool) UI Designer Lead Designer Apprenticeship Training Program (1+ year exp.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes with our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Example Newsletter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/example-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/example-newsletter/</guid><description>hello world</description></item><item><title>note.d.foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/home/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This brain repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Newsletter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tech Radar</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dwarves Community Earn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</guid><description>The Dwarves bounty program is the means through which both company peeps and the community can contribute to our daily activities. This includes tasks like building internal tools, engaging in new technology research and development, or sharing knowledge session.
→ Apply for research team: open ticket in our Discord
→ To contribute: open ticket in our Discord and give @hnh a ping
title bounty status Trend Command 60 ICY Open Tech Radar Status 60 ICY Open Tech Radar Report 60 ICY Open Fortress Shanky Data 120 ICY Open Fortress Mma Score 120 ICY Open Fleeting Notes 60 ICY Open Dwarvesf Map 80 ICY Open Consulting Map 80 ICY Open Zod Nextjs Boilerplate 10 ICY Done Wagmi Website 150 ICY Done Upgraed Nextjs Boilerplate 10 ICY Done Type Safe Framework 100 ICY Done Treasure Hunt 100 ICY Done Summary Article 60 ICY Done React Server Component 20 ICY Done Project Changelog Tool 100 ICY Done Optimize Query Database 100 ICY Done Monorepo Deployment Flow 80 ICY Done Locale Web Mobile 100 ICY Done Layer 2 Zk Rollup 100 ICY Done Integrate Ts Reset 10 ICY Done Integrate Rss Feed 50 ICY Done Hunger Game 100 ICY Done Financial Literacy Outline 45 ICY Done Feature Toggle 100 ICY Done Enigma Checksum 20 ICY Done Engagament Log 100 ICY Done Economic Calendar 40 ICY Done Dwarves Email Domain 100 ICY Done Discord Role 20 ICY Done Discord Publish Braniery 40 ICY Done Company Social Graph 40 ICY Done Company Signature 20 ICY Done Chatbot Prompt Size 30 ICY Done Chatbot Memory 100 ICY Done Chatbot Llm Accuracy 100 ICY Done Chatbot Adversarial Prompt 30 ICY Done Centralize Dwarves Calendar 30 ICY Done Brainery Metrics Report 100 ICY Done</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</guid><description> Dwarves Memo 2018 Wrapping Up 2020 In A Flashback 2021 Dwarves In Review 2021 July Updates 2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Quick Intro To Webassembly A Tips Of Hiring Dont A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell About Devops Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Account Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform Adoption Of Pnpm Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool An Alternative To Tm An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate Applied Security Basis Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem Architecture Decision Record Are We Really Engineers Are You Helping Asking As A Junior Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services Augusts Forward Engineering Avoid Burn Out Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup Beyond The Title Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App Blockchain For Designers Blocking Distraction Bric A Brac Build A Passcode View With Swift Build An Assistant On The Terminal Building A Solid High Performing Team Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage Bunk License Check Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas Competency Mapping Conduct A Meeting Configure The Company Email Connecting Vim With Golang Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating Constructive Feedback Continuous Translation Cost Of React Native Create Circular Text Using Swiftui Daemons And Services Programming Guide Data Analyst In Retail Trading Database Designs For Multilingual Apps Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab December All Hands Meeting Definition Of Done Delegate Work Not Responsibility Delegation And Believe It Will Work Design Better Mobile Application Design Resourcestools Design System Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup Design Tips Tricks Design Workflow Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao Different Ways To Test React Application Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process Discord Roles Docker Microcontainers Docker Registry Domain Glossary Domain Insight Research Framework Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui Dwarves Community Bounty Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022 Dwarves Memo Dwarves Of 2021 Dwarves Of The Year 2022 Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03 Dwarves Ventures Fund 0 Dwarves Ventures Fund 1 Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Effective Meeting Estimation In Agile Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation Federated Byzantine Finite State Machine Fixed Budget Scope Controlled Focus On Software Delivery Forward Engineering 2022 Forward Engineering June 2023 Forward Engineering March 2023 Forward Engineering May 2023 From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress Gestalt Principles In Ui Design Getting Started With Webflow Git Commit Message Convention Gitflow Pull Request Go Concurrency Go In Software Engineering Go The Extra Mile Good Design Understanding Grid And Layout Growth Is Our Universal Language Happy 2023 Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg Hiring Approach Hiring For Operations Team Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs How A Design System Work How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi How People Matter Should Work How We Contribute To Homebrew How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt How We Setup Cicd I18n Frontend Guideline Infinite Image Gallery With R3f An Approach Introduce To Dwarves Memo Introduction To Software Craftsmanship Istio January Updates Konvoy X Dwarves Kubernetes Helm 101 Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Micro Frontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Life At Dwarves Software Design Group Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves Looking Back 2019 Make Remote Working Works Making Decision As A Team Member Managing Dataflow And Sql Database With Concurrency Control May 2022 All Hands Meeting Mbti Type Estj Mbti Type Intj Mbti Type Istj Mbti Type Istp Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq Micro Frontends Microservices For Frontend Development Objective Ogif Open Fabric Set The Tech Foundation And Built An Mvp From Scratch Our Daily Standup Format Our Metrics For Performance Review Our Policy For Remote Working Our View On Fullstack Engineering Overview On Broker Pattern In Distributed System Passing The Probation Get 3 Upvotes Playaround With Clojure Playaround With Rust Project Management Qc Onboarding Radio Talk 60 Blue Green Deployment Radio Talk 61 Monorepo React 18 React Native New Architecture Recursively Export File Pattern In Javascript Es6 Application Red Flags Remix Versus Nextjs Remote Moderated Usability Testing Remote Prepare And Get Going Remove Unused Css Styles From Bootstrap Using Purgecss Reproduce Apple Find Me Bottom Menu View Resource Assignment Responsibility Reusability In Software Development Road To 100 Sdk Event Sourcing Setting The Budget Setup React Project With Webpack And Babel Six Things I Extracted From Design Thinking Skill Of Software Engineer Slice And Array In Golang Software Development Life Cycle 101 Software Modeling Sol Travel Planning App Part 1 Sol Travel Planning App Part 2 Sol Travel Planning App Part 3 Spike Inu Engineering A Seamless Experience For Cross Chain Swap And Decentralized Exchange Split And Reuse Code In React Application Sprint Lifecycle Sql Practices Orm Vs Plain Sql Startups Vs Junior Designers Startupvn Succeed Naru A Browser Focus Web Extension For Us Market Supercharged Setel Malaysias First Pay Pump Go Super App Support Relay In Shipping Their Mvp Product For Us Market Testing Swiftui Team Up With Basehq Us First Ever Platform Built For Assistants Tech Event In The Latest Transforming Healthcare With Technology The 10x Engineer The Adjacent Possible The Correct Way To Build Kpi The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions The Dwarves Culture Handbook The Dwarves Runs By Ideas The Four Preferences The Inner Circle The Key Of Security Mechanisms In Tackling Cyber Threats The Next Leading Chairs The Okr The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 1 The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 2 Three Levels Of Design Traits To Assess During An Interview Transparency Types Of Employees Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves Ui Design Fundamental Uidynamicanimator Understanding An Application Design Unit Testing Best Practices In Golang Use Go Selenium To Crawl Data Using Correct Html Element To Increase Website Accessibility Ux Model Well Crafted Software What I Learned On Design Thinking And Software Development What Is Kubernetes What Is Pnpm Compare To Npmyarn Why Micro Frontend Why We Chose Our Tech Stack Accelerating Development With A Robust Frontend Solution Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves Writing Management Objectives In Smart Xpc Services On Macos App Using Swift</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</guid><description/></item><item><title>monitoring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>nda</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>release</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aarrr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</guid><description>AARRR framework We use the AARRR framework to measure and optimize every phase of a product by optimizing it through the insane focus on one metric at a time.
What is AARRR framework? The AARRR framework consists of five phases a customer goes through in order to achieve growth and each phase has its own set of metrics to focus on. AARRR stands for Acquisition, Activation, Retention, Referral, and Revenue.</description></item><item><title>business-playbook-outline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</guid><description> BUSINESS PLAYBOOK Table of Contents
Introduction Who we are The Team Team chart Team members Portfolio Achievements Vision &amp;amp; mission
Strategy
Operating Process
Diagram Process workflows Sales Partnership process Commission model/tier Payment timeline FAQ</description></item><item><title>collaboration-guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</guid><description>Collaboration Guideline Guidelines for project collaboration between DF and Clients.
Tools Project management &amp;amp; communication: Basecamp (invited as Client) Sprint planning &amp;amp; tracking: Jira/Basecamp Meeting: Google Meet Source control platform: Github/Gitlab (self-hosted) Design: Figma/Sketch Schedule Project kick-off meeting: 1 session Sprint length: 1 week/2 weeks Sprint planning meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint review &amp;amp; retrospective meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint daily standup meetings (can as well be done via communication channel or Basecamp’s check-ins) Project/team feedback meeting (with Account Manager): 1 per week or 1 every 2 weeks Meeting notes for Sprint planning and Sprint retrospective will be sent within 30 minutes after meeting.</description></item><item><title>design-sprint</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</guid><description>Design Sprint What is the design sprint? The sprint is a four-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping and testing ideas with customers.
Design sprint mostly applied to the Exploration phase.
Friday is usually Education event or Lab projects at Dwarves Design, learning and continuous professional and personal development are in the core of our DNA. No one wants to settle, everyone wants to take the next step forward.</description></item><item><title>df-workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</guid><description>Monday:
Sprint Planning
End-of-day (EOD) check-in message
Tuesday:
EOD check-in message
Wednesday:
Sprint review message
EOD check-in message
Thursday:
EOD check-in message
Performance review (Account Manager, Team Lead, Project Owner, every 2 weeks)
Friday:
Investment time/Tech Radar
Sprint Review
Retrospective</description></item><item><title>fbsc</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</guid><description>Budget We do need to know clients&amp;rsquo; budgets. This is often uncomfortable for them but their budget helps determines what scope is possible. It saves time. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know their budget, we discuss different options.
We talk about breaking product rollout into stages and try to improve the product&amp;rsquo;s chances of success at each stage by:
Focusing on a small subset of features. Designing a valuable user experience. Developing a meaningful relationship with users.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</guid><description>TRAINING COURSE: HOW TO WORK WITH CLIENT What skills that an engineer should have in order to work with client effectively?
Strong technical skills: includes Basics of testing: Unit, Integration, System Software testing and debugging Attention to details
Communication skills: good English skills (both written and verbal)
-&amp;gt; require somewhere Intermediate - Upper Intermediate level
Problem solving and logical thinking
Work planning
Teamwork
Project Management
Consistency in delivering work result</description></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</guid><description>Lean Canvas Lean Canvas is an adaptation of Business Model Canvas by Alexander Osterwalder which Ash Maurya created in the Lean Startup spirit (Fast, Concise and Effective startup). Lean Canvas promises an actionable and entrepreneur-focused business plan. It focuses on problems, solutions, key metrics, and competitive advantages.
1. Problem What is the crucial problem faced by the product’s consumers? Capture their central frustration. The best way to describe the problem is in terms of the jobs customers need to do, what they are ultimately trying to achieve and what is the pain or frustration they currently feel.</description></item><item><title>prototype</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</guid><description>Low-fidelity prototype: UI Design Research 1. Understand prospect Understanding stakeholder, company, business model, goals and challenges of the product in order to set mindset, define style, color palette, and typography, iconography, illustration, and photography.
2. Define product Style Based on the target user and product’s requirement, we define layout style. Make references from Dribbble, Behance and other showcase sites to catch up with the current design trends.
Color Define primary and secondary based on the logo and branding of the product.</description></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</guid><description>GENERAL QUESTIONS FOR SERVICE FEEDBACKS Engineer performances
a. Communication
How did the engineer interact with your team? How was the communication between the engineer and your team? Was our engineer proactive in communicating with you? Did our engineer ask lots of questions? On which aspect our engineer should improve to provide better communication? b. Work ethic, delivery
Have our engineers “coming to work” on time? Have you ever had to wait too long to get a response from our engineer?</description></item><item><title>UI</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UX</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</guid><description>UX Research Framework 1. Gather Data In the first phase, we focus on gathering as much valuable data as humanly possible. It’s time for open-question asking, non-judgmental listening, and meticulous note-taking.
Stakeholder Interview In order to create successful products as a designer, it’s crucial to discover how the stakeholders think - what is the vision for the product (from each of the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; perspectives), and how can these be amalgamated?</description></item><item><title>wireframe</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</guid><description>Wireframe: Workflow Design Created on scraps of paper, a whiteboard, or in a software program, serve to establish relationships between elements in a project such as navigation, imagery, and calls to action.
Often, a wireframe has 3 core goals:
To show the content and functionality of the pages before any further designs. To help designers communicate with clients about the design concept. To establish the information hierarchy of the site.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t edit this file Well, actually you can actually edit this file. It won&amp;rsquo;t actually do much since this is a placeholder to avoid a weird bug when we deploy our site.
We can only travel on the paved road in the forest of bugs :monkas:</description></item><item><title>Index</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation 2018 Wrapping Up 2020 In A Flashback 2021 Dwarves In Review 2021 July Updates 2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Quick Intro To Webassembly A Tips Of Hiring Dont A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google aarrr Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell About Devops Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Account Adapt Cucumber As A Bdd For Wego Add Type Safe Client Server Support For Next Boilerplate Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform Adoption Of Pnpm Adoption Of Pnpm Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support Adversarial Prompting Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool An Alternative To Tm An Engineering Story Map For Llms An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate Android Ant Design Apache Kafka Apache Spark Applied Security Basis Apply Blue Green Deployment To Mochi Apply Monorepos To Repit To Resolve The Problem Of Consistency Apply Page Object Model Structure To Aharooms Apply Page Object Model Structure To Artzy Apply Page Object Model Structure To Basehq Apply Page Object Model Structure To Sci Apply Page Object Model Structure To Wego Applying Mock Service Worker Msw For Seamless Web Development Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr Apprentice Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem Architecture Decision Record Are We Really Engineers Are You Helping Argocd Asking As A Junior Astro Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services Augusts Forward Engineering Avoid Burn Out Backend For Call Requests To Binance And Get Data From Multiple Platforms Backstage Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup Benefits And Perks Beyond The Title Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App Blockchain For Designers Blocking Distraction Blue Green Deployment Brainery Blue Green Deployment Brainery Metrics Report Brainery Progressive Delivery Brainery Validation With Zod Bric A Brac Browserstack Build A Passcode View With Swift Build An Assistant On The Terminal Build Automation For Sci Build Your Chatbot With Open Source Large Language Models Building A Solid High Performing Team Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage Building Reliable Apps Sentry And Distributed Tracing For Effective Monitoring Bunk License Check business-playbook-outline Carbon Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session Case Study From Multiple Repo To Monorepo At Nghe Nhan Case Study How Blue Green Deployment Help Mochi Centralize Dwarves Calendar Challenge Faced When Researching Rlhf With Open Assistant Chatbot Adversarial Prompt Chatbot Llm Accuracy Chatbot Memory Chatbot Prompt Size Chatgpt Assistance Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue Chromatic Chunking Strategies To Overcome Context Limitation In Llm Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience Clickhouse Cloudflare Workers Codecept Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas collaboration-guideline Commitlint Common Design Patterns In Golang Part 1 Company Signature Company Social Graph Competency Mapping Conduct A Meeting Configure The Company Email Connecting Vim With Golang Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating Constructive Feedback Consulting Map Continuous Translation Copilot Cost Of React Native Create Api Service For Urbox To Sync Orders From 3rd Parties And Manage Shipment Create Backend Monorepo To Share Code And Manage Multiple Services In One Repo Create Circular Text Using Swiftui Create Working Devcontainer For Go Api Create Working Devcontainer For Nextjs Boilerplate Cucumber Cypress Daemons And Services Programming Guide Dapr Data Analyst In Retail Trading Database Designs For Multilingual Apps Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab Dealing With Long Term Memory Of Chatbot December All Hands Meeting Definition Of Done Delegate Work Not Responsibility Delegation And Believe It Will Work Deno Design Better Mobile Application Design Resourcestools Design System Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup Design Tips Tricks Design Workflow design-sprint Detox Devcontainers Develop Develop Codecept To Integrate With Fortress Develop Sdk Integration Demo For Sajari Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions Devpod Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao df-workflow Diagnosing And Resolving Performance Issues With Pprof And Trace In Go Different Ways To Test React Application Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process Discord Publish Braniery Discord Role Discord Roles Docker Microcontainers Docker Registry Domain Glossary Domain Insight Research Framework Dora Metrics Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui Duckdb Dwarves Community Bounty Dwarves Community Earn Dwarves Email Domain Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022 Dwarves Memo Dwarves Newsletter Dwarves Of 2021 Dwarves Of The Year 2022 Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03 Dwarves Ventures Fund 0 Dwarves Ventures Fund 1 Dwarvesf Map Earthly Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Economic Calendar Effective Meeting Elixir Elixir Umbrella Project Embracing Go 1210s Slog A Unified Logging Interface With Benchmarks Against Zerolog And Zap Engagament Log Enigma Checksum Erlang Error Handling And Failure Management In A Go System Error Logging Convention Eslint Estimation In Agile Event Sourcing Example Newsletter Excalidraw Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models Exploring Resumable Server Side Rendering With Qwik Expo Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation fbsc Fe 23 Training Type Safe Client Server Feature Toggle Federated Byzantine Figma Financial Literacy Outline Finite State Machine First Introduced Use Of Duckdb In Consolelabs Logconsoleso Fixed Budget Scope Controlled Fleeting Notes Focus On Software Delivery Formal Verification Fortress Mma Score Fortress Shanky Data Forward Engineering 2022 Forward Engineering June 2023 Forward Engineering March 2023 Forward Engineering May 2023 Foundation Model From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo Frontend Fullstack Tracing Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress Gestalt Principle Gestalt Principles In Ui Design Getting Started With Webflow Git Commit Message Convention Gitflow Pull Request Github Actions Go Concurrency Go In Software Engineering Go The Extra Mile Go Training 2023 From Basic To Advanced Golang Golang Good Design Understanding Grafana Graylog Grid And Layout Growth Growth Is Our Universal Language Happy 2023 Headless Ui Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg Hiring Approach Hiring For Operations Team Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs Hoppscotch How A Design System Work How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi How People Matter Should Work How We Contribute To Homebrew How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt How We Hire How We Setup Cicd How We Work how-to-work-with-clients how-to-work-with-clients Hunger Game I18n Frontend Guideline IA Infinite Image Gallery With R3f An Approach Integrate Playwright To Run E2e Test With Fortress Integrate Playwright X Codecept With Discord Integrate Rss Feed Integrate Ts Reset Integrate Zod To Nextjs Boilerplate Intern Introduce To Dwarves Memo Introduction To Software Craftsmanship IOS Ipfs Istio January Updates Jotai K6 K9s Kaniko Konvoy X Dwarves Kotlin Kubernetes Helm 101 Kubeseal Sops Ladle Langchain Large Language Model Llm Layer 2 Zk Rollup lean-canvas lean-canvas Learn Typescript As A Mandatory To Develop Reapit Foundation Lessons Learned Building An Llm Chatbot A Case Study Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Micro Frontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Microfrontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Level Up Your Testing Game Harnessing Gomock For Unbeatable Unit Testing In Go Life At Dwarves Software Design Group Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves Live View Llm 101 Enhance Developer Productivity Llm Query Caching Llms Accuracy Self Refinement Locale Web Mobile Loki Looking Back 2019 Make Remote Working Works Makefile Making A Career Making Decision As A Team Member Managing Dataflow And Sql Database With Concurrency Control May 2022 All Hands Meeting Mbti Type Estj Mbti Type Intj Mbti Type Istj Mbti Type Istp Mdx Document For Memo Blue Green Deployment Memo React Native New Architecture Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq Micro Frontend Micro Frontends Microservices For Frontend Development Migrate Aharooms Pms To Typescript Migrate Headlessui To Radixui Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Fortress Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Nextjs Boilerplate Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Nghe Nhan Droppii Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In React Toolkit monitoring Monorepo Monorepo Deployment Flow Msw N6n nda Nestjs Netlify Newrelic Nextjs Nextjs Boilerplate Nghenhan Microservices Nodejs Nostrum note.</description></item><item><title>Our View On Fullstack Engineering</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</guid><description>In tackling challenges in the world of software development, the term &amp;ldquo;full-stack engineer&amp;rdquo; often evokes a sense of wonder. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of my school days when our chemistry teacher explained the fundamental principles behind chemical reactions. Just as every chemical reaction is governed by the behavior of atoms, there&amp;rsquo;s an underlying principle in software development that defines full-stack engineering.
At its core, full-stack engineering is more than just a developer who works on both the backend and frontend.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves Software Design Group</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</guid><description>The idea: A path to better software “Everything in software architecture is a trade-off, and the why is more important than how.&amp;quot; Neal Ford is a Director and software architect at ThoughtWorks
At Dwarves, we believe that growth is our universal language, and we always strive to improve ourselves, individual-wise and team-wise.
At the end of 2021, starting with engineering practices, the core idea behind creating a software design group is to enable engineers to develop the skills required to become software architects.</description></item><item><title>Happy 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/happy-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/happy-2023/</guid><description>As we enter a new year, I want to reflect on the role that software has played in my life. From the early days of my career to now, software has been a constant presence and something that I have dedicated countless hours to as both an engineer and project manager. I have put in over 10,000 hours of work in this field, and it has become an integral part of my existence.</description></item><item><title>2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</guid><description>Table of Content: 2022 Dwarves Renaissance: A Year-End Rewind Successfully went through 2022, a year that we might say - a new record: team reached highest growth record, kickstarted community engagement, home, compliance training &amp;amp; individual development are speeding up, and a whole new place to call Dwarves.
We’ve achieved to this year’s resolution: A team that cares about how to build software right and can teach others on that.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of The Year 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</guid><description>Dwarves of The Year 2022 - Wins to Celebrate It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, but we&amp;rsquo;ve finally made it to 2022 and what a year it&amp;rsquo;s been for our team of Dwarves. Countless hours of hard work and it&amp;rsquo;s all paid off with our big wins of the year. Honored for all and huge congratulations for our Dwarves of 2022.
A total of ~$18,000 awarded and rewarded by ****$ICY - Dwarves official token, with a few names appearing several times.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</guid><description>Dwarves Summit 2022: Engineering a good time. We don’t treat team bonding the common way, because we understand our engineers. Most of our engineers don’t want running and getting sweaty on the beach for “team-building” activities, or pretending to smile in front of the travel agent’s camera.
This was our first company get-together after 2 years of COVID. It was organized in ways that we can all look back to the progress we’ve made, pat ourselves on the back, have a blast together, and look forward to an even better 2023.</description></item><item><title>The Key Of Security Mechanisms In Tackling Cyber Threats</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</guid><description>Hosted by Thanh Pham - Engineering Manager, Dwarves had a great time with the best minds in cybersecurity- Mr. Hieu PC to share his knowledge and experience. As someone who is always looking to improve skills, this event is extremely valuable. We learned a lot about the different elements of cybersecurity and how to better protect our code.
Hieu PC was a pro ex-hacker who made headlines and is now a Security Expert at Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s National Cybersecurity Centre (NCSC).</description></item><item><title>Configure The Company Email</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</guid><description>1. Make sure you have 2FA enabled For this method to work, you need to have two factor authentification enabled for your Google account. If it’s not, follow the link below and set it up.
https://www.google.com/landing/2step/
2. Create an App Password Google will verify your ownership with this app password. Select “Mail” under app, and “Mac” under device. Hit “Generate”. Copy and keep for later!
3. Add your email to Gmail Go to Gmail -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Accounts and Import.</description></item><item><title>Tech Event In The Latest Transforming Healthcare With Technology</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/tech-event---in-the-latest-transforming-healthcare-with-technology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/tech-event---in-the-latest-transforming-healthcare-with-technology/</guid><description>Hosted by Nikki - Dwarves&amp;rsquo; COO, and Thanh Pham - Engineering Manager, Dwarves had a great lineup and gleaned insights on the new wave of healthcare through the immense knowledge and practical experience through inspiring stories from Ms. Ruby Nguyen and Mr. Binh Le.
Start-up ideas come from your own needs.
“Momby started with the health needs of a pregnant mother and grew by understanding the worries of soon-to-be parents. Momby aims to provide a foundation for supporting knowledge, creating a safe and reliable space for expecting parents to freely learn, share, and help one another helping, thus making social impacts on Maternity care.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</guid><description>It’s our second attempt rolling out this program. But the motivation stays the same: Accelerating someone’s current software development skillset.
It’s neither for interns nor veterans. As stated in the beginning, our goal is to empower software engineers with at least 1 years of experience to rebuild their foundation through:
Software Development Practices Real-projects Scenarios Engineering Work Ethics &amp;amp; Principles The stats speak Although keeping the bar high might extend the searching time, but we maintain a solid standard for every batch.</description></item><item><title>From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-data-to-backend-an-apprentice-sharing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-data-to-backend-an-apprentice-sharing/</guid><description>For My Anh*, Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship has surpassed a traditional training program concept. With her, it’s been a huge shift: A supportive team that embraces her for who she is and unlocks her capabilities to grow in ways she never imagined. *
My Anh, Saigon-based Data &amp;amp; Backend
Dwarves Apprentices, batch of 2022
How did you first envision the Dwarves Apprenticeship Program? “I expected it would be a stepping stone to reinforcing my software development skillset.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</guid><description>English below ↓ **Life at Dwarves #6**, là những chia sẻ của Hiếu Vũ về hành trình pick up và yêu thích Golang, quá trình gắn bó từ dự án đến con người tại Dwarves. Những trải nghiệm đó để lại cho Hiếu nhiều bài học và lời khuyên cho các bạn trẻ muốn theo đuổi công việc lập trình viên. Hiếu Vũ từng là thực tập sinh ở tập đoàn công nghệ KMS, và hiện tại là Backend Engineer tại Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</guid><description>English below ↓
**Life at Dwarves #5** là câu chuyện về Nam Nguyễn và hành trình hơn 5 năm gắn bó với Dwarves. Sau khi hoàn thành Cao Đẳng, Nam làm ở một công ty offshore của Nhật Bản với vị trí Fullstack Engineer. Sau khi quyết định nghỉ việc tại công ty cũ để tập trung cho tấm bằng Đại học, Nam gia nhập Dwarves, và trở thành một trong những contributor lâu nhất tại tech firm này.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</guid><description>***“Anh nghiệm ra rằng trong hành trình trở thành Senior Software Engineer, càng thử thách bản thân, mọi thứ sẽ càng thú vị.”*** Life at Dwarves lần này là một nhân vật khá kín tiếng ở Dwarves với đời sống lành mạnh và tính cách nhẹ nhàng. Anh An Trần, Senior Software Engineer với 7 năm kinh nghiệm làm nghề từ các start-up đến Project Lead tại Dwarves Foundation.</description></item><item><title>May 2022 All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>FOUNDATION Project Allocation
We concluded the partnership with Relay and Eklipse. It has been a fun (and wild) ride for some of you. New resources are being allocated to help balance the current workload of active projects. If you need to discuss your workload or seek more room for project work, please help ping Giang or Nikki.
Our view on Blockchain
Got a quick chat with Ngoc Thanh, our Sr.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</guid><description>[DF APPRENTICESHIP 2022 - MEET THE MENTORS]
Dwarves Team is shifting our focus to blockchain technology. We offer study groups and blockchain-based projects for peeps to grow and catch up with this rising trend. Thanh is one of the vital elements of this team; and we know he’ll be more than happy to have you onboard.
What raises your interest for Dwarves?
“My path at Dwarves began with the zeal to develop web3 and blockchain products.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</guid><description>Tuan Dao - Senior Frontend/ Blockchain Engineer
Tuan has 4+ years of experience under his belt, 2 out of those 4+ was spent at Dwarves Foundation. Tuan’s years of experience don’t quite do him justice though, for he’s skilled and knowledge beyond the year, and has took part in projects of various sizes and domains.
When asked what’s the force behind, Tuan shared it’s because of is very own principle of working: “To find joy in your profession”.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</guid><description>A catch-up with Tom - our Data Lead, and hear how remote working has fit him perfectly. Tom is one of our core contributors of Dwarves Brainery, and he&amp;rsquo;ll be playing as a key mentor for our upcoming Apprenticeship.
Working remotely fits me well. It keeps me from distraction. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m always at home, so WFH is awesome. My previous workplace required people to be at the office and hang out for drinks afterward, and it was a bit overwhelmed in my pov.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</guid><description>Anh, in short, is the UI wizard behind most of our branding identity. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing her work of art on every Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s digital asset.
A person can take care of both UX and UI design if the project is small. As a product designer, you&amp;rsquo;re expected to know both. “I work for the graphic side, mainly on UI, app appearance, and app research to gain more insight for the team.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</guid><description>Been with us for nearly 5 years, Thanh has been taking care of the juniors and ensuring their progress goes alongside the company’s direction. He is also the co-host of Dwarves Radio Talk - our weekly tech training every Monday.
My job is to ensure a healthy environment for everyone to thrive. “I guide and train people if they are assigned to me. Dwarves Team has a 60-day Program to evaluate, and it usually is a 90-day plan, but based on the company size, the timeline can be adjusted to optimize its teammate growth.</description></item><item><title>2021 Dwarves In Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-dwarves-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-dwarves-in-review/</guid><description>Table of Content Wrapping up Dwarves 1.0 A few things worth celebrating We are expanding Dwarves 1.0 in numbers Highlighted Dwarves of 2021 Onto Dwarves 2.0 **Started with 3 engineers working in different coffee shops because we didn&amp;rsquo;t have an office back then, we are gearing up for the second coming in our journey with over 40 clients and partners worldwide, +1M lines of code later throughout more than 7 years.</description></item><item><title>December All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/december-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/december-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>Moving with Blockchain We shift our focus to real deals.
Meanwhile, #blockchain #web3 channels are there for the Dwarves to learn &amp;amp; exchange their knowns. Grab your seat.
The teammates also propose to join blockchain projects. We’re happy onboard Hien, Tu and Ngoc Mai on Spike Inu and Eklipse - and actively seek more chances for our teammates.
Selective in Project Decision It’s a promise of bigger clients &amp;amp; better team deployment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of 2021</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-2021/</guid><description>Dwarves of 2021 - We met at last ♡ Apart from the voting result from the team of each title, we also have the Honorable Mention and Client Endorsed - selected by the team leads, as we want to honor all of the hard work.
You can find the voting details here. The final result was close, since you’re all awesome!
Let’s all welcome our Dwarves of 2021 🛠</description></item><item><title>The Dwarves Culture Handbook</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</guid><description>For the past 5 years, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have something called &amp;lsquo;Culture Book&amp;rsquo;. Whenever a newbie steps in, it&amp;rsquo;s natural to pick up the job and go with the flow. We hardly force them into other periodical office traps like team-bonding activities or late night drinks. It&amp;rsquo;s likely to be &amp;lsquo; Hey it&amp;rsquo;s your birthday give us a treat&amp;rsquo;; and next thing you know, 30 milk tea or coffee orders are on the way.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</guid><description>Android Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN ANDROID DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Knowledge in Dart fundamentals and Flutter framework Passionate about programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Android Development in Java/Kotlin is a plus You own the Android platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Benefits And Perks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Since the majority of Dwarves Foundation employees work in Saigon, this section is written with that as the default. Some benefits don’t make sense in other countries. We will try our best to provide comparable benefits and perks as it makes sense, though.
Continuing Education Allowance You will always grow by learning and playing with new and cool technologies. From books to conferences, you’ll get a yearly budget for your individual learning and development goals.</description></item><item><title>How We Hire</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</guid><description>How we hire Hiring means we need help. We only hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. We always look for long-term teammates that why we want to ensure the new hire is a value fit and culture fit.
Rounds Several Dwarves will talk to the candidates to walk them through 4 rounds
Pre-assessment: We evaluate the logic, English, and the personalities in non-interrupted 30 minutes online test.</description></item><item><title>How We Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</guid><description>How we work We do Agile We build software. The way we see it is a collaboration between multiple people in the team with sufficient knowledge on the domain and clearly understand the project vision that they can quickly adapt to the changes in the market. We adopt the Agile philosophy at this level.
Also, based on that philosophy, we apply the Scrum framework, which we find out a good fit for us.</description></item><item><title>Making A Career</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</guid><description>Making a Career The average tenure of employees working at many technology companies today is shockingly low. At both Amazon, Google and other companies, it’s just around one year. At Dwarves Foundation, it’s just around three years as of late 2018. That’s something to be proud of, and something to ensure endures. When you work at Dwarves Foundation, it should be feasible to think about this as the place for making a life-long career.</description></item><item><title>What We Stand For</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</guid><description>What we stand for Empower Innovation with Software Craftsmanship Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.
Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time.</description></item><item><title>What We Value</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</guid><description>What we value Before anything else, values come first. The value is important to us. They are what we proud of. They help guide us when we are facing a difficult decision. They will be the things you like about what we do at Dwarves Foundation and how we do it.
Our core values guide our strategies and individual actions so that we create a company whose character is as radical as our work.</description></item><item><title>Where We Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</guid><description>Where we work Office The Dwarves HQ is in Saigon, Vietnam. Thirty people and two cats have desk space in the Saigon office, but those people also work from home regularly. We expand the office space when the old one is full and people want the new office. Anyone is welcome to visit Saigon and work from the office at any time.
From home A few people at Dwarves Foundation are based in other countries and they work from home most of the time.</description></item></channel></rss>