<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in Career on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>穢 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marketing and Communications Specialist</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Specialists to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will have a passion for technology, a strong understanding of the software development industry, and excellent communication skills.
This role will involve developing and implementing marketing strategies, creating compelling content, managing social media presence, and maintaining effective communication with both internal and external stakeholders.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Consultant Growth Track</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</guid><description>While there is no fixed path in the consulting field, we do have a structured growth guidance for career development, skill enhancement, and professional advancement.
Tier 1: Associate Consultant What you do Participate in client engagements, assisting senior consultants Gain exposure to various projects and technologies Learn company methodologies, tools, and best practices Perform research, analysis, and contribute to project documentation Skills needed Expert technical skills Client needs and project requirements gathering Project management basics Communication and presentation skills Reward Project lead bonus Tier 2: Consultant What you do Lead projects or work streams Communicate directly with clients, understanding business objectives Analyze complex problems and provide technical solutions Develop and present proposals, contributing to business development Mentor junior team members and contribute to knowledge sharing Skills needed Specialization in specific tech stacks / domains Advanced project management and leadership skills Client relationship management Deep understanding of industry-specific challenges / solutions Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Tier 3: Lead Consultant What you do Oversee multiple projects or departments Act as a subject matter expert in specialized areas Provide thought leadership, guide strategy, and drive innovation Represent the company at industry events and conferences Skills needed Strategic thinking and business acumen Thought leadership through publications or public speaking Mentorship and coaching of consultants Advanced problem-solving and critical thinking skills Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Tier 4: Partner What you do Set strategic direction and drive business growth Establish and maintain key client relationships Contribute to company-wide decision-making and management Skills needed Leadership and organizational management Business development, sales, and negotiation skills Operational efficiency and financial management Reward Project lead bonus Sales bonus Company shares dfg</description></item><item><title>Business Development</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Business Development talents to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Culture Handbook</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</guid><description>Towards growth Keep learning and growing. We started this team out of software practice advancement.
The continuous study lays the foundation for the future growth. Just like software, knowledge must evolve and be useful. We collect the lesson learned and input into our team knowledge base.
Purpose-built Everything we do comes with the purpose behind. Good software is software that works and provide actual value. Effort is count when it&amp;rsquo;s placed on things that matter.</description></item><item><title>Executive Assistant</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for an Executive Assistant to join Dwarves and work remotely. We are seeking a highly organized, proactive, and experienced Executive Assistant to provide support to our senior executives. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Technical Recruiter</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a Technical Recruiter to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will play a pivotal role in sourcing, attracting, and hiring top-tier talents and take care of our team members&amp;rsquo; growth.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>React Native Developer</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for talented developer with experience in React Native to join Dwarves and work remotely, on a fast-growing US startup.
 Apply now (We respond within three days)
 As an engineer at Dwarves, you will be working closely with a team of talented, kind people and working directly with our clients. There is a lot of freedom to contribute to the quality of the project and improve, or prove yourself.</description></item><item><title>Careers</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/</guid><description>When we put Foundation in our name, we mean it. We want to put in place a team of go-getters who solve real-world problems, build big platforms, and spread goodwill across communities.
Join us. Let&amp;rsquo;s create the next big things together. At Dwarves, you will be working with an experienced, talented team who loves technology and knows how to use technology to better life on a global level.
Apply: Marketing and Communications Specialist How we work at Dwarves.</description></item></channel></rss>