<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 as an innovation arm of INDODAX, Tokenomy is a crypto investment network through blockchain-enabled tokens. Currently reached the seed round funded by LazyLedger, Tokenomy aims to reach a broader customer segment through web platforms and mobile apps. We fully support a team of Senior Frontend Engineer, Android Mobile Engineer, and UX Designer to help them stay on track with the release timeline. Technical Highlight MVVM for mobile application architecture WebSocket for real-time trading support Reactivex to bind data and process asynchronous tasks Biometric authentication approach for data encryption Custom-built Android module to support different APIs Weekly product changelog apply for the team synergy The Context They came to us at first to refactor the frontend foundation.</description></item><item><title>Understanding An Application Design</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/understanding-an-application-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/understanding-an-application-design/</guid><description>Requested by our Apprentices, and hosted by Thanh Pham - our Head of Web. Understanding an Application Design is the upfront work for every web project. An application design consists of different main parts, which we highlighted a few below.
Type of Web Project Admin dashboard Client app(almost Listing app) Landing page Important Factors The critical factors that helps define the right framework
Type of Project Required SEO support State of Design: Sketch, Mockup, or Final design Cost for development Number of end-users: 10-100, 100-1000, &amp;gt;1000 Required Responsive Rendering Technique The process of taking HTML code and interprets it into visual results and interactive web pages.</description></item><item><title>Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2019, Para is a platform connecting hospitals with medical professionals. Continuing with Go microservices, we have shipped numerous features, markedly workshift management and candidate screening. We partnered and helped unburden Para from the financial stress during the early stage of their MVP development. Our Covid-19 program was launched in early 2020. We aim to provide software development, technical support for startups and businesses to help them stay stable during and progress forward despite the pandemic.</description></item><item><title>The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Aharooms wants to be a remarkable Vietnamese brand in franchised hotel chains. They look to enter the affordable hotel market to support business owners. Their vision was to build an MVP for market testing in no time. Aharooms&amp;rsquo;s system had almost 2 years in development. It demands high effort to balance new feature development with technical debt. We step in as product team and venture builder. We take on the development stage that supercharges their product development.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</guid><description>One of the factors that could make or break a project is the process of communication between designers and developers. Designers and developers have their own working “languages.”
It’s important to find a protocol in which a mutual language can bridge the gap between designers and developers. This protocol helps everyone in the team understand the ultimate objective of the project, minimize the guesswork, save time and effort, ensuring the high-quality standard outcomes we promised to deliver to clients.</description></item><item><title>Domain Insight Research Framework</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/domain-insight-research-framework/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/domain-insight-research-framework/</guid><description>As a designer working in the Digital Product industry, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we all hear about UX Research once at least. In this field, we learn about the business&amp;rsquo;s strategy, users&amp;rsquo; behaviors, needs, pain points, etc. to build a product that meets the business&amp;rsquo;s goal and solves users&amp;rsquo; existing problems. There are multiple ways to do UX research; our team also has one. However, there is a higher level, which helps UX Researchers process their works much faster, empathize with target users much easier, and save more effort and time; it is called Domain Insight Research.</description></item><item><title>Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</guid><description>In brief Founded by Desmond Goh - a Singaporean dental surgeon, Dental Marketplace is an online platform for dental professionals to stay active in dentistry and simplify operation process. Web and App development as MVP release for marketing testing and user feedback. We support them with tech solution and market-fit product design. We work according with Desmond to extract business problem and propose suitable solution. Technical Highlight Product-fit Design: Design Thinking Method &amp;amp; Design UX research for Golang-backend: Steady and microservices-extendable system Startup-centric: Scalable system &amp;amp; cost-efficient solution Microservice architecture Agile process and Scrum framework for product iteration The Context Singapore dentists faces bottlenecks to practice dentistry and operates dental clinic with SDC rules licensed regulated by MOH.</description></item><item><title>An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</guid><description>How is the real estate market moving? When an industry begins this journey of digital transformation depends largely on the specific nature of its offering. As a rule of thumb, the more product-oriented and direct-to-customer an industry is, the sooner its digital transformation journey begins. The first important question is: why do industries go through this transformation process? What is the overall purpose? One common misconception is that fear is a major driver of transformation - the fear of being disrupted, the fear of becoming obsolete, the fear of losing out.</description></item><item><title>Grid And Layout</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/grid-and-layout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/grid-and-layout/</guid><description>To almost fresher who started in Graphic design and Digital design, who wants to make our model look beautiful and right. When we - fresher receive brief directly from the client or leader, we start to search online for ideas. Honestly, those projects look pretty good, super clean, and all you want is your project look the same way as them, but you just CAN’T. That’s because you don’t do the same way they did.</description></item><item><title>Gestalt Principles In Ui Design</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/gestalt-principles-in-ui-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/gestalt-principles-in-ui-design/</guid><description>Take a second to look at the image above. How do you feel? Do you see that it is similar to an owl face? The answer to this phenomenon is called Isomorphism which is part of the 12 Gestalt rules. Just like Isomorphism, you will sometimes feel that a cloud is similar to a horse or a branding logo which is created by different shapes that can finally turn out to be a meaning object.</description></item><item><title>Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</guid><description>We could find a bunch of AARRR frameworks definition across the internet (Thanks to Google). I don’t intend to create another one here.
Today I just want to share the simplest definition of this framework and how we have done here at Dwarves. It is a jumping-off point to brainstorming what AARRR does, and why it’s the important step that needs to be done.
What is AARRR framework by the way AARRR is a revenue-driven funnel, what makes it different than other funnels?</description></item><item><title>How A Design System Work</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-a-design-system-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-a-design-system-work/</guid><description>This talk is created from my experiences &amp;amp; lesson learnt, the rule and self-code I&amp;rsquo;ve built and believe to be applicable. So I can guarantee you may not find some of it in any other places on the internet.
Table of Content Color Style &amp;amp; Text Style Naming Convention Component Naming Convention &amp;amp; Component Structure Auto Layout Application Description of Design System Naming Convention Color Style Naming Convention There are 2 types of color: Flat &amp;amp; Gradient.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain For Designers</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/blockchain-for-designers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/blockchain-for-designers/</guid><description>Intro Recently, Bitcoin and Blockchain become popular, they are the trending and media’s favorite topics. Blockchain is buzzing with the capability of solving trust issues in not only the technology but also other domains like economies and even government regulators. Though people are talking about this promising technology, it’s too complicated for everyone to understand what precisely it is and how it works. The complexity of Blockchain and what it does make users feel confused and suspicious, which builds a huge barrier between users and products.</description></item><item><title>Design Better Mobile Application</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-better-mobile-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-better-mobile-application/</guid><description>This workshop wraps up the useful information on 2 types of operating system for UX/UI designers, based on the personal research on iOS and Android. The purpose is to create an application that brings comfortability and a great experience to the end user.
Table of Content Introduction to iOS &amp;amp; Android The platforms to build application Useful tips to create an effective mobile application Introduction to iOS &amp;amp; Android Adjustment &amp;amp; Privacy iOS has better privacy protection since it belongs exclusively to iOS, but this leads to the limitation of function adjustment.</description></item><item><title>Domain Glossary</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/domain-glossary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/domain-glossary/</guid><description>T1: Retail 2.0 Definition
Enhancing consumer engagement within brick and mortar - online/using mobile devices, moving beyond simply blending in the online and the mobile experience, all driven at the heart by sophisticated big data tools that truly enable contextual, personalized and real-time conversations between brands, retailers and consumers. [1] Made up of AR (augmented reality), VR (virtual reality), in-store apps, new payment methods and artificial intelligence. Personalized Exp Designing or producing services and products to meet customer&amp;rsquo;s individual requirements.</description></item><item><title>Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</guid><description>In brief AirWatt is an IoT solution that integrates and monitors electricity usage using AI/ML. AirWatt&amp;rsquo;s vision is to help businesses track electric usage status of electrical equipment. Hence, they can save electricity and money, even avoid disaster. They seek for product development support, with insight on business to provide suitable product design The MVP must be done fast to prove the product&amp;rsquo;s concept. We built Airwatt system from zero with other teams: Business, Hardware, and AI.</description></item><item><title>Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</guid><description>Introduction BHD is one of the biggest cinema chains in Vietnam with hundreds of thousands tickets sold monthly. However, its mobile application is a complete drawback; users cannot book tickets online, it feels and looks outdated, inconsistent and cluttered.
Mission BHD’s new app covers all the basic needs of movie-goers, in an intuitive and pleasant way. Meaning, users can easily scan screening schedules, view movie details and book tickets online.</description></item><item><title>The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 2</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-2/</guid><description>1. Vertical spacing Spacing within each paragraph Firstly, I start the simplest content type — paragraph. One of the atoms decides aesthetic design. So you need to focus on them. You commonly depend on default line-height of the font to design the content. I have increased line by 2px to 3px in this way because they are too tight.
Everything almost has a proportional so line-height also it. 1.5 is a suggestion for you to have a good starting point.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 1</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</guid><description>Introduction The following case study is my first app design project. In this project, I have gone through the design process, including interviews, analysis, user flows, wireframes, prototyping, and user testing.
The mobile app Sol is a travel app focused on some highlight features: planning trips, managing members and expenses, and tracking/sharing location. In facts, when traveling by groups, we often face some troubles: getting lost, confusing with plans, hard-communicating and the most challenging thing: managing expenses.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 3</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</guid><description>Introduction Today we shall continue our series of designing “Sol-Travel Planning” app. As we mentioned our process on UX research and UI design in the last two articles, Sol’s target users are the young so keeping the app fun with interaction is a must.
Main Motions According to Issara Willenskomer from UxinMotion, motion implementation in UX design can greatly help improving usability in four noticeable ways: fulfilling expectation from the users, maintaining continuity among a set of scenes, inventing narrative — story-telling flow throughout the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 2</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</guid><description>Following the previous article on UX case study of Sol — Travel App, an app that was tailored to meet the needs of groups on traveling days. In this article, we will describe our creative process of the UI for it. We choose iOS as our platform to be presented, considering that it is the more favored devices being used.
As we have gone through the UX research tasks in the last article, we started brainstorming about how the mobile application should look.</description></item><item><title>Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/card-sorting-and-a-glimpse-at-experimental-sorting-session/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/card-sorting-and-a-glimpse-at-experimental-sorting-session/</guid><description>As part of our team’s weekly activities is a knowledge sharing session. So, in this article I’d like to share a UX technique we practiced recently — Card Sorting.
And plus, a real lesson learned with our team’s workshop.
A brief intro to Card Sorting Definition Card sorting is a method used to help design or evaluate the information architecture of a site and broader a digital product (web-app and mobile app).</description></item><item><title>Good Design Understanding</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/good-design-understanding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/good-design-understanding/</guid><description>Good design is not just what looks good. It also needs to perform, convert, astonish, and fulfill its purpose. It can be innovative or it might just get the job done.
A good design cannot be measured by a finite way – multiple perspectives are needed.
What is a good UX design? User experience (UX) focuses on having a deep understanding of users, what they need, what they value, their abilities, and also their limitations.</description></item><item><title>Competency Mapping</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/competency-mapping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/competency-mapping/</guid><description>We identified skills and actions showing someone has one competency or not.
Six levels to measure the level of knowledge:
0 – Completely unfamiliar: Doesn’t understand the competency.
1 – Novice: Understands the competency and its importance.
2 – Advanced Beginner: Demonstrates this competency under supervision or with encouragement.
3 – Competent: Demonstrates this competency independent of supervision or encouragement.
4 – Proficient: Encourages or supervises others in this competency.</description></item><item><title>Design Resourcestools</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-resourcestools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-resourcestools/</guid><description>Besides learning the UI design, the most important thing is to learn UX design to create a good user experience. Helps the user get the goal when in your app.
This compilation is synthetic all the websites or tools to help you improve your knowledge of UX Design. All of these websites where UX designers around the world often go to learn, just as you usually do on Behance or Dribbble to find trends, styles or ideas.</description></item><item><title>Design Tips Tricks</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-tips-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-tips-tricks/</guid><description> https://uxplanet.org/the-18-must-do-principles-in-the-form-design-fe89d0127c92 https://blog.prototypr.io/4-common-mistakes-ux-designers-should-avoid-during-product-design-process-cace92d8b8b3 https://uxplanet.org/why-is-online-checkout-so-difficult-and-how-to-simplify-it-eeb3da2ea530</description></item><item><title>Design System</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-system/</guid><description>Now having a Design System in place unites product teams around a common visual language, accelerates your design process ten-fold and gives you a strong foundation to build any project. Learn how you can create a design system and help your team improve product quality when increase the speed of your workflow.
INTRODUCE Today there are many the companies products compete with each other, the company should have one of the conditions:</description></item><item><title>Design Workflow</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/design-workflow/</guid><description>1. Project Research The goal of this step is to figure what the problems you need to solve using your design from asking the people involved such as our customers (businesses owners) and the users, the people who will use your design outcome directly. We don&amp;rsquo;t guess or assume things.
There are 2 types of research you can do to figure this out:
Quantitative: These are the things we can measure.</description></item><item><title>Three Levels Of Design</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/three-levels-of-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/three-levels-of-design/</guid><description>Don Norman in his book titled The Design of Everyday Things talks about three levels of design — Visceral Level, Behavioral Level and Reflective Level — on how they work together and play an important role in determining how people like or dislike the product. In other words, these three levels together determine whether your product is successful or not.
1. Visceral Level Visceral level is about first impression First impression is the best impression.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Fundamental</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-fundamental/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-fundamental/</guid><description>When you design UI for an app or a website, the first thing that the designer needs to determine the purpose of the product and the target audience. You should plan and calculate for your UI design.
Creativity does not exceed the limits of design goals.
Differentiate between customer and user: Put more on the role of the user than the customer
Identify the user who will use your app, identify the behavior, user characteristics.</description></item><item><title>Ux Model</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ux-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ux-model/</guid><description>What is good UX? Useful A new product should first be designed to solve the users&amp;rsquo; problems. It should be the solution users expected. It is necessary to define the users&amp;rsquo; problem and search for ways to resolve it. Failure of defining the problem exactly will lead to failure of getting the right solution to users&amp;rsquo; expectation. Thus, the product will not be useful to them.
Usability A product should be designed that it is easy to use.</description></item><item><title>The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 1</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-1/</guid><description>Why is spacing important? Before I talk about spacing principle, you should know how spacing important is with our design.
In design have four main factors in such as:
Content Graphic Navigation Identify Spacing has not only an impact directly on this factors but also on aesthetics design. Even more, it gives the page a united harmonic look. It decides you want them to pay attention to what. If you know the principle of spacing, you can use it in all your products.</description></item></channel></rss>