<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in work on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Estimation Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</guid><description>When we conduct an estimation, it is recommended to abandon the transitional “exact hours” assessment method, instead, use the story point based on the Fibonacci number (1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21…). The number expresses an estimation of the overall effort required to fully implement a backlog item or any piece of work.
Below’s an example of an estimation table based on the matrix of complexity, uncertainty, and effort:</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Last November, we kicked off the Labs team, introduced Salary Advance for the Dwarves, upgraded note.d.foundation, supported Golang meetup, and demonstrated craftsmanship through various case studies and demos.</description></item><item><title>Careers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</guid><description>When we put Foundation in our name, we mean it. We want to put in place a team of go-getters who solve real-world problems, build big platforms, and spread goodwill across communities.
Join us. Let&amp;rsquo;s create the next big things together. At Dwarves, you will be working with an experienced, talented team who loves technology and knows how to use technology to better life on a global level.
Apply: How we work at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life at Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re like-minded teammates who pursue ambitious goals with tech culture and codes of conduct.
Build a place we love to work at We build this company like we build a product. There are roadmaps for growth; there are phases; there are iterations. There might also be bugs, places where the company crashes because of bad organizational design, or cultural oversights.
That means we advocate for changes. Changes always start with making our people better.</description></item><item><title>Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation Team&amp;rsquo;s guide on our project delivery process. This post will serve as your go-to resource for understanding our weekly, bi-weekly, and monthly activities, ensuring that we stay on track and excel in our deliveries.
Weekly Activities 1. Weekly Points/Effort Report Every Friday
Action: Fill out the weekly points/effort report. Link: Weekly Report Spreadsheet. Deadline for Data Sync: Data is sync by EOD next Tuesday. Outcome: Weekly leaderboard on delivery.</description></item><item><title>Labs - Who we are</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-who-we-are/</guid><description>At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies. We are a diverse group of individuals, each with unique backgrounds and personalities, but our common ground lies in our dedication to exploring and understanding emerging technologies. Our goal is to investigate and learn about advancements that have the potential to enhance our lives and contribute to a better future.
Our beliefs Our culture at Labs is a confluence of diverse backgrounds, personalities, and perspectives, yet united by core beliefs:</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</guid><description> 💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg $icy in 2024 $icy Salary Advance 2018 Wrapping Up 2020 In A Flashback 2021 Dwarves In Review 2021 July Updates 2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Quick Intro To Webassembly A Tips Of Hiring Dont A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell About Devops Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Account Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform Adoption Of Pnpm Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool An Alternative To Tm An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate Applied Security Basis Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem Architecture Decision Record Are We Really Engineers Are You Helping Asking As A Junior Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services Avoid Burn Out Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup Beyond The Title Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App Blockchain For Designers Blocking Distraction Bric A Brac Build A Passcode View With Swift Build An Assistant On The Terminal Building A Solid High Performing Team Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage Bunk License Check Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas Community Bounty Competency Mapping Conduct A Meeting Configure The Company Email Connecting Vim With Golang Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating Constructive Feedback Continuous Translation Cost Of React Native Create Circular Text Using Swiftui Daemons And Services Programming Guide Data Analyst In Retail Trading Database Designs For Multilingual Apps Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab December All Hands Meeting Definition Of Done Delegate Work Not Responsibility Delegation And Believe It Will Work Design Better Mobile Application Design Resourcestools Design System Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup Design Tips Tricks Design Workflow Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao Different Ways To Test React Application Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process Discord Roles Docker Microcontainers Docker Registry Domain Glossary Domain Insight Research Framework Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui DuckDB demo and showcase Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022 Dwarves Memo Dwarves Of 2021 Dwarves Of The Year 2022 Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03 Dwarves Ventures Fund 0 Dwarves Ventures Fund 1 Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Effective Meeting Estimation Guidelines Estimation In Agile Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation Federated Byzantine Finite State Machine Fixed Budget Scope Controlled Focus On Software Delivery Forward Engineering August 2023 Forward Engineering June 2023 Forward Engineering March 2023 Forward Engineering May 2023 Forward Engineering Year 2022 From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress Gestalt Principles In Ui Design Getting Started With Webflow Git Commit Message Convention Gitflow Pull Request Go Concurrency Go In Software Engineering Go The Extra Mile Good Design Understanding Grid And Layout Growth Is Our Universal Language Happy 2023 Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg Hiring Approach Hiring For Operations Team Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs How A Design System Work How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi How People Matter Should Work How R&amp;amp;D contributes to Performance Review How We Contribute To Homebrew How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt How We Setup Cicd I18n Frontend Guideline Infinite Image Gallery With R3f An Approach Introduce To Dwarves Memo Introduction To Software Craftsmanship Istio January Updates Knowledge Journey Konvoy X Dwarves Kubernetes Helm 101 Labs - New Member Onboarding Labs - Topic proposal &amp;amp; progress tracking Labs - Who we are Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update) Labs Team Labs Team Labs Weekly Catchup #1 Labs x Consulting Workflow Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Micro Frontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Life At Dwarves Software Design Group Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves Looking Back 2019 Make Remote Working Works Making Decision As A Team Member Managing Dataflow And Sql Database With Concurrency Control May 2022 All Hands Meeting Mbti Type Estj Mbti Type Intj Mbti Type Istj Mbti Type Istp Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq Micro Frontends Microservices For Frontend Development November Forward Engineering 2023 Objective October Forward Engineering 2023 Ogif Open Fabric Set The Tech Foundation And Built An Mvp From Scratch Our Daily Standup Format Our Metrics For Performance Review Our Policy For Remote Working Our View On Fullstack Engineering Overview On Broker Pattern In Distributed System Passing The Probation Get 3 Upvotes Playaround With Clojure Playaround With Rust Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines Project Management Qc Onboarding Radio Talk 60 Blue Green Deployment Radio Talk 61 Monorepo React 18 React Native New Architecture Recursively Export File Pattern In Javascript Es6 Application Red Flags Remix Versus Nextjs Remote Moderated Usability Testing Remote Prepare And Get Going Remove Unused Css Styles From Bootstrap Using Purgecss Reproduce Apple Find Me Bottom Menu View Resource Assignment Responsibility Reusability In Software Development Reward Model &amp;amp; Nomination Road To 100 Sdk Event Sourcing Setting The Budget Setup React Project With Webpack And Babel Six Things I Extracted From Design Thinking Skill Of Software Engineer Slice And Array In Golang Software Development Life Cycle 101 Software Modeling Sol Travel Planning App Part 1 Sol Travel Planning App Part 2 Sol Travel Planning App Part 3 Spike Inu Engineering A Seamless Experience For Cross Chain Swap And Decentralized Exchange Split And Reuse Code In React Application Sprint Lifecycle Sql Practices Orm Vs Plain Sql Startups Vs Junior Designers Startupvn Succeed Naru A Browser Focus Web Extension For Us Market Supercharged Setel Malaysias First Pay Pump Go Super App Support Relay In Shipping Their Mvp Product For Us Market Testing Swiftui Team Up With Basehq Us First Ever Platform Built For Assistants Tech Event In The Latest Transforming Healthcare With Technology The 10x Engineer The Adjacent Possible The Correct Way To Build Kpi The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions The Dwarves Culture Handbook The Dwarves Runs By Ideas The Four Preferences The Inner Circle The Key Of Security Mechanisms In Tackling Cyber Threats The Next Leading Chairs The Okr The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 1 The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 2 Three Levels Of Design Traits To Assess During An Interview Transparency Types Of Employees Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves Ui Design Fundamental Uidynamicanimator Understanding An Application Design Unit Testing Best Practices In Golang Use Go Selenium To Crawl Data Using Correct Html Element To Increase Website Accessibility Ux Model Well Crafted Software What I Learned On Design Thinking And Software Development What Is Kubernetes What Is Pnpm Compare To Npmyarn Why Micro Frontend Why We Chose Our Tech Stack Accelerating Development With A Robust Frontend Solution Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves Writing Management Objectives In Smart Xpc Services On Macos App Using Swift</description></item><item><title>DuckDB demo and showcase</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 23/11/2023 🎙・labs-stage Internal DuckDB has been an emerging OLAP database for analytical needs. Use cases for analytics usually use around 1GB-10GB of data, not enough to take advantage of the full potential of databases in data warehouses. The use case of analyzing data in small chunks is enough to pop up startups such as MotherDuck.
Agenda: DuckDB is a great starting point for modern stacks that don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about scalability, but want to derive hard analytics from the data that they have.</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s our draft internal map/v0 for 🧊 $icy play, based on our current activities at this borderless software firm.
Context:
Back in 2018, when i envisioned doing something unconventional with our setup, we introduced 💎 $dfg.
It came with a dream that everyone on the team can help build next generation software, stay cool making money and own something. I planned to step down and give more ownership to those who actually implement our projects by gradually distributing $dfg to our grind chads.</description></item><item><title>How R&amp;D contributes to Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</guid><description>Our organization values the research and development (R&amp;amp;D) efforts of our team members and aims to incorporate these contributions into performance reviews. It&amp;rsquo;s important that individual R&amp;amp;D activities not only pursue personal growth but also align with our team and organizational objectives.
Key Assessment Factors For R&amp;amp;D activities, there are a few factors will contribute to your performance:
Alignment with Team Objectives: Your research should be aligned with topics identified as crucial for the future growth and success of our team.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Journey</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</guid><description>Our process for evaluating and integrating technology is designed to be thorough yet efficient, ensuring we adopt only the most effective tools into our operations. It consists of four key stages: Assess, Trial, Adopt, and Hold.
Assess: is the initial state where a technology is being evaluated. The objective is to understand the potential and limitations of the technology before committing more resources. Trial: is where the technology is tested in projects.</description></item><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</guid><description>In a recent collaborative discussion between key members of the Labs and Consulting teams, we&amp;rsquo;ve made decisive strides in pinpointing key topics and potential projects for development. Each topic is paired with specific challenges to ensure we engage deeply with the technology, understanding its practical applications. The focal point for the coming month is WebAssembly (WASM), alongside a range of exciting use-cases we plan to implement and demonstrate.
Our discussions have led to the identification of several intriguing topics, each with its own set of challenges.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Newsletter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Community Earn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</guid><description>The Dwarves bounty program is the means through which both company peeps and the community can contribute to our daily activities. This includes tasks like building internal tools, engaging in new technology research and development, or sharing knowledge session.
→ Apply for research team: open ticket in our Discord
→ To contribute: open ticket in our Discord and give @hnh a ping
Title 💰 Bounty Status PIC Function $icy withdrawal 🧊 120 Doing minhlq 🛠️ Tooling Rework Fortress Command 🧊 100 Open - 🛠️ Tooling $icy utility commands 🧊 50 Doing bienvh, phucld 🛠️ Tooling $icy store 🧊 100 Open minhlq 🛠️ Tooling $icy staking 🧊 350 Open phucld, minhlq, nam, bienvh 🛠️ Tooling Fortress Shanky Data 🧊 120 Open nam 🛠️ Tooling</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</guid><description/></item><item><title>monitoring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>nda</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>release</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aarrr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</guid><description>AARRR framework We use the AARRR framework to measure and optimize every phase of a product by optimizing it through the insane focus on one metric at a time.
What is AARRR framework? The AARRR framework consists of five phases a customer goes through in order to achieve growth and each phase has its own set of metrics to focus on. AARRR stands for Acquisition, Activation, Retention, Referral, and Revenue.</description></item><item><title>business-playbook-outline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</guid><description> BUSINESS PLAYBOOK Table of Contents
Introduction Who we are The Team Team chart Team members Portfolio Achievements Vision &amp;amp; mission
Strategy
Operating Process
Diagram Process workflows Sales Partnership process Commission model/tier Payment timeline FAQ</description></item><item><title>collaboration-guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</guid><description>Collaboration Guideline Guidelines for project collaboration between DF and Clients.
Tools Project management &amp;amp; communication: Basecamp (invited as Client) Sprint planning &amp;amp; tracking: Jira/Basecamp Meeting: Google Meet Source control platform: Github/Gitlab (self-hosted) Design: Figma/Sketch Schedule Project kick-off meeting: 1 session Sprint length: 1 week/2 weeks Sprint planning meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint review &amp;amp; retrospective meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint daily standup meetings (can as well be done via communication channel or Basecamp’s check-ins) Project/team feedback meeting (with Account Manager): 1 per week or 1 every 2 weeks Meeting notes for Sprint planning and Sprint retrospective will be sent within 30 minutes after meeting.</description></item><item><title>design-sprint</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</guid><description>Design Sprint What is the design sprint? The sprint is a four-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping and testing ideas with customers.
Design sprint mostly applied to the Exploration phase.
Friday is usually Education event or Lab projects at Dwarves Design, learning and continuous professional and personal development are in the core of our DNA. No one wants to settle, everyone wants to take the next step forward.</description></item><item><title>df-workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</guid><description>Monday:
Sprint Planning
End-of-day (EOD) check-in message
Tuesday:
EOD check-in message
Wednesday:
Sprint review message
EOD check-in message
Thursday:
EOD check-in message
Performance review (Account Manager, Team Lead, Project Owner, every 2 weeks)
Friday:
Investment time/Tech Radar
Sprint Review
Retrospective</description></item><item><title>fbsc</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</guid><description>Budget We do need to know clients&amp;rsquo; budgets. This is often uncomfortable for them but their budget helps determines what scope is possible. It saves time. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know their budget, we discuss different options.
We talk about breaking product rollout into stages and try to improve the product&amp;rsquo;s chances of success at each stage by:
Focusing on a small subset of features. Designing a valuable user experience. Developing a meaningful relationship with users.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</guid><description>TRAINING COURSE: HOW TO WORK WITH CLIENT What skills that an engineer should have in order to work with client effectively?
Strong technical skills: includes Basics of testing: Unit, Integration, System Software testing and debugging Attention to details
Communication skills: good English skills (both written and verbal)
-&amp;gt; require somewhere Intermediate - Upper Intermediate level
Problem solving and logical thinking
Work planning
Teamwork
Project Management
Consistency in delivering work result</description></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</guid><description>Lean Canvas Lean Canvas is an adaptation of Business Model Canvas by Alexander Osterwalder which Ash Maurya created in the Lean Startup spirit (Fast, Concise and Effective startup). Lean Canvas promises an actionable and entrepreneur-focused business plan. It focuses on problems, solutions, key metrics, and competitive advantages.
1. Problem What is the crucial problem faced by the product’s consumers? Capture their central frustration. The best way to describe the problem is in terms of the jobs customers need to do, what they are ultimately trying to achieve and what is the pain or frustration they currently feel.</description></item><item><title>prototype</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</guid><description>Low-fidelity prototype: UI Design Research 1. Understand prospect Understanding stakeholder, company, business model, goals and challenges of the product in order to set mindset, define style, color palette, and typography, iconography, illustration, and photography.
2. Define product Style Based on the target user and product’s requirement, we define layout style. Make references from Dribbble, Behance and other showcase sites to catch up with the current design trends.
Color Define primary and secondary based on the logo and branding of the product.</description></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</guid><description>GENERAL QUESTIONS FOR SERVICE FEEDBACKS Engineer performances
a. Communication
How did the engineer interact with your team? How was the communication between the engineer and your team? Was our engineer proactive in communicating with you? Did our engineer ask lots of questions? On which aspect our engineer should improve to provide better communication? b. Work ethic, delivery
Have our engineers “coming to work” on time? Have you ever had to wait too long to get a response from our engineer?</description></item><item><title>UI</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UX</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</guid><description>UX Research Framework 1. Gather Data In the first phase, we focus on gathering as much valuable data as humanly possible. It’s time for open-question asking, non-judgmental listening, and meticulous note-taking.
Stakeholder Interview In order to create successful products as a designer, it’s crucial to discover how the stakeholders think - what is the vision for the product (from each of the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; perspectives), and how can these be amalgamated?</description></item><item><title>wireframe</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</guid><description>Wireframe: Workflow Design Created on scraps of paper, a whiteboard, or in a software program, serve to establish relationships between elements in a project such as navigation, imagery, and calls to action.
Often, a wireframe has 3 core goals:
To show the content and functionality of the pages before any further designs. To help designers communicate with clients about the design concept. To establish the information hierarchy of the site.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t edit this file Well, actually you can actually edit this file. It won&amp;rsquo;t actually do much since this is a placeholder to avoid a weird bug when we deploy our site.
We can only travel on the paved road in the forest of bugs :monkas:</description></item><item><title>Index</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation 💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg $icy in 2024 $icy Salary Advance $icy staking $icy store $icy utility commands $icy withdrawal 2018 Wrapping Up 2020 In A Flashback 2021 Dwarves In Review 2021 July Updates 2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Quick Intro To Webassembly A Tips Of Hiring Dont A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google aarrr Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell About Devops Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Account Adapt Cucumber As A Bdd For Wego Add Type Safe Client Server Support For Next Boilerplate Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform Adoption Of Pnpm Adoption Of Pnpm Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support Adversarial Prompting Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool An Alternative To Tm An Engineering Story Map For Llms An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate Ant Design Apache Kafka Apache Spark Applied Security Basis Apply Blue Green Deployment To Mochi Apply Monorepos To Repit To Resolve The Problem Of Consistency Apply Page Object Model Structure To Aharooms Apply Page Object Model Structure To Artzy Apply Page Object Model Structure To Basehq Apply Page Object Model Structure To Sci Apply Page Object Model Structure To Wego Applying Mock Service Worker Msw For Seamless Web Development Applying MPC for authentication for web3 Console Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem Architecture Decision Record Are We Really Engineers Are You Helping Argocd Asking As A Junior Astro Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services Avoid Burn Out Backend For Call Requests To Binance And Get Data From Multiple Platforms Backstage Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup Beyond The Title Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App Blockchain For Designers Blocking Distraction Blue Green Deployment Brainery Blue Green Deployment Brainery Progressive Delivery Brainery Validation With Zod Bric A Brac Browserstack Build A Passcode View With Swift Build An Assistant On The Terminal Build Automation For Sci Build Your Chatbot With Open Source Large Language Models Building A Solid High Performing Team Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage Building Reliable Apps Sentry And Distributed Tracing For Effective Monitoring Bunk License Check business-playbook-outline Carbon Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session Careers Careers Case Study From Multiple Repo To Monorepo At Nghe Nhan Case Study How Blue Green Deployment Help Mochi Challenge Faced When Researching Rlhf With Open Assistant Chatgpt Assistance Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue Chromatic Chunking Strategies To Overcome Context Limitation In Llm Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience Clickhouse Cloudflare Workers Codecept Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas collaboration-guideline Commitlint Common Design Patterns In Golang Part 1 Community Bounty Community Earn Community Earn Competency Mapping Conduct A Meeting Configure The Company Email Connecting Vim With Golang Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating Constructive Feedback Continuous Translation Copilot Cost Of React Native Create Api Service For Urbox To Sync Orders From 3rd Parties And Manage Shipment Create Backend Monorepo To Share Code And Manage Multiple Services In One Repo Create Circular Text Using Swiftui Create Working Devcontainer For Go Api Create Working Devcontainer For Nextjs Boilerplate Cucumber Cypress Daemons And Services Programming Guide Dapr Data Analyst In Retail Trading Database Designs For Multilingual Apps Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab Dealing With Long Term Memory Of Chatbot December All Hands Meeting Definition Of Done Delegate Work Not Responsibility Delegation And Believe It Will Work Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection) Demo: Magic Links Demo: QR Code based Login Deno Design Better Mobile Application Design Resourcestools Design System Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup Design Tips Tricks Design Workflow design-sprint Detox Devcontainers Develop Develop Codecept To Integrate With Fortress Develop Sdk Integration Demo For Sajari Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions Devpod Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao df-workflow Diagnosing And Resolving Performance Issues With Pprof And Trace In Go Different Ways To Test React Application Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process Discord Roles Docker Microcontainers Docker Registry Domain Glossary Domain Insight Research Framework Dora Metrics Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui Duckdb DuckDB demo and showcase Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022 Dwarves Memo Dwarves Newsletter Dwarves Of 2021 Dwarves Of The Year 2022 Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03 Dwarves Ventures Fund 0 Dwarves Ventures Fund 1 Earthly Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Effective Meeting Elixir Elixir Umbrella Project Embracing Go 1210s Slog A Unified Logging Interface With Benchmarks Against Zerolog And Zap Erlang Error Handling And Failure Management In A Go System Error Logging Convention Eslint Estimation Guidelines Estimation In Agile Event Sourcing Excalidraw Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models Exploring Resumable Server Side Rendering With Qwik Expo Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation fbsc Fe 23 Training Type Safe Client Server Federated Byzantine Figma Finite State Machine First Introduced Use Of Duckdb In Consolelabs Logconsoleso Fixed Budget Scope Controlled Focus On Software Delivery Formal Verification Fortress Mma Score Fortress Shanky Data Forward Engineering August 2023 Forward Engineering June 2023 Forward Engineering March 2023 Forward Engineering May 2023 Forward Engineering Year 2022 Foundation Model From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo Fullstack Tracing Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress Gestalt Principle Gestalt Principles In Ui Design Getting Started With Webflow Git Commit Message Convention Gitflow Pull Request Github Actions Go Concurrency Go In Software Engineering Go The Extra Mile Go Training 2023 From Basic To Advanced Golang Good Design Understanding Grafana Graylog Grid And Layout Growth Is Our Universal Language Happy 2023 Headless Ui Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg Hiring Approach Hiring For Operations Team Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs Hoppscotch How A Design System Work How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi How People Matter Should Work How R&amp;amp;D contributes to Performance Review How We Contribute To Homebrew How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt How We Setup Cicd how-to-work-with-clients how-to-work-with-clients I18n Frontend Guideline IA Implement a rust game through WASM Implementing a game server on Rust Infinite Image Gallery With R3f An Approach Integrate Playwright To Run E2e Test With Fortress Integrate Playwright X Codecept With Discord Integrate Zod To Nextjs Boilerplate Introduce To Dwarves Memo Introduction To Software Craftsmanship Ipfs Istio January Updates Jotai K6 K9s Kaniko Knowledge Journey Konvoy X Dwarves Kotlin Kubernetes Helm 101 Kubeseal Sops Labs - New Member Onboarding Labs - Topic proposal &amp;amp; progress tracking Labs - Who we are Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update) Labs Team Labs Team Labs Weekly Catchup #1 Labs x Consulting Workflow Ladle Langchain Large Language Model Llm lean-canvas lean-canvas Learn Typescript As A Mandatory To Develop Reapit Foundation Lessons Learned Building An Llm Chatbot A Case Study Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Micro Frontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Microfrontend Implementation Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects Level Up Your Testing Game Harnessing Gomock For Unbeatable Unit Testing In Go Life at Dwarves Life At Dwarves Software Design Group Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves Live View Llm 101 Enhance Developer Productivity Llm Query Caching Llms Accuracy Self Refinement Loki Looking Back 2019 Make Remote Working Works Makefile Making Decision As A Team Member Managing Dataflow And Sql Database With Concurrency Control May 2022 All Hands Meeting Mbti Type Estj Mbti Type Intj Mbti Type Istj Mbti Type Istp Mdx Document For Memo Blue Green Deployment Memo React Native New Architecture Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq Micro Frontend Micro Frontends Microservices For Frontend Development Migrate Aharooms Pms To Typescript Migrate Headlessui To Radixui Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Fortress Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Nextjs Boilerplate Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In Nghe Nhan Droppii Migrate Yarn To Pnpm In React Toolkit monitoring Monorepo Msw N6n nda Nestjs Netlify Newrelic Nextjs Nextjs Boilerplate Nghenhan Microservices Nodejs Nostrum note.</description></item></channel></rss>