<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in work on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Bounties</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</guid><description>The Dwarves bounty program is the means through which both company peeps and the community can contribute to our daily activities. This includes tasks like building internal tools, engaging in new technology research and development, or sharing knowledge session.
→ Apply for research team: open ticket in our Discord
→ To contribute: open ticket in our Discord and give @hnh a ping
Title 💰 Bounty Status PIC Function Move internal notes to note.</description></item><item><title>Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</guid><description>Industry
E-Commerce
Location
Vietnam and SEA
Business Context
Need for an advanced e-commerce platform to streamline drop shipping operations
Solution
Revamped and technologically advanced online system development by Dwarves Foundation
Outcome
Launch of Droppii for Business v3.0, providing a scalable, user-friendly platform for business clients and enhancing customer interaction
Our Service
Full-Stack Development / Agile Project Management
In brief Droppii, in collaboration with Dwarves Foundation, revamps its e-commerce platform, enhancing dropshipping operations with the launch of Droppii for Business v3.</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-december-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-december-2023/</guid><description>[Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In December, we launched our Consulting Team, released our finding on tech trends, and last but not least, got everyone ready to wrap up 2023.
Reporting tech signals - We stay ahead by monitoring high-potential trends in tech.</description></item><item><title>Market Report Dec 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/market-report-dec-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/market-report-dec-2023/</guid><description>Trends on our Radar Here are some of the few trends we are seeing across the industry, in our projects, as well as our community. This market report isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive, at least just yet, with certain trends not yet listed such as Blockchain, data management, DevEx, etc. We see a lot of promising trends and we hope that understanding what engineers and firms are becoming more passionate about that it will help us create a foundation of ideas and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #4</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 27/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our fourth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Broadway in elixir to handle million messages by @Hieu Using WebAuthn API to implement passkeys by @Vincent Labeling image using openAI vision and embedding flow by @Lap Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #4 - 27/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Consultant Growth Track</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</guid><description>While there is no fixed path in the consulting field, we do have a structured growth guidance for career development, skill enhancement, and professional advancement.
Tier 1: Associate Consultant What you do:
Participate in client engagements, assisting senior consultants Gain exposure to various projects and technologies Learn company methodologies, tools, and best practices Perform research, analysis, and contribute to project documentation Skills needed:
Expert technical skills Client needs and project requirements gathering Project management basics Communication and presentation skills Reward:</description></item><item><title>Consulting - How we work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-how-we-work/</guid><description>Our Approach: Collaborative Expertise Team of Specialists: we favor collective expertise, encouraging knowledge sharing and collaboration, to craft innovative solutions that exceed expectations. Innovative Mindset: we encourage out-of-the-box thinking, experimentation, and creative problem-solving Transparent Communication: we lay everything out on the open, fostering a collaborative environment that promotes trust, clarity, and alignment Because we function based on real life demands, we recommend at least the following appointments
Weekly note: written record consists of 3 main components; current project health &amp;amp; issues, potential project / deal, market signal report Monthly report: wins, losses &amp;amp; lessons learned collected from weekly notes Monthly planning / retro: conducted by Consulting team to reflect on our performance metrics, planning for the next period Monthly demo/showcase: team-wise event to show off what we built / learned Monthly calibration: a joint appointment between Consulting, Labs and Ops to review individual / team performance Information Flow</description></item><item><title>Consulting - Who should join us</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-who-should-join-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-who-should-join-us/</guid><description>Consulting teams consists of anyone who&amp;rsquo;s hungry for more than just coding; those who are curious about the trends, the market, who can introduce new projects / challenges, who care about providing sensible solutions, and who take great care of projects.
When assessing new members, we have a few qualities that we look for. Those qualities can be something that you have already possess, or can be something you are growing toward.</description></item><item><title>Consulting - Who We Are</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consulting-who-we-are/</guid><description>Who we are Dwarves Consulting is team of individuals who possess a combination of technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and strong communication abilities.
Our culture Ahead of the market: we continuously learn and discover about the market and technology so we can participate in new, cool challenges, strive for high-quality deliverables and maintaining high standards Tech to solve problems: first we understand the problems, we provide solutions before any hard coding Network matters: we welcome collaborations with everyone who has the same goals and believe as we do Main functions of Consulting team We monitor the market to stay informed about industry trends, advancements, emerging technologies, and market dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 20/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our third weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Rise on chatbot alternatives, LibreChat to use OpenAI and custom LLMs by @Tom Bypass reCaptcha using self-hosted AI model by @Toan Shared query processing through DuckDB WASM by @Tom Build desktop app with Tauri by @Vy Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #3 - 20/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Business Development</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/business-development/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Business Development talents to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Culture Handbook</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/culture-handbook/</guid><description>Towards growth Keep learning and growing. We started this team out of software practice advancement.
The continuous study lays the foundation for the future growth. Just like software, knowledge must evolve and be useful. We collect the lesson learned and input into our team knowledge base.
Purpose-built Everything we do comes with the purpose behind. Good software is software that works and provide actual value. Effort is count when it&amp;rsquo;s placed on things that matter.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Community</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community/</guid><description>Dwarves Community is melting pot for software engineers, thinkers, learners and techies who are to explore, learn and master the latest advancements in technology. Technology is moving at the speed of light, and we want to stay at the forefront. Background or experience doesn’t matter to us, we are more keen on the mindset of always being curious about what’s next in tech, collaborating for the better, learning profusely and sharing unconditionally.</description></item><item><title>Executive Assistant</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/executive-assistant/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for an Executive Assistant to join Dwarves and work remotely. We are seeking a highly organized, proactive, and experienced Executive Assistant to provide support to our senior executives. The ideal candidates will be responsible for identifying new business opportunities, fostering strong client relationships, and driving growth by promoting our services to potential clients globally.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>Technical Recruiter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/technical-recruiter/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a Technical Recruiter to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will play a pivotal role in sourcing, attracting, and hiring top-tier talents and take care of our team members&amp;rsquo; growth.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item><item><title>The Manifesto</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</guid><description>Aim for Quality Quality exists in every piece of work. We thrive to deliver the best because we can.
Well-crafted Software
We humbly imply our expertise and experience into well-crafted software. We take pride in high quality products and perfect solution. We can&amp;rsquo;t stand preventable defects. Quality Pays
Quality outweighs everything else. Once it isn&amp;rsquo;t managed, the entire project goes down as well. Crafting solid software requires time, efforts, disciplines and proper methods.</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 13/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>Consulting Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/</guid><description>Who we are Dwarves Consulting is team of individuals who possess a combination of technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and strong communication abilities.
Our culture Ahead of the market: we continuously learn and discover about the market and technology so we can participate in new, cool challenges, strive for high-quality deliverables and maintaining high standards Tech to solve problems: first we understand the problems, we provide solutions before any hard coding Network matters: we welcome collaborations with everyone who has the same goals and believe as we do How we work Our working environment is dynamic.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/events/</guid><description>This page holds a collection of both our internal and external events, including the things we do with the Labs team, Consulting team, Operations, team, and the community.
Events Labs Weekly Catchup 4 Labs Weekly Catchup 3 Labs Weekly Catchup 2 Labs Weekly Catchup 1 DuckDB demo and showcase</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This note repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges, new tech, hiring, bounty, etc.</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/home/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This note repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges, new tech, hiring, bounty, etc.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/</guid><description>This is our newsletter page, where we keep you up to date with latest industry news and updates, valuable content from our engineers at Dwarves, and a picture of how we operate with our engineers and community.
whats-new-december-2023 whats-new-november-2023 whats-new-october-2023</description></item><item><title>React Native Developer</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for talented developer with experience in React Native to join Dwarves and work remotely, on a fast-growing US startup.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
🤝 As an engineer at Dwarves, you will be working closely with a team of talented, kind people and working directly with our clients. There is a lot of freedom to contribute to the quality of the project and improve, or prove yourself.</description></item><item><title>Estimation Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</guid><description>When we conduct an estimation, it is recommended to abandon the transitional “exact hours” assessment method, instead, use the story point based on the Fibonacci number (1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21…). The number expresses an estimation of the overall effort required to fully implement a backlog item or any piece of work.
Below’s an example of an estimation table based on the matrix of complexity, uncertainty, and effort:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Last November, we kicked off the Labs team, introduced Salary Advance for the Dwarves, upgraded note.d.foundation, supported Golang meetup, and demonstrated craftsmanship through various case studies and demos.</description></item><item><title>Careers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</guid><description>When we put Foundation in our name, we mean it. We want to put in place a team of go-getters who solve real-world problems, build big platforms, and spread goodwill across communities.
Join us. Let&amp;rsquo;s create the next big things together. At Dwarves, you will be working with an experienced, talented team who loves technology and knows how to use technology to better life on a global level.
Apply: Business Development Executive Assistant Technical Recruiter How we work at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life at Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/life-at-dwarves/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re like-minded teammates who pursue ambitious goals with tech culture and codes of conduct.
Build a place we love to work at We build this company like we build a product. There are roadmaps for growth; there are phases; there are iterations. There might also be bugs, places where the company crashes because of bad organizational design, or cultural oversights.
That means we advocate for changes. Changes always start with making our people better.</description></item><item><title>Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation Team&amp;rsquo;s guide on our project delivery process. This post will serve as your go-to resource for understanding our weekly, bi-weekly, and monthly activities, ensuring that we stay on track and excel in our deliveries.
Weekly Activities 1. Weekly Points/Effort Report Every Friday
Action: Fill out the weekly points/effort report. Link: Weekly Report Spreadsheet. Deadline for Data Sync: Data is sync by EOD next Tuesday. Outcome: Weekly leaderboard on delivery.</description></item><item><title>Labs - Who we are</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-who-we-are/</guid><description>At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies. We are a diverse group of individuals, each with unique backgrounds and personalities, but our common ground lies in our dedication to exploring and understanding emerging technologies. Our goal is to investigate and learn about advancements that have the potential to enhance our lives and contribute to a better future.
Our beliefs Our culture at Labs is a confluence of diverse backgrounds, personalities, and perspectives, yet united by core beliefs:</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</guid><description>Our newest memos This is where we keep our internal updates, learned and curated by our engineers.
Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions: Droppii, in collaboration with Dwarves Foundation, revamps its e-commerce platform, enhancing dropshipping operations with the launch of Droppii for Business v3.0. This strategic partnership focuses on improving user experience and operational efficiency through a new dashboard, CMS, and ERP system. The initiative marks a significant step in Droppii&amp;rsquo;s growth in the competitive e-commerce sector, showcasing the impact of technical and strategic collaboration.</description></item><item><title>DuckDB demo and showcase</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 23/11/2023 🎙・labs-stage Internal DuckDB has been an emerging OLAP database for analytical needs. Use cases for analytics usually use around 1GB-10GB of data, not enough to take advantage of the full potential of databases in data warehouses. The use case of analyzing data in small chunks is enough to pop up startups such as MotherDuck.
Agenda: DuckDB is a great starting point for modern stacks that don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about scalability, but want to derive hard analytics from the data that they have.</description></item><item><title>💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s our draft internal map/v0 for 🧊 $icy play, based on our current activities at this borderless software firm.
Context:
Back in 2018, when i envisioned doing something unconventional with our setup, we introduced 💎 $dfg.
It came with a dream that everyone on the team can help build next generation software, stay cool making money and own something. I planned to step down and give more ownership to those who actually implement our projects by gradually distributing $dfg to our grind chads.</description></item><item><title>How R&amp;D contributes to Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</guid><description>Our organization values the research and development (R&amp;amp;D) efforts of our team members and aims to incorporate these contributions into performance reviews. It&amp;rsquo;s important that individual R&amp;amp;D activities not only pursue personal growth but also align with our team and organizational objectives.
Key Assessment Factors For R&amp;amp;D activities, there are a few factors will contribute to your performance:
Alignment with Team Objectives: Your research should be aligned with topics identified as crucial for the future growth and success of our team.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Journey</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/knowledge-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/knowledge-journey/</guid><description>Our process for evaluating and integrating technology is designed to be thorough yet efficient, ensuring we adopt only the most effective tools into our operations. It consists of four key stages: Assess, Trial, Adopt, and Hold.
Assess: is the initial state where a technology is being evaluated. The objective is to understand the potential and limitations of the technology before committing more resources. Trial: is where the technology is tested in projects.</description></item><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</guid><description>In a recent collaborative discussion between key members of the Labs and Consulting teams, we&amp;rsquo;ve made decisive strides in pinpointing key topics and potential projects for development. Each topic is paired with specific challenges to ensure we engage deeply with the technology, understanding its practical applications. The focal point for the coming month is WebAssembly (WASM), alongside a range of exciting use-cases we plan to implement and demonstrate.
Our discussions have led to the identification of several intriguing topics, each with its own set of challenges.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</guid><description/></item><item><title>monitoring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>nda</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>release</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aarrr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</guid><description>AARRR framework We use the AARRR framework to measure and optimize every phase of a product by optimizing it through the insane focus on one metric at a time.
What is AARRR framework? The AARRR framework consists of five phases a customer goes through in order to achieve growth and each phase has its own set of metrics to focus on. AARRR stands for Acquisition, Activation, Retention, Referral, and Revenue.</description></item><item><title>business-playbook-outline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</guid><description> BUSINESS PLAYBOOK Table of Contents
Introduction Who we are The Team Team chart Team members Portfolio Achievements Vision &amp;amp; mission
Strategy
Operating Process
Diagram Process workflows Sales Partnership process Commission model/tier Payment timeline FAQ</description></item><item><title>collaboration-guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</guid><description>Collaboration Guideline Guidelines for project collaboration between DF and Clients.
Tools Project management &amp;amp; communication: Basecamp (invited as Client) Sprint planning &amp;amp; tracking: Jira/Basecamp Meeting: Google Meet Source control platform: Github/Gitlab (self-hosted) Design: Figma/Sketch Schedule Project kick-off meeting: 1 session Sprint length: 1 week/2 weeks Sprint planning meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint review &amp;amp; retrospective meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint daily standup meetings (can as well be done via communication channel or Basecamp’s check-ins) Project/team feedback meeting (with Account Manager): 1 per week or 1 every 2 weeks Meeting notes for Sprint planning and Sprint retrospective will be sent within 30 minutes after meeting.</description></item><item><title>design-sprint</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</guid><description>Design Sprint What is the design sprint? The sprint is a four-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping and testing ideas with customers.
Design sprint mostly applied to the Exploration phase.
Friday is usually Education event or Lab projects at Dwarves Design, learning and continuous professional and personal development are in the core of our DNA. No one wants to settle, everyone wants to take the next step forward.</description></item><item><title>df-workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</guid><description>Monday:
Sprint Planning
End-of-day (EOD) check-in message
Tuesday:
EOD check-in message
Wednesday:
Sprint review message
EOD check-in message
Thursday:
EOD check-in message
Performance review (Account Manager, Team Lead, Project Owner, every 2 weeks)
Friday:
Investment time/Tech Radar
Sprint Review
Retrospective</description></item><item><title>fbsc</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</guid><description>Budget We do need to know clients&amp;rsquo; budgets. This is often uncomfortable for them but their budget helps determines what scope is possible. It saves time. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know their budget, we discuss different options.
We talk about breaking product rollout into stages and try to improve the product&amp;rsquo;s chances of success at each stage by:
Focusing on a small subset of features. Designing a valuable user experience. Developing a meaningful relationship with users.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</guid><description>TRAINING COURSE: HOW TO WORK WITH CLIENT What skills that an engineer should have in order to work with client effectively?
Strong technical skills: includes Basics of testing: Unit, Integration, System Software testing and debugging Attention to details
Communication skills: good English skills (both written and verbal)
-&amp;gt; require somewhere Intermediate - Upper Intermediate level
Problem solving and logical thinking
Work planning
Teamwork
Project Management
Consistency in delivering work result</description></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</guid><description>Lean Canvas Lean Canvas is an adaptation of Business Model Canvas by Alexander Osterwalder which Ash Maurya created in the Lean Startup spirit (Fast, Concise and Effective startup). Lean Canvas promises an actionable and entrepreneur-focused business plan. It focuses on problems, solutions, key metrics, and competitive advantages.
1. Problem What is the crucial problem faced by the product’s consumers? Capture their central frustration. The best way to describe the problem is in terms of the jobs customers need to do, what they are ultimately trying to achieve and what is the pain or frustration they currently feel.</description></item><item><title>prototype</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</guid><description>Low-fidelity prototype: UI Design Research 1. Understand prospect Understanding stakeholder, company, business model, goals and challenges of the product in order to set mindset, define style, color palette, and typography, iconography, illustration, and photography.
2. Define product Style Based on the target user and product’s requirement, we define layout style. Make references from Dribbble, Behance and other showcase sites to catch up with the current design trends.
Color Define primary and secondary based on the logo and branding of the product.</description></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</guid><description>GENERAL QUESTIONS FOR SERVICE FEEDBACKS Engineer performances
a. Communication
How did the engineer interact with your team? How was the communication between the engineer and your team? Was our engineer proactive in communicating with you? Did our engineer ask lots of questions? On which aspect our engineer should improve to provide better communication? b. Work ethic, delivery
Have our engineers “coming to work” on time? Have you ever had to wait too long to get a response from our engineer?</description></item><item><title>UI</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UX</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</guid><description>UX Research Framework 1. Gather Data In the first phase, we focus on gathering as much valuable data as humanly possible. It’s time for open-question asking, non-judgmental listening, and meticulous note-taking.
Stakeholder Interview In order to create successful products as a designer, it’s crucial to discover how the stakeholders think - what is the vision for the product (from each of the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; perspectives), and how can these be amalgamated?</description></item><item><title>wireframe</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</guid><description>Wireframe: Workflow Design Created on scraps of paper, a whiteboard, or in a software program, serve to establish relationships between elements in a project such as navigation, imagery, and calls to action.
Often, a wireframe has 3 core goals:
To show the content and functionality of the pages before any further designs. To help designers communicate with clients about the design concept. To establish the information hierarchy of the site.</description></item><item><title>Index</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation 💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg $icy in 2024 $icy Salary Advance $icy staking $icy store $icy utility commands $icy withdrawal 2018 Wrapping Up 2020 In A Flashback 2021 Dwarves In Review 2021 July Updates 2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform A Quick Intro To Webassembly A Tips Of Hiring Dont A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google aarrr Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell About Devops Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit Account Adapt Cucumber As A Bdd For Wego Add Type Safe Client Server Support For Next Boilerplate Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform Adoption Of Pnpm Adoption Of Pnpm Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support Adversarial Prompting Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool An Alternative To Tm An Engineering Story Map For Llms An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate Ant Design Apache Kafka Apache Spark Applied Security Basis Apply Blue Green Deployment To Mochi Apply Monorepos To Repit To Resolve The Problem Of Consistency Apply Page Object Model Structure To Aharooms Apply Page Object Model Structure To Artzy Apply Page Object Model Structure To Basehq Apply Page Object Model Structure To Sci Apply Page Object Model Structure To Wego Applying Mock Service Worker Msw For Seamless Web Development Applying MPC for authentication for web3 Console Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem Architecture Decision Record Archive Are We Really Engineers Are You Helping Argocd Asking As A Junior Astro Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services Avoid Burn Out Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust Backend For Call Requests To Binance And Get Data From Multiple Platforms Backstage Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup Beyond The Title Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App Blockchain For Designers Blocking Distraction Blue Green Deployment Brainery Blue Green Deployment Brainery Progressive Delivery Brainery Validation With Zod Bric A Brac Browserstack Build A Passcode View With Swift Build An Assistant On The Terminal Build Automation For Sci Build Your Chatbot With Open Source Large Language Models Building A Solid High Performing Team Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage Building Reliable Apps Sentry And Distributed Tracing For Effective Monitoring Bunk License Check Business Development business-playbook-outline Carbon Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session Careers Careers Case Study From Multiple Repo To Monorepo At Nghe Nhan Case Study How Blue Green Deployment Help Mochi Challenge Faced When Researching Rlhf With Open Assistant Chatgpt Assistance Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue Chromatic Chunking Strategies To Overcome Context Limitation In Llm Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience Clickhouse Cloudflare Workers Codecept Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas collaboration-guideline Commitlint Common Design Patterns In Golang Part 1 Community Bounty Competency Mapping Conduct A Meeting Configure The Company Email Connecting Vim With Golang Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating Constructive Feedback Consultant Growth Track Consulting - How we work Consulting - Who should join us Consulting - Who We Are Consulting Team Consulting Team Continuous Translation Copilot Cost Of React Native Create Api Service For Urbox To Sync Orders From 3rd Parties And Manage Shipment Create Backend Monorepo To Share Code And Manage Multiple Services In One Repo Create Circular Text Using Swiftui Create Working Devcontainer For Go Api Create Working Devcontainer For Nextjs Boilerplate Cucumber Culture Handbook Cypress Daemons And Services Programming Guide Dapr Data Analyst In Retail Trading Data processing and visual infographics (through DuckDB-WASM) Database Designs For Multilingual Apps Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab Dealing With Long Term Memory Of Chatbot December All Hands Meeting Definition Of Done Delegate Work Not Responsibility Delegation And Believe It Will Work Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection) Demo: Magic Links Demo: QR Code based Login Deno Design Better Mobile Application Design Resourcestools Design System Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup Design Tips Tricks Design Workflow design-sprint Detox Devcontainers Develop Develop Codecept To Integrate With Fortress Develop Sdk Integration Demo For Sajari Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions Devpod Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao df-workflow Diagnosing And Resolving Performance Issues With Pprof And Trace In Go Different Ways To Test React Application Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process Discord Roles Docker Microcontainers Docker Registry Domain Glossary Domain Insight Research Framework Dora Metrics Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions Duckdb DuckDB demo and showcase Dwarves Community Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022 Dwarves Memo Dwarves Memo Dwarves Of 2021 Dwarves Of The Year 2022 Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02 Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03 Dwarves Ventures Fund 0 Dwarves Ventures Fund 1 Earthly Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms Effective Meeting Elixir Elixir Umbrella Project Embracing Go 1210s Slog A Unified Logging Interface With Benchmarks Against Zerolog And Zap Erlang Error Handling And Failure Management In A Go System Error Logging Convention Eslint Estimation Guidelines Estimation In Agile Event Sourcing Events Events Excalidraw Executive Assistant Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models Exploring Resumable Server Side Rendering With Qwik Expo Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation fbsc Fe 23 Training Type Safe Client Server Federated Byzantine Figma Finite State Machine First Introduced Use Of Duckdb In Consolelabs Logconsoleso Fixed Budget Scope Controlled Focus On Software Delivery Formal Verification Fortress Mma Score Fortress Shanky Data Forward Engineering August 2023 Forward Engineering June 2023 Forward Engineering March 2023 Forward Engineering May 2023 Forward Engineering Year 2022 Foundation Model From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo Fullstack Tracing Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress Gestalt Principle Gestalt Principles In Ui Design Getting Started With Webflow Git Commit Message Convention Gitflow Pull Request Github Actions Go Concurrency Go In Software Engineering Go The Extra Mile Go Training 2023 From Basic To Advanced Golang Good Design Understanding Grafana Graylog Grid And Layout Growth Is Our Universal Language Happy 2023 Headless Ui Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg Hiring Approach Hiring For Operations Team Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs Home Home Hoppscotch How A Design System Work How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi How People Matter Should Work How R&amp;amp;D contributes to Performance Review How to submit a Bounty?</description></item></channel></rss>