<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in work on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tech Radar</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/radar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dwarves Earn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/</guid><description> Earn and Bounty Program Our earn and bounty program for all of the open-source work we do at Dwarves Foundation. A good portion of the earns and bounties help to improve quality-of-life for our community, creating bots and extensions for our messaging apps, and more serious work such as aggregating data from blockchains.
title bounty status ?trend command 60 ICY Open Tech radar status report 60 ICY Open Tech radar status report 60 ICY Open Fortress: API to show shanky data 120 ICY Open Fortress: MMA data 120 ICY Open A discord cmd to receive a link, and create a brainery fleeting note 60 ICY Open A webpage showing where the Dwarves from 80 ICY Open Consulting record webpage 80 ICY Open</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</guid><description> Dwarves Memo August Forward Engineering</description></item><item><title>WeAreHiring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/</guid><description>iOS Intern QA Growth Golang Frontend Apprentice Android where-we-work what-we-value what-we-stand-for making-a-career how-we-work how-we-hire benefits-and-perks WeAreHiring WeAreHiring Marketing Marketing Lead Engineering Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust Web Developer, React.js App Developer, Apple Platform QA Engineer, Automation QA Engineer, Manual Data Engineer AI/ML Engineer Engineering Manager Design UX Designer (Blockchain/Fintech) UX Designer (Productivity/Dev Tool) UI Designer Lead Designer Apprenticeship Training Program (1+ year exp. required)
Backend Engineer Web Developer Table of Content Dwarves: Team of craftsmen We believe the future is built, not discovered We get things done a bit differently Built with the purpose Engineering-driven culture Work where you feel best Win as a team Giving back Our masterpiece Products we ship Cutting-edge Tech Index Dwarves handbook Apprenticeship Program Knowledge exchange activities How to apply Dwarves: Team of craftsmen We are on the mission to empower innovations.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/invoice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-system/</guid><description/></item><item><title>monitoring</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>nda</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>release</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/engineering/repo-icon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/nda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aarrr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/aarrr/</guid><description>AARRR framework We use the AARRR framework to measure and optimize every phase of a product by optimizing it through the insane focus on one metric at a time.
What is AARRR framework? The AARRR framework consists of five phases a customer goes through in order to achieve growth and each phase has its own set of metrics to focus on. AARRR stands for Acquisition, Activation, Retention, Referral, and Revenue.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/android/</guid><description>Android Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN ANDROID DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Knowledge in Dart fundamentals and Flutter framework Passionate about programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Android Development in Java/Kotlin is a plus You own the Android platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Apprentice</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/apprentice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/apprentice/</guid><description>Apprenticeship Program About the program Apprenticeship is a six-month earn-and-learn training program; it&amp;rsquo;s a way to learn about being a professional software developer. Specifically, it is a way to learn to be like the most skilled software developers you can find. It involves seeking out good teachers and taking opportunities to learn by working alongside them.
Apprenticeship is designed for the individuals who
are looking for the zen way to ship quality software or haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out the clear path to a job in the tech industry or with non-traditional work and educational background to find full-time roles The program provides a real-world experience where you will</description></item><item><title>August Forward Engineering</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/august-forward-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/august-forward-engineering/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>benefits-and-perks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/benefits-and-perks/</guid><description>Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Since the majority of Dwarves Foundation employees work in Saigon, this section is written with that as the default. Some benefits don’t make sense in other countries. We will try our best to provide comparable benefits and perks as it makes sense, though.
Continuing Education Allowance You will always grow by learning and playing with new and cool technologies. From books to conferences, you’ll get a yearly budget for your individual learning and development goals.</description></item><item><title>business-playbook-outline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/business-playbook-outline/</guid><description> BUSINESS PLAYBOOK Table of Contents
Introduction Who we are The Team Team chart Team members Portfolio Achievements Vision &amp;amp; mission
Strategy
Operating Process
Diagram Process workflows Sales Partnership process Commission model/tier Payment timeline FAQ</description></item><item><title>collaboration-guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/collaboration-guideline/</guid><description>Collaboration Guideline Guidelines for project collaboration between DF and Clients.
Tools Project management &amp;amp; communication: Basecamp (invited as Client) Sprint planning &amp;amp; tracking: Jira/Basecamp Meeting: Google Meet Source control platform: Github/Gitlab (self-hosted) Design: Figma/Sketch Schedule Project kick-off meeting: 1 session Sprint length: 1 week/2 weeks Sprint planning meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint review &amp;amp; retrospective meeting: 1 per sprint Sprint daily standup meetings (can as well be done via communication channel or Basecamp’s check-ins) Project/team feedback meeting (with Account Manager): 1 per week or 1 every 2 weeks Meeting notes for Sprint planning and Sprint retrospective will be sent within 30 minutes after meeting.</description></item><item><title>design-sprint</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/design-sprint/</guid><description>Design Sprint What is the design sprint? The sprint is a four-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping and testing ideas with customers. Design sprint mostly applied to the Exploration phase. Friday is usually Education event or Lab projects at Dwarves Design, learning and continuous professional and personal development are in the core of our DNA. No one wants to settle, everyone wants to take the next step forward.</description></item><item><title>df-workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/df-workflow/</guid><description>Monday: Sprint Planning End-of-day (EOD) check-in message
Tuesday: EOD check-in message
Wednesday: Sprint review message EOD check-in message
Thursday: EOD check-in message Performance review (Account Manager, Team Lead, Project Owner, every 2 weeks)
Friday: Investment time/Tech Radar Sprint Review Retrospective</description></item><item><title>fbsc</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/fbsc/</guid><description>Budget We do need to know clients&amp;rsquo; budgets. This is often uncomfortable for them but their budget helps determines what scope is possible. It saves time. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know their budget, we discuss different options.
We talk about breaking product rollout into stages and try to improve the product&amp;rsquo;s chances of success at each stage by:
Focusing on a small subset of features. Designing a valuable user experience. Developing a meaningful relationship with users.</description></item><item><title>Frontend</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/frontend/</guid><description>Frontend Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A FRONTEND ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Passionate about coding and programming, innovation, and solving challenging problems Strong knowledge in JavaScript fundamentals Well versed in various browser technologies Your HTML/CSS have to be good enough to create world-class UI (hint: we don&amp;rsquo;t use float) Knowledge of techniques like BEM, CSS modules, inline styles, .</description></item><item><title>Golang</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/golang/</guid><description>Gopher WE ARE LOOKING FOR A GOPHER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Experience with Golang Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test and integration test Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>Growth</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/growth/</guid><description>Marketing We are open to a marketing position!
If you are looking for a tech-savvy company to contribute to and make your career, this may be your opportunity to put in your spirit and ideal setup.
Purpose Dwarves are a group of software engineers, designers, and innovation advocates. We are one of the most tech-savvy teams out there. We build this team together six years ago from a corner of Saigon and Toronto.</description></item><item><title>how-to-work-with-clients</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/how-to-work-with-clients/</guid><description>TRAINING COURSE: HOW TO WORK WITH CLIENT What skills that an engineer should have in order to work with client effectively?
Strong technical skills: includes Basics of testing: Unit, Integration, System Software testing and debugging Attention to details
Communication skills: good English skills (both written and verbal) -&amp;gt; require somewhere Intermediate - Upper Intermediate level
Problem solving and logical thinking
Work planning
Teamwork
Project Management
Consistency in delivering work result</description></item><item><title>how-we-hire</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-hire/</guid><description>How we hire Hiring means we need help. We only hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. We always look for long-term teammates that why we want to ensure the new hire is a value fit and culture fit.
Rounds Several Dwarves will talk to the candidates to walk them through 4 rounds
Pre-assessment: We evaluate the logic, English, and the personalities in non-interrupted 30 minutes online test.</description></item><item><title>how-we-work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/how-we-work/</guid><description>How we work We do Agile We build software. The way we see it is a collaboration between multiple people in the team with sufficient knowledge on the domain and clearly understand the project vision that they can quickly adapt to the changes in the market. We adopt the Agile philosophy at this level.
Also, based on that philosophy, we apply the Scrum framework, which we find out a good fit for us.</description></item><item><title>Intern</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/intern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/intern/</guid><description>The Program In 2018, we launched the first Summer Internship Program for students with or without Engineering background from top universities. The program was designed with the purpose to give an opportunity for candidates to experience the real world projects. No coffee runs here. We love watching talented people learn and explore their skills.
We strive to create a generation of new tech enthusiasts who possess the same DNA with us, to generate a solid groundwork and go along with the company’s triumph.</description></item><item><title>iOS</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/ios/</guid><description>iOS Developer WE ARE LOOKING FOR AN iOS DEVELOPER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements Same DNA A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile philosophy and Scrum framework Strong knowledge in Swift fundamentals and its framework Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Experience with Objective-C is a plus You own the iOS platform Job and the challenges Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Collaborate with Backend Engineers to build features and ship experiments Participate in design and code reviews Identify and communicate front-end best practices Benefits &amp;amp; Perks Healthcare We provide comprehensive medical and life insurance for our fulltime members.</description></item><item><title>lean-canvas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/lean-canvas/</guid><description>Lean Canvas Lean Canvas is an adaptation of Business Model Canvas by Alexander Osterwalder which Ash Maurya created in the Lean Startup spirit (Fast, Concise and Effective startup). Lean Canvas promises an actionable and entrepreneur-focused business plan. It focuses on problems, solutions, key metrics, and competitive advantages.
1. Problem What is the crucial problem faced by the product’s consumers? Capture their central frustration. The best way to describe the problem is in terms of the jobs customers need to do, what they are ultimately trying to achieve and what is the pain or frustration they currently feel.</description></item><item><title>making-a-career</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/making-a-career/</guid><description>Making a Career The average tenure of employees working at many technology companies today is shockingly low. At both Amazon, Google and other companies, it’s just around one year. At Dwarves Foundation, it’s just around three years as of late 2018. That’s something to be proud of, and something to ensure endures. When you work at Dwarves Foundation, it should be feasible to think about this as the place for making a life-long career.</description></item><item><title>prototype</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/prototype/</guid><description>Low-fidelity prototype: UI Design Research 1. Understand prospect Understanding stakeholder, company, business model, goals and challenges of the product in order to set mindset, define style, color palette, and typography, iconography, illustration, and photography.
2. Define product Style Based on the target user and product’s requirement, we define layout style. Make references from Dribbble, Behance and other showcase sites to catch up with the current design trends.
Color Define primary and secondary based on the logo and branding of the product.</description></item><item><title>QA</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/qa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/qa/</guid><description>QA Engineer WE ARE LOOKING FOR A QA ENGINEER TO JOIN OUR TEAM IN SAIGON. Join a team of developers and designers dedicated to creating products people love to use
About Us Found in 2014, Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We stand for the craftsmanship in software development. Our woodland is a sum of great technology, engineering culture, and smart people. The numbers speak for themselves:
5 years in the market 40 talented members 10 common team size per deployments 3 Vietnam Development Communities Influenced Requirements CAREFULNESS is our first prerequisite A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp.</description></item><item><title>service-feedbacks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/business/service-feedbacks/</guid><description>GENERAL QUESTIONS FOR SERVICE FEEDBACKS Engineer performances a. Communication
How did the engineer interact with your team? How was the communication between the engineer and your team? Was our engineer proactive in communicating with you? Did our engineer ask lots of questions? On which aspect our engineer should improve to provide better communication? b. Work ethic, delivery
Have our engineers “coming to work” on time? Have you ever had to wait too long to get a response from our engineer?</description></item><item><title>UI</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ui/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UX</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/ux/</guid><description>UX Research Framework 1. Gather Data In the first phase, we focus on gathering as much valuable data as humanly possible. It’s time for open-question asking, non-judgmental listening, and meticulous note-taking.
Stakeholder Interview In order to create successful products as a designer, it’s crucial to discover how the stakeholders think - what is the vision for the product (from each of the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; perspectives), and how can these be amalgamated?</description></item><item><title>what-we-stand-for</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-stand-for/</guid><description>What we stand for Empower Innovation with Software Craftsmanship Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.
Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time.</description></item><item><title>what-we-value</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/what-we-value/</guid><description>What we value Before anything else, values come first. The value is important to us. They are what we proud of. They help guide us when we are facing a difficult decision. They will be the things you like about what we do at Dwarves Foundation and how we do it.
Our core values guide our strategies and individual actions so that we create a company whose character is as radical as our work.</description></item><item><title>where-we-work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/additional-info/where-we-work/</guid><description>Where we work Office The Dwarves HQ is in Saigon, Vietnam. Thirty people and two cats have desk space in the Saigon office, but those people also work from home regularly. We expand the office space when the old one is full and people want the new office. Anyone is welcome to visit Saigon and work from the office at any time.
From home A few people at Dwarves Foundation are based in other countries and they work from home most of the time.</description></item><item><title>wireframe</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/playbook/design/wireframe/</guid><description>Wireframe: Workflow Design Created on scraps of paper, a whiteboard, or in a software program, serve to establish relationships between elements in a project such as navigation, imagery, and calls to action. Often, a wireframe has 3 core goals:
To show the content and functionality of the pages before any further designs. To help designers communicate with clients about the design concept. To establish the information hierarchy of the site.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t edit this file Well, actually you can actually edit this file. It won&amp;rsquo;t actually do much since this is a placeholder to avoid a weird bug when we deploy our site.
We can only travel on the paved road in the forest of bugs :monkas:</description></item><item><title>Index</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/site-index/</guid><description> Dwarves Foundation ?trend command A discord cmd to receive a link, and create a brainery fleeting note A discord cmd to summary article, using ChatGPT A webpage showing where the Dwarves from aarrr Add new discord command to publish new brainery post Android Apprentice August Forward Engineering benefits-and-perks Brainery metrics report business-playbook-outline Centralize Dwarves Calendar Chatbot: Adversarial prompts - politics, weapons, etc Chatbot: LLM accuracy with RLHF Chatbot: memory (few shot) Chatbot: prompt size, context (zero shot) collaboration-guideline Company Signature Company Social Graph Consulting record webpage Design system for layer 2 using ZK rollup design-sprint df-workflow Dwarves Earn Dwarves Memo Economic calendar Engagement Log fbsc Feature toggle Financial Literacy outline: Phổ cập Kiến thức Tài chính Fortress: API to show shanky data Fortress: MMA data Frontend Golang Growth how-to-work-with-clients how-to-work-with-clients how-we-hire how-we-work Hunger Game - Submit 2022 IA Integrate RSS feeds to chapter discord channels Integrate ts-reset to nextjs boilerplate Intern iOS lean-canvas lean-canvas Locale on Web, Mobile making-a-career monitoring Monorepo deployment flow with Vercel nda Open source Enigma checksum Optimize Query Database 500M records, filter multiple tables Project Weekly Changelog Tooling prototype QA React Server Componen release Rework Discord Role Rework Dwarves Email Domain service-feedbacks service-feedbacks Tech radar status report Tech radar status report Treasure Hunt - Submit 2022 UI Upgrade nextjs-boilerplate to Nextjs 13 Use Zod to validate schema in nextjs-boilerplate UX wagmi website, fork xkcd, with crm for img uploading wagmi website, fork xkcd, with crm for img uploading WeAreHiring what-we-stand-for what-we-value where-we-work wireframe</description></item></channel></rss>