<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Framework on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/framework/</link><description>Recent content in Framework on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</guid><description>Selecting the ideal JavaScript framework can be a daunting task, particularly when faced with an abundance of highly resourceful and capable options. To make an informed decision that caters to specific project requirements, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to possess a deep understanding of various critical aspects. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll shed light on some of these essential points by conducting a comprehensive comparison of Angular, React, and Vue.
We’ve had our fair share of decision fatigue keeping up with new frameworks and choosing the right ones for the job.</description></item><item><title>Cost Of React Native</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cost-of-react-native/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cost-of-react-native/</guid><description>React Native is a popular cross-platform app development framework that allows developers to build mobile apps for both iOS and Android platforms using a single codebase. It has gained popularity in recent years due to its ability to provide a native-like experience while reducing development time and cost.
Introduction At Dwarves, React Native has been on our radar and we use it in some of our projects. Lately, we have been investigating cost-benefits of using it and making light of some concerns we should be aware of.</description></item><item><title>Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</guid><description>Accelerate Project Initiation with Advanced NextJS-Boilerplate &amp;amp; React-Toolkit In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world of software development, project initiation can often be a challenging and time-consuming process, with teams facing issues such as inconsistent code quality, slow setup times, and suboptimal workflows. To address these obstacles and streamline the project initiation process, we&amp;rsquo;ve developed two powerful libraries, NextJS-Boilerplate and React-Toolkit, that can help teams get started quickly and efficiently.
Challenges in Project Initiation Software development teams often face several challenges during project initiation, including:</description></item><item><title>From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</guid><description>In this case study, we share our experience of transitioning from multi-repository structure to a monorepo using Turbo in our project. This migration led to numerous benefits, including a 60% reduction in build times, a 40% increase in developer productivity, and simplified dependency management. Our goal is to offer valuable insights and lessons learned throughout our journey to help others considering a similar transition.
Introduction Over the past two years, we have developed NgheNhan - a trading platform that not only enables users to manage their accounts efficiently but also allows them to analyze market data and trading performance in realtime.</description></item><item><title>Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</guid><description>We could find a bunch of AARRR frameworks definition across the internet (Thanks to Google). I don’t intend to create another one here.
Today I just want to share the simplest definition of this framework and how we have done here at Dwarves. It is a jumping-off point to brainstorming what AARRR does, and why it’s the important step that needs to be done.
What is AARRR framework by the way AARRR is a revenue-driven funnel, what makes it different than other funnels?</description></item></channel></rss>