<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>architecture on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in architecture on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Micro Frontend</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</guid><description>Micro-Frontend - What &amp;amp; Why? As web applications become more complex and feature-rich, traditional frontend architectures such as monolithic will become harder to maintain, scale, and evolve. Micro-frontend is an emerging front-end architecture that aims to address these challenges by breaking down the front-end into small, independent and reusable modules.
In this article, we will explore the concept of micro-frontend, its benefits, design principles, tools and technologies, implementation strategies, and challenges.</description></item><item><title>Architecture Decision Record</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</guid><description>There is an issue that every team will inevitably bump into. Newbies might get confused when a project is being developed. They wonder how that code was written, how we ended up choosing that architecture. It somehow leads to finger-point, and even the decision-maker himself can&amp;rsquo;t remember how that decision was taken.
That happens in a long-term project, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. We believe we&amp;rsquo;re not the only one who gets that, so we&amp;rsquo;d like to gather you all and tackle this today by a practice called Architecture Decision Record (ADR)</description></item><item><title>Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fabric-hyperledger-architecture-explanation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fabric-hyperledger-architecture-explanation/</guid><description>What is Hyperledger Hyperledger is an open source community focused on developing a suite of stable frameworks, tools and libraries for enterprise-grade blockchain deployments.
It serves as a neutral home for various distributed ledger frameworks including Hyperledger Fabric, Sawtooth, Indy, as well as tools like Hyperledger Caliper and libraries like Hyperledger Ursa.
Key concept of Blockchain in Hyperledger A Distributed Ledger Records all the transactions that take place on the network</description></item></channel></rss>