<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dwarves Memo on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><description>Recent content in Dwarves Memo on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/memo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>November Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>$icy in 2024</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/icy-in-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/icy-in-2024/</guid><description>Follow up on our recent post df protocol, $icy and $dfg.
Since 2020, $icy has been a part of our workflow. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap.
2020: we introduced ICY as our first community experiment. 2021: we launched icy.so, a site to redeem $icy. 2022: $icy became our primary reward method, starting with summit-2022 and doty where we sent out about $20000 2023: we introduced vault as a reward avenue for our functional team.</description></item><item><title>$icy Salary Advance</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/salary-advance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/salary-advance/</guid><description>as we said in our recent post $icy in 2024 plan. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re launching the first feature from our 2024 roadmap: an $icy salary advance.
tl:dr, It&amp;rsquo;s a short-term credit benefit available to all full-time employees in our company.
e.g:
hnh earn $5000 a month hnh can ask for upto 25% ($1250) of his monthly allowance in advanced the credit will be paid automatically by hnh next pay day, plus 0.</description></item><item><title>💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s our draft internal map/v0 for 🧊 $icy play, based on our current activities at this borderless software firm.
Context:
Back in 2018, when i envisioned doing something unconventional with our setup, we introduced 💎 $dfg.
It came with a dream that everyone on the team can help build next generation software, stay cool making money and own something. I planned to step down and give more ownership to those who actually implement our projects by gradually distributing $dfg to our grind chads.</description></item><item><title>October Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-october-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of October, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been for the most part very exciting, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;Full-stack engineering’ Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is prolific and always true: Open-source.
Open-source has always been the foundation for many hobby projects, learning experiences, startups, and enterprises. It has stayed true to the idea for the rights to use, study, change, and distribute the software and its source code to anyone and for any purpose - originally helping to fix bugs and later accelerating state-of-the-art tech and AI.</description></item><item><title>Konvoy X Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/konvoy-x-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/konvoy-x-dwarves/</guid><description>**Industry: **
Logistics, Supply Chain Management
Location:
Australia,
**Business Context: **
An innovative company providing beverage industry with a unique keg rental solution, emphasizing sustainability and ease of use.
Solution:
A tech-driven rental system with real-time keg tracking and analytics ensuring security and transparency.
Outcome:
Increase the operational efficiency and profitability of breweries with a flexible, secure, and eco-friendly keg supply chain.
Our Service:
Product Consulting, Staff Augmentation
In brief Konvoy, a pioneering force in the keg management industry, first surfaced in Australia and New Zealand in October 2019.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Our View On Fullstack Engineering</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</guid><description>In tackling challenges in the world of software development, the term &amp;ldquo;full-stack engineer&amp;rdquo; often evokes a sense of wonder. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of my school days when our chemistry teacher explained the fundamental principles behind chemical reactions. Just as every chemical reaction is governed by the behavior of atoms, there&amp;rsquo;s an underlying principle in software development that defines full-stack engineering.
At its core, full-stack engineering is more than just a developer who works on both the backend and frontend.</description></item><item><title>Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</guid><description>Industry
Fintech
Tech stack
MySQL, JAVA Spring Boot, and Angular
Location
South East Asia
Solution
Fast recruiting senior engineers to collaborate with CIMB’s tech team.
Deliver quality and collaboration control through out the project to hit targeted timeline.
Outcome
In charge of the backend foundation, we marked a milestone in CIMB&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation journey, with a streamlined, customer-focused experience contributed to CIMB&amp;rsquo;s forward-looking vision.
Our Service
Tech Consulting, Staff Augmentation</description></item><item><title>Adoption Of Pnpm</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share that the Dwarves team has officially decided to switch to pnpm as our primary package management tool. After careful evaluation, we found that pnpm is widely embraced by the development community and has been successfully used by great teams at Vercel, Nx, and Chakra UI.
Previously, we were using Yarn V1 classic, but as our projects grew, we faced challenges with disk space and slow installations.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Community Bounty</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</guid><description>As you may know, Dwarves Discord network is where we connect with our friends, alumni, and like-minded people.
Bounties are rewards (in ICY - Dwarves’ token) given out to community members for work that encourages community developers to get more involved in the development outside of their core skills.
Who can join
We offer a platform for those seeking development work and a dynamic environment to connect with skilled developers capable of building new tools, new features.</description></item><item><title>Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</guid><description>I had my fair share of interviews. Most of them are &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; QnA sessions, and unpaid take-home projects, and coding assessments. Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s paid project is different and left a good impression on me.
The Beginning At the time, I had been looking for a new job for a while, and somehow found Dwarves, which is a rare functional programming (Elixir) shop in Vietnam. Skimming the site and what people wrote, I found the organization fascinating: they value learning and craftsmanship.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves Software Design Group</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</guid><description>The idea: A path to better software “Everything in software architecture is a trade-off, and the why is more important than how.&amp;quot; Neal Ford is a Director and software architect at ThoughtWorks
At Dwarves, we believe that growth is our universal language, and we always strive to improve ourselves, individual-wise and team-wise.
At the end of 2021, starting with engineering practices, the core idea behind creating a software design group is to enable engineers to develop the skills required to become software architects.</description></item><item><title>How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-created-an-ai-powered-interview-system-using-openais-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-created-an-ai-powered-interview-system-using-openais-chatgpt/</guid><description>The Idea While ChatGPT has garnered a lot of attention over the last few months, Ngoc Thanh, our senior software engineer, has been exploring how OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s API can expedite and elevate job interviews by distilling key candidate insights through an interactive chat interview. The system automatically constructs a question set based on the candidate&amp;rsquo;s position, such as fresher, mid-level, or senior, to provide relevant questions based on their expertise.</description></item><item><title>Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/approaches-to-manage-concurrent-workloads-like-worker-pools-and-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/approaches-to-manage-concurrent-workloads-like-worker-pools-and-pipelines/</guid><description>Introduction Go provides us great and convenient ways to write concurrent programs with high performance to execute tasks concurrently (perhaps in parallel if the program is run on a machine with multiple physical cores, GOMAXPROCS are automatically set to the number of physical cores of the machine that the program is running on)
While the Go concurrency primitives are easy to work with (it means it&amp;rsquo;s easy to create the Go concurrency primitives and start using them), but they don&amp;rsquo;t prevent us the developers to write something incorrectly or buggy.</description></item><item><title>Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/easy-prompt-engineering-for-business-use-and-mitigating-risks-in-llms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/easy-prompt-engineering-for-business-use-and-mitigating-risks-in-llms/</guid><description>Preface At Dwarves, we&amp;rsquo;ve begun creating apps with ChatGPT for some of our clients. One common problem we face is what techniques of prompt engineering should we use for cases like avoiding political interactions and defending against data leaks. We have been exposed to jailbreaks for ChatGPT such as DAN and Mango Tom, but only recently have figured out how to engineer these kinds of prompts for our research. There are quite a lot of prompt engineering techniques, but below is a collection of common techniques we think you might need the most when creating business apps.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/exploring-machine-learning-approaches-for-fine-tuning-llama-models/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/exploring-machine-learning-approaches-for-fine-tuning-llama-models/</guid><description>At Dwarves, we&amp;rsquo;ve been increasingly exposed to more state-of-the-art news coming from AI than ever before, of course, related to Large Language Models (LLM). We&amp;rsquo;ve had a taste of what AI has to offer with Stable Diffusion and more commercial apps, and have been eager to learn and hone our skillsets in applying these new AI breakthroughs in our everyday lives and our apps.
Introduction If 2021 was the year of blockchain, it&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to say that 2023 is the year of generative AI.</description></item><item><title>Managing Dataflow And Sql Database With Concurrency Control</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/managing-dataflow-and-sql-database-with-concurrency-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/managing-dataflow-and-sql-database-with-concurrency-control/</guid><description>memo/assets/managing-dataflow-and-sql-database-with-concurrency-control/c11c827159778f301fbd67b9d155b80b_MD5.avif
Some of us had built a game, while others were familiar with e-commerce platforms, D-apps, or even all of these types of applications, and more. Each type of software that we were working on needed different techniques, some of which were similar. So the same problem can happen in every software product. In this post, we will discuss an issue in high-workload databases together. It is Concurrency Control.
Problem Let&amp;rsquo;s consider that we have an e-bank application that includes an account table.</description></item><item><title>Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/message-queues-and-streaming-platforms-eg-kafka-nats-rabbitmq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/message-queues-and-streaming-platforms-eg-kafka-nats-rabbitmq/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, we host a few learning sessions to understand some of the technology around us. We regularly pick up topics we find interesting to dive deeper into to understand them better and present our findings. One topic that piqued my interest was the use of message brokers, due to how prevalent their use case is in our projects.
In today&amp;rsquo;s digital world, the exchange of information between different systems and applications is becoming increasingly important.</description></item><item><title>Choosing The Right Javascript Framework A Deep Dive Into React Vs Angular Vs Vue</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/choosing-the-right-javascript-framework-a-deep-dive-into-react-vs-angular-vs-vue/</guid><description>Selecting the ideal JavaScript framework can be a daunting task, particularly when faced with an abundance of highly resourceful and capable options. To make an informed decision that caters to specific project requirements, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to possess a deep understanding of various critical aspects. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll shed light on some of these essential points by conducting a comprehensive comparison of Angular, React, and Vue.
We’ve had our fair share of decision fatigue keeping up with new frameworks and choosing the right ones for the job.</description></item><item><title>Design System For Layer 2 Using Zk Rollup</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-system-for-layer-2-using-zk-rollup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-system-for-layer-2-using-zk-rollup/</guid><description>At Dwarves, we are currently working on creating a bridge token in one of our blockchain projects. With more recent concerns on privacy and security, we wanted to understand how we could move tokens across blockchains without needing to know any other information about the transaction. This has motivated our research on Zero-Knowledge proofs and their possible applications for bridges.
Introduction Blockchain technology has revolutionized the way we think about trust and decentralization, enabling the creation of secure and transparent systems without the need for intermediaries.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned From Being A Part Of Corporate Micro Frontend Implementation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-being-a-part-of-corporate-micro-frontend-implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-being-a-part-of-corporate-micro-frontend-implementation/</guid><description>Introduction As we venture further into the dynamic world of frontend development, we developers are on a constant quest for techniques that boost productivity, maintainability, and collaboration among multiple teams. Micro-frontends have risen to prominence as a favored architectural choice for achieving these goals. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the experiences and insights we&amp;rsquo;ve gained from a recent corporate micro-frontend implementation project, shedding light on the technical specifics and best practices that can be applied to comparable endeavors.</description></item><item><title>Cost Of React Native</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cost-of-react-native/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cost-of-react-native/</guid><description>React Native is a popular cross-platform app development framework that allows developers to build mobile apps for both iOS and Android platforms using a single codebase. It has gained popularity in recent years due to its ability to provide a native-like experience while reducing development time and cost.
Introduction At Dwarves, React Native has been on our radar and we use it in some of our projects. Lately, we have been investigating cost-benefits of using it and making light of some concerns we should be aware of.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-concurrency-practices-in-blockchain-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-concurrency-practices-in-blockchain-projects/</guid><description>This article covers some lessons learned from working on blockchain projects, with a team that was often optimistic about transparent distributed concurrency. Our API server was scaled to 3 replicas, which introduces a lot of concurrency nuance and race conditions in our app. This post mentions one of those problems, which we tackled with advisory locks. All examples are written in Go.
Introduction This story comes from a few projects with our teams optimistically setting more than one replica for a server on Kubernetes (heck, this still happens now).</description></item><item><title>Continuous Translation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/continuous-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/continuous-translation/</guid><description>Introduction Continuous Translation (CT) is a modern approach to translation management that involves synchronizing software development and translation workflows. This means that developers, translators, and product owners work together in a continuous cycle to ensure that all translations are up-to-date and aligned with the latest software developments.
Unlike traditional translation workflows, Continuous Translation eliminates the need for file and space synchronization between different stakeholders, streamlining the translation process and promoting better collaboration.</description></item><item><title>Database Designs For Multilingual Apps</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</guid><description>This story comes from the necessity of multi-language support across our applications. Dwarves Foundation handles a lot of international clients and there is always some level of concern for supporting multiple languages for certain apps. This is a concern not just from our clients, but also from us, which motivated our research for multilingual support.
Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s globalized world, many applications need to support multiple languages to reach a broader audience.</description></item><item><title>Unit Testing Best Practices In Golang</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/unit-testing-best-practices-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/unit-testing-best-practices-in-golang/</guid><description>One common issue we often tackle in backend engineering is writing test cases. In this article, we will explore the techniques for crafting effective tests in Go, discussing best practices for writing unit tests and utilizing mocks to achieve better isolation. Although our primary focus lies in unit testing-related practices, it is important to note that Golang also supports integration testing. We will also tackle the subject of integration testing in a future article, where we will examine the details and best practices for integration testing in Golang.</description></item><item><title>What Is Pnpm Compare To Npmyarn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-is-pnpm-compare-to-npmyarn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-is-pnpm-compare-to-npmyarn/</guid><description>What is PNPM? At Dwarves Foundation, we are always on the lookout for new tech. Researching PNPM was originally from research on what package manager Next.js uses. We then tried to experiment with it for dwarves/react-toolkit, which has given us some insights into some of the cost-benefits of using the package manager.
Introduction PNPM is a package manager for Node.js which stands for “Performant NPM”. It was introduced in 2016, the same year Yarn was released.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</guid><description>Accelerate Project Initiation with Advanced NextJS-Boilerplate &amp;amp; React-Toolkit In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world of software development, project initiation can often be a challenging and time-consuming process, with teams facing issues such as inconsistent code quality, slow setup times, and suboptimal workflows. To address these obstacles and streamline the project initiation process, we&amp;rsquo;ve developed two powerful libraries, NextJS-Boilerplate and React-Toolkit, that can help teams get started quickly and efficiently.
Challenges in Project Initiation Software development teams often face several challenges during project initiation, including:</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, our team has always faced some bit of friction when deploying apps for our clients. We’ve known about blue-green deployments for a while and were recently given the chance to evaluate and demonstrate them for one of our Discord bot projects.
Applying Blue-green deployment for Mochi Bot Introducing Mochi Bot to the Web3 space, our team has developed a flexible and user-friendly product with features like NFT rarity queries, sales alerts on Discord and Twitter, and showing various tips.</description></item><item><title>I18n Frontend Guideline</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</guid><description>In a front-end web application, locales are used to determine the language and geographic location of the user and to display the appropriate content to them.
When a user visits a web page, the application will first detect their locale, then use this information to determine which version of the content to display.
To support multiple languages and locales, the application needs to have the necessary content available for each locale.</description></item><item><title>Radio Talk 61 Monorepo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-61-monorepo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-61-monorepo/</guid><description>Demystifying Monorepos: A Recap of Our Recent Sharing Session During our recent sharing session, we delved into the world of monorepos, exploring their benefits, challenges, and the tools available to manage them effectively. This recap aims to summarize the key points of the discussion and highlight some potential business outcomes of adopting monorepos.
Introduction A monorepo is a version control strategy where all the code for an organization&amp;rsquo;s projects is stored in a single repository.</description></item><item><title>From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</guid><description>In this case study, we share our experience of transitioning from multi-repository structure to a monorepo using Turbo in our project. This migration led to numerous benefits, including a 60% reduction in build times, a 40% increase in developer productivity, and simplified dependency management. Our goal is to offer valuable insights and lessons learned throughout our journey to help others considering a similar transition.
Introduction Over the past two years, we have developed NgheNhan - a trading platform that not only enables users to manage their accounts efficiently but also allows them to analyze market data and trading performance in realtime.</description></item><item><title>Why Micro Frontend</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</guid><description>Micro-Frontend - What &amp;amp; Why? As web applications become more complex and feature-rich, traditional frontend architectures such as monolithic will become harder to maintain, scale, and evolve. Micro-frontend is an emerging front-end architecture that aims to address these challenges by breaking down the front-end into small, independent and reusable modules.
In this article, we will explore the concept of micro-frontend, its benefits, design principles, tools and technologies, implementation strategies, and challenges.</description></item><item><title>Why We Chose Our Tech Stack Accelerating Development With A Robust Frontend Solution</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-we-chose-our-tech-stack-accelerating-development-with-a-robust-frontend-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/why-we-chose-our-tech-stack-accelerating-development-with-a-robust-frontend-solution/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, we pride ourselves on being a team of seasoned technology experts, passionate about crafting innovative solutions for our clients. With years of experience in the technology industry, we understand the importance of selecting the right tools and technologies to deliver exceptional results. In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, staying ahead of the competition requires building and deploying features quickly without sacrificing quality or stability. When selecting a technology for our frontend tech stack, the foremost question we ask is: &amp;ldquo;Has this technology achieved a certain level of stability and maturity?</description></item><item><title>Radio Talk 60 Blue Green Deployment</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-60-blue-green-deployment/</guid><description>Blue-green deployment has become an important topic in modern software development, and this deployment strategy has become our focus on the tech radar. In a recent radio talk, Quang Le, one of our DevOps engineers, presented the significance of blue-green deployment and its benefits. This memo is a quick recap of the talk.
A brief Blue-green deployment is a software deployment strategy that involves creating two identical environments: one that is live and serving user traffic (blue) and one that is not (green).</description></item><item><title>Growth Is Our Universal Language</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</guid><description>At Dwarves, the core team live and breathe growth. We believe that growth is our universal language, and we&amp;rsquo;re always striving to improve ourselves, both personally and professionally. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a job for us; it&amp;rsquo;s a way of life. We&amp;rsquo;re hustlers with an extra hat, always pushing ourselves to be better and earn more.
Every time we hire, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for like-minded individuals who share our growth mindset. We want to be with people who are willing to challenge themselves and reach new heights.</description></item><item><title>Ogif</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ogif/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ogif/</guid><description>I would like to introduce to you our new initiative called OGIF — Oh God It&amp;rsquo;s Friday. Moving forward, our Friday Showcase will have a broader range of topics to discuss and share.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to reflect on our achievements from the past week, and look forward to the next with optimism and enthusiasm.
The tradition At Dwarves, we value work-life balance and believe that it comes after fulfilling our responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Red Flags</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/red-flags/</guid><description>These red flags are things we don’t want to see in our peeps. Even when you think they are improper, don’t waste your time with a wrong group of people.
Negative attitude The employee may exhibit a negative attitude towards their work, colleagues, or the company. They may also show signs of disengagement, lack of motivation, lack of integrity or unwillingness to learn.
Incompatibility** **The employee may not fit in with the company culture or may have a personality clash with other team members.</description></item><item><title>Focus On Software Delivery</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/focus-on-software-delivery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/focus-on-software-delivery/</guid><description>Focus on shipping when you are struggling with what to do next to be better as a software engineer. When you ship something new, users will try out your build and give you feedback. It may contain bugs. It may ship with the wrong flow implemented. It may ship with known issues. You may feel bad but and frustrated but those emotions will save you ton of time. The point is: Users will let you know.</description></item><item><title>Are You Helping</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-you-helping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-you-helping/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive business environment, it is crucial for organizations to have a clear understanding of the value and performance of their employees. In a recent post I wrote, titled &amp;ldquo;Inner Circle&amp;rdquo;, I expounded on the importance of contribution and value in relation to a person&amp;rsquo;s work or performance. However, there is another key aspect to this topic that must be taken into consideration. One of the most effective ways to determine how well a person is performing is by asking the question, &amp;ldquo;Are you helping?</description></item><item><title>Discord Roles</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/discord-roles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/discord-roles/</guid><description>To organize our discord and make it fun to interact between community members, we setup those roles for specific purposes. They are ladder-based and function-based roles.
Moderating supporter: help with day-to-day activity, welcome new folks. moderator: organize events, tech talks, &amp;hellip; . smod: run community &amp;amp; company-wide operational works. Community members guest: it is a default role, you will gain this role joined discord. newbie: did an introduction within our network.</description></item><item><title>Happy 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/happy-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/happy-2023/</guid><description>As we enter a new year, I want to reflect on the role that software has played in my life. From the early days of my career to now, software has been a constant presence and something that I have dedicated countless hours to as both an engineer and project manager. I have put in over 10,000 hours of work in this field, and it has become an integral part of my existence.</description></item><item><title>2022 Dwarves Renaissance A Year End Rewind</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2022-dwarves-renaissance-a-year-end-rewind/</guid><description>Table of Content: 2022 Dwarves Renaissance: A Year-End Rewind Successfully went through 2022, a year that we might say - a new record: team reached highest growth record, kickstarted community engagement, home, compliance training &amp;amp; individual development are speeding up, and a whole new place to call Dwarves.
We’ve achieved to this year’s resolution: A team that cares about how to build software right and can teach others on that.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of The Year 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-the-year-2022/</guid><description>Dwarves of The Year 2022 - Wins to Celebrate It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, but we&amp;rsquo;ve finally made it to 2022 and what a year it&amp;rsquo;s been for our team of Dwarves. Countless hours of hard work and it&amp;rsquo;s all paid off with our big wins of the year. Honored for all and huge congratulations for our Dwarves of 2022.
A total of ~$18,000 awarded and rewarded by ****$ICY - Dwarves official token, with a few names appearing several times.</description></item><item><title>The Inner Circle</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-inner-circle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-inner-circle/</guid><description>The concept of an &amp;ldquo;inner circle&amp;rdquo; within a company is not a new one, and at Dwarves, a software company founded by a group of engineers, this idea holds a significant value. Starting from scratch, the company has always placed emphasis on being surrounded by individuals who can efficiently ship software and don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on unimportant tasks. These individuals are highly respected and valued within the company, as they play a crucial role in the development and success of projects.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Summit 2022 Engineering A Good Time</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-summit-2022-engineering-a-good-time/</guid><description>Dwarves Summit 2022: Engineering a good time. We don’t treat team bonding the common way, because we understand our engineers. Most of our engineers don’t want running and getting sweaty on the beach for “team-building” activities, or pretending to smile in front of the travel agent’s camera.
This was our first company get-together after 2 years of COVID. It was organized in ways that we can all look back to the progress we’ve made, pat ourselves on the back, have a blast together, and look forward to an even better 2023.</description></item><item><title>The Key Of Security Mechanisms In Tackling Cyber Threats</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</guid><description>Hosted by Thanh Pham - Engineering Manager, Dwarves had a great time with the best minds in cybersecurity- Mr. Hieu PC to share his knowledge and experience. As someone who is always looking to improve skills, this event is extremely valuable. We learned a lot about the different elements of cybersecurity and how to better protect our code.
Hieu PC was a pro ex-hacker who made headlines and is now a Security Expert at Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s National Cybersecurity Centre (NCSC).</description></item><item><title>Configure The Company Email</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</guid><description>1. Make sure you have 2FA enabled For this method to work, you need to have two factor authentification enabled for your Google account. If it’s not, follow the link below and set it up.
https://www.google.com/landing/2step/
2. Create an App Password Google will verify your ownership with this app password. Select “Mail” under app, and “Mac” under device. Hit “Generate”. Copy and keep for later!
3. Add your email to Gmail Go to Gmail -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Accounts and Import.</description></item><item><title>Tech Event In The Latest Transforming Healthcare With Technology</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/tech-event---in-the-latest-transforming-healthcare-with-technology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/tech-event---in-the-latest-transforming-healthcare-with-technology/</guid><description>Hosted by Nikki - Dwarves&amp;rsquo; COO, and Thanh Pham - Engineering Manager, Dwarves had a great lineup and gleaned insights on the new wave of healthcare through the immense knowledge and practical experience through inspiring stories from Ms. Ruby Nguyen and Mr. Binh Le.
Start-up ideas come from your own needs.
“Momby started with the health needs of a pregnant mother and grew by understanding the worries of soon-to-be parents. Momby aims to provide a foundation for supporting knowledge, creating a safe and reliable space for expecting parents to freely learn, share, and help one another helping, thus making social impacts on Maternity care.</description></item><item><title>Open Fabric Set The Tech Foundation And Built An Mvp From Scratch</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</guid><description>Founded and led by veterans from fintech players like Paypal &amp;amp; Grab, Open Fabric is a BNPL platform, built to enable an open commerce network for customers and credit providers in South East Asia to radically simplify merchant integrations for digital payment methods.
With a team of 8 engineers, Dwarves helped set the tech foundation and together built an MVP from scratch. Within a year, Dwarves helped ship the system to onboard and configure payment methods for companies to the Open Fabric commerce network.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship Batch Of 2022</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-foundation-apprenticeship-batch-of-2022/</guid><description>It’s our second attempt rolling out this program. But the motivation stays the same: Accelerating someone’s current software development skillset.
It’s neither for interns nor veterans. As stated in the beginning, our goal is to empower software engineers with at least 1 years of experience to rebuild their foundation through:
Software Development Practices Real-projects Scenarios Engineering Work Ethics &amp;amp; Principles The stats speak Although keeping the bar high might extend the searching time, but we maintain a solid standard for every batch.</description></item><item><title>From Data To Backend An Apprentice Sharing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-data-to-backend-an-apprentice-sharing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-data-to-backend-an-apprentice-sharing/</guid><description>For My Anh*, Dwarves Foundation Apprenticeship has surpassed a traditional training program concept. With her, it’s been a huge shift: A supportive team that embraces her for who she is and unlocks her capabilities to grow in ways she never imagined. *
My Anh, Saigon-based Data &amp;amp; Backend
Dwarves Apprentices, batch of 2022
How did you first envision the Dwarves Apprenticeship Program? “I expected it would be a stepping stone to reinforcing my software development skillset.</description></item><item><title>Data Analyst In Retail Trading</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</guid><description>I am Bach Phuong and I work at Dwarves Foundation as a Data Analyst, helping partner companies realize insights and understand their business better.
What does a Data Analyst do? A Data Analyst is a gatekeeper for an organization’s data. They are tasked to explore, transform, aggregate data to create business insights from that data to then create reports to stakeholders. Thanks to these reports, companies can make more informed business decisions.</description></item><item><title>Passing The Probation Get 3 Upvotes</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/passing-the-probation-get-3-upvotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/passing-the-probation-get-3-upvotes/</guid><description>The talent pool Dwarves are backed by the talent pool. We’re selective for those that are in the funnel. Like-minded people and their unique values stay above everything. Therefore, we run a significant adjustment on the admission principle: To pass the probation means the current Dwarves accept you.
The 3 out of 4 principle We’re divided into 4 kinds of association:
Project member: The people you are directly working with.</description></item><item><title>Road To 100</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/road-to-100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/road-to-100/</guid><description>2022 matched us with the 80th Dwarves. A notable highlight, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to have more. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to find people that has the same value. It takes true &amp;amp; solid seeks.
On our way to meet the 81th and onward, we&amp;rsquo;re launching a mechanism to help us find like-minded DNAs, and co-create our future using tech.
The Dwarves Referral Program We usually hire and keep the quality bar. The Dwarves are encouraged to recommend friends they think might be a good match for the team.</description></item><item><title>The Next Leading Chairs</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-next-leading-chairs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-next-leading-chairs/</guid><description>OUR VISION FOR GROWTH Last Jan 2020, we got the chance to celebrate our first milestone - Dwarves Foundation reached 5 years old. The remarkable moment contained the proudest thing we delivered.
**Remote Culture - **That enables us to make things work without any physical constraints. We were able to focus on what we value: Knowledge and People. To name a few: **T****he Handbook **- To demonstrate our culture, the future we pursue and what portrays the Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Hieu Vu</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-hieu-vu/</guid><description>English below ↓ **Life at Dwarves #6**, là những chia sẻ của Hiếu Vũ về hành trình pick up và yêu thích Golang, quá trình gắn bó từ dự án đến con người tại Dwarves. Những trải nghiệm đó để lại cho Hiếu nhiều bài học và lời khuyên cho các bạn trẻ muốn theo đuổi công việc lập trình viên. Hiếu Vũ từng là thực tập sinh ở tập đoàn công nghệ KMS, và hiện tại là Backend Engineer tại Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Nam Nguyen Keep Pushing Oneself Towards Goal</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-nam-nguyen-keep-pushing-oneself-towards-goal/</guid><description>English below ↓
**Life at Dwarves #5** là câu chuyện về Nam Nguyễn và hành trình hơn 5 năm gắn bó với Dwarves. Sau khi hoàn thành Cao Đẳng, Nam làm ở một công ty offshore của Nhật Bản với vị trí Fullstack Engineer. Sau khi quyết định nghỉ việc tại công ty cũ để tập trung cho tấm bằng Đại học, Nam gia nhập Dwarves, và trở thành một trong những contributor lâu nhất tại tech firm này.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With An Tran The More You Challenge Yourself The More Exciting It Gets</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-an-tran-the-more-you-challenge-yourself-the-more-exciting-it-gets/</guid><description>***“Anh nghiệm ra rằng trong hành trình trở thành Senior Software Engineer, càng thử thách bản thân, mọi thứ sẽ càng thú vị.”*** Life at Dwarves lần này là một nhân vật khá kín tiếng ở Dwarves với đời sống lành mạnh và tính cách nhẹ nhàng. Anh An Trần, Senior Software Engineer với 7 năm kinh nghiệm làm nghề từ các start-up đến Project Lead tại Dwarves Foundation.</description></item><item><title>Spike Inu Engineering A Seamless Experience For Cross Chain Swap And Decentralized Exchange</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</guid><description>In brief When blockchain becomes the new tech blockbuster, worldwide blockchain networks such as Ethereum, Polygon, Avalanche, Fantom, or Binance Smart Chance started to develop their own tokens. They all possess the same vision: Empower crypto users to transfer their assets in multiple chains hassle-free and effective. The core engine of those products is building a secured bridging solution between chains, enabling tokens to move back and forth, and transferring tokens on the same network.</description></item><item><title>Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</guid><description>In brief Hedge Foundation is a powerful dashboard to support users in managing crypto account positions, balance, PNL and works on bulk orders for profit and loss tracking.
Move alongside the crypto era, Hedge Foundation works to be part of the industry by providing practical tools for crypto users in terms of automating, syncing &amp;amp; managing accounts by utilizing the most out of market database.
Technical Highlight
AG Grid to optimize big table with fast update real-time data.</description></item><item><title>React Native New Architecture</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</guid><description>📖 Introducing react-native&amp;rsquo;s new architecture changes that boost performance, bringing react-native back into the race with Flutter
Introduction of react-native 📱 React Native is a JavaScript framework for writing high-performance mobile apps that leverage iOS and Android native components. It is based on React, and is very accessible to React Web developers
After a long announcement, planned from 2018, appeared in 2020, merged in 2021 and officially published in April 2022, react-native has a new architecture that improves performance dramatically.</description></item><item><title>React 18</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</guid><description>React 18 was released in March 2022. This release focuses on performance improvements and updating the rendering engine.
React 18 Feature Quick Guide Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these updates in more detail.
Concurrency in React Concurrency is not a feature, per se. It’s a new behind-the-scenes mechanism that enables React to prepare multiple versions of your UI at the same time. A key property of Concurrent React is that rendering is interruptible.</description></item><item><title>May 2022 All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/may-2022-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>FOUNDATION Project Allocation
We concluded the partnership with Relay and Eklipse. It has been a fun (and wild) ride for some of you. New resources are being allocated to help balance the current workload of active projects. If you need to discuss your workload or seek more room for project work, please help ping Giang or Nikki.
Our view on Blockchain
Got a quick chat with Ngoc Thanh, our Sr.</description></item><item><title>Remix Versus Nextjs</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</guid><description>📖 A brief comparison between Remix and Next.js frameworks
Introduction of Remix Remix describes itself as:
Remix is an edge native, full-stack JavaScript framework for building modern, fast, and resilient user experiences. It unifies the client and server with web standards so you can think less about code and more about your product.
Compared to Next.js, which is one of the most React frameworks used for server-side rendering and has been there for a significant time, Remix appears as a new strong competitor.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Ngoc Thanh Pham</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-ngoc-thanh-pham/</guid><description>[DF APPRENTICESHIP 2022 - MEET THE MENTORS]
Dwarves Team is shifting our focus to blockchain technology. We offer study groups and blockchain-based projects for peeps to grow and catch up with this rising trend. Thanh is one of the vital elements of this team; and we know he’ll be more than happy to have you onboard.
What raises your interest for Dwarves?
“My path at Dwarves began with the zeal to develop web3 and blockchain products.</description></item><item><title>Df Apprenticeship 2022 Meet The Mentors Tuan Dao</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-apprenticeship-2022---meet-the-mentors-tuan-dao/</guid><description>Tuan Dao - Senior Frontend/ Blockchain Engineer
Tuan has 4+ years of experience under his belt, 2 out of those 4+ was spent at Dwarves Foundation. Tuan’s years of experience don’t quite do him justice though, for he’s skilled and knowledge beyond the year, and has took part in projects of various sizes and domains.
When asked what’s the force behind, Tuan shared it’s because of is very own principle of working: “To find joy in your profession”.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Tom Nguyen Remote Working At Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-tom-nguyen-remote-working-at-dwarves/</guid><description>A catch-up with Tom - our Data Lead, and hear how remote working has fit him perfectly. Tom is one of our core contributors of Dwarves Brainery, and he&amp;rsquo;ll be playing as a key mentor for our upcoming Apprenticeship.
Working remotely fits me well. It keeps me from distraction. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m always at home, so WFH is awesome. My previous workplace required people to be at the office and hang out for drinks afterward, and it was a bit overwhelmed in my pov.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Anh Tran How Its Like To Be A Head Of Ui</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-anh-tran-how-its-like-to-be-a-head-of-ui/</guid><description>Anh, in short, is the UI wizard behind most of our branding identity. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing her work of art on every Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s digital asset.
A person can take care of both UX and UI design if the project is small. As a product designer, you&amp;rsquo;re expected to know both. “I work for the graphic side, mainly on UI, app appearance, and app research to gain more insight for the team.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves With Thanh Pham Ensure A Place Where People Can Thrive</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-with-thanh-pham-ensure-a-place-where-people-can-thrive/</guid><description>Been with us for nearly 5 years, Thanh has been taking care of the juniors and ensuring their progress goes alongside the company’s direction. He is also the co-host of Dwarves Radio Talk - our weekly tech training every Monday.
My job is to ensure a healthy environment for everyone to thrive. “I guide and train people if they are assigned to me. Dwarves Team has a 60-day Program to evaluate, and it usually is a 90-day plan, but based on the company size, the timeline can be adjusted to optimize its teammate growth.</description></item><item><title>January Updates</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/january-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/january-updates/</guid><description>Project Highlights MStation as our latest blockchain-based project
It’s the first BSCS Metaverse blockchain game on Binance Smart Chain (BSC). Players can summon characters, complete daily mining missions, protect the MStation, loot rare items to play and earn.
We get to deploy a full team for this project, consist of 6 people, with Khai Le as part time PM and Ngọc Thành as Team Lead.
In general, we’re getting multiple upselling requests which means we need more people to join our team.</description></item><item><title>2021 Dwarves In Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-dwarves-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-dwarves-in-review/</guid><description>Table of Content Wrapping up Dwarves 1.0 A few things worth celebrating We are expanding Dwarves 1.0 in numbers Highlighted Dwarves of 2021 Onto Dwarves 2.0 **Started with 3 engineers working in different coffee shops because we didn&amp;rsquo;t have an office back then, we are gearing up for the second coming in our journey with over 40 clients and partners worldwide, +1M lines of code later throughout more than 7 years.</description></item><item><title>December All Hands Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/december-all-hands-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/december-all-hands-meeting/</guid><description>Moving with Blockchain We shift our focus to real deals.
Meanwhile, #blockchain #web3 channels are there for the Dwarves to learn &amp;amp; exchange their knowns. Grab your seat.
The teammates also propose to join blockchain projects. We’re happy onboard Hien, Tu and Ngoc Mai on Spike Inu and Eklipse - and actively seek more chances for our teammates.
Selective in Project Decision It’s a promise of bigger clients &amp;amp; better team deployment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Of 2021</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-of-2021/</guid><description>Dwarves of 2021 - We met at last ♡ Apart from the voting result from the team of each title, we also have the Honorable Mention and Client Endorsed - selected by the team leads, as we want to honor all of the hard work.
You can find the voting details here. The final result was close, since you’re all awesome!
Let’s all welcome our Dwarves of 2021 🛠</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Radio Talk 17 Conduct A 1 1 Session</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-radio-talk-17-conduct-a-1-1-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-radio-talk-17-conduct-a-1-1-session/</guid><description>In this Radio Talk, Thanh Pham - our Head of Web, shared how he conducts a 1-1 meeting with the Fellows. Working already four years at Dwarves, he has mentored a bunch of Juniors and realized many lesson-learned.
Understand the spirit of 1-1 session goal Why do we need to run this practice, and how to avoid wasting time? First of all, it&amp;rsquo;s all bout building trust and creates mutual belief.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Radio Talk 16 Run An Effective Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-radio-talk-16-run-an-effective-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-radio-talk-16-run-an-effective-performance-review/</guid><description>Performance Review We perform bi-yearly reviews in July and January. The primary purpose of these reviews is to **give feedback **on career path advancement and recognize accomplishments. We follow a simple process:
Everyone writes up a 1-2 page summary and sends it to the head of their team. The head of your team reviews your summary and prepares their thoughts. He schedules a one-hour meeting to discuss. Inside the summary We run this practice with two spirits:</description></item><item><title>2021 July Updates</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-july-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2021-july-updates/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re closing July with some notable highlights. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through them ✌️
🚨 *Note: Covid situation is getting worse. Stay safe. 🦠
*The pandemic is going stronger than ever. There has been over 100k internal cases over the country til now. Take good care of you and your beloved ones. We hope everyone can stay safe.
Finish the shipment for our WFH station We&amp;rsquo;ve finished the shipment for all the WFH gears.</description></item><item><title>Startupvn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startupvn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startupvn/</guid><description>[startup.vn](http://startup.vn/) was founded 10 years ago, when the concept of "startups" was still fairly new in Vietnam. A handful of people from diverse backgrounds joined hands to create a homeland for Vietnamese who aim at building and growing their own businesses. 💡 Fostering innovation and entrepreneurship in Vietnam since 2011.
What started out as a weekend passion project quickly progressed into a strong, proud, aspiring community. 10 years in, startup.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Intj</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-intj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-intj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Offers opportunities to work with people who are experts in their field Is on the cutting edge or innovative Provides opportunities to work on complex problems Is hard driving and achievement oriented Challenges people intellectually How Type Affects Career Exploration How you go about exploring career options will be influenced by your INTJ preferences. Your type will help you in your career exploration activities in distinct ways, just as it may present some distinct challenges for you.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Istp</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-istp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-istp/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Needs a more practical environment, where they can master skills and do things and see tangible results. Need variety and the opportunity to dip in and out of activities. The environment where their natural disregard for rules, authority and structures allows them to focus on and tackle the emergency at hand in the most effective way ISTP and Career Exploration An ISTP tends to find career satisfaction with careers that have the following characteristics:</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Estj</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-estj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-estj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Tasks Require thorough analysis Practical planning and organizational skills Process control and responsibility Preferred Work Environment Will fit best where the norms are clear The culture is performance driven. The place for everything and everything is in its place ESTJ prefer working with facts, details and the known, where the product or service is tangible rather than conceptual. Clear lines of responsibility and a planning process. Do not like to ‘wing it’ or take risks without being in possession of the facts and having thought things through.</description></item><item><title>Mbti Type Istj</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-istj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/mbti---type-istj/</guid><description>Preferred Work Environment Company where the norms are clear The culture is performance driven and where there is a place for everything and everything is in its place. They prefer working with facts, details and the known, where the product or service is tangible rather than conceptual There are clear lines of responsibility and a planning process. They do not like to ‘wing it’ or take risks without being in possession of the facts and having thought things through so that they are clear.</description></item><item><title>Applying Myersbriggs Type Indicator In Hr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applying-myersbriggs-type-indicator-in-hr/</guid><description>Getting Started This is a part from our study how to recognize people traits at the first sight. This guide is made to help HRs or Project Lead have a quick view of potential candidates and/or new teammates personality. Working with nature is more productive than working against it.
No personality type is inherently better or more desirable than another in general. This reference is applied to the tech industry only.</description></item><item><title>The Four Preferences</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-four-preferences/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-four-preferences/</guid><description>The Four Preferences are:
Extraversion and Introversion When we talk about &amp;ldquo;extraversion&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;introversion&amp;rdquo;, we are distinguishing between the two worlds in which all of us live. There is a world inside ourselves, and a world outside ourselves. When we are dealing with the world outside of ourself, we are &amp;ldquo;extraverting&amp;rdquo;. When we are inside our own minds, we are &amp;ldquo;introverting&amp;rdquo;.
We are extraverting when we:
Talk to other people Listen to what someone is saying Cook dinner, or make a cup of coffee Work on a car We are introverting when we:</description></item><item><title>Making Decision As A Team Member</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</guid><description>Democracy in a Nutshell Sure we all heard of democracy. Mostly, this term appears in erhm, election?
However, from what I understand, democracy is maintained by giving decision-making power to the people. And not just &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; people. Your people.
We make sure they all feel respected. We all work in the same boat. It&amp;rsquo;s their benefit to care of, too. Letting people know the direction means sharing the responsibility, and sharing the responsibility equals reducing the risk.</description></item><item><title>Micro Frontends Microservices For Frontend Development</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/micro-frontends---microservices-for-frontend-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/micro-frontends---microservices-for-frontend-development/</guid><description>Micro-frontend What is Micro-frontend ? An architectural style where independently deliverable frontend applications are composed into a greater whole
Benefits Smaller, more cohesive, and maintainable codebases More scalable organizations with decoupled, autonomous teams The ability to upgrade, update, or even rewrite parts of the frontend in a more incremental fashion than was previously possible Easier maintenance: Keeping frontend repositories small and specialized allows them to be more easily understood, and this simplifies long-term maintenance and testing.</description></item><item><title>Understanding An Application Design</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/understanding-an-application-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/understanding-an-application-design/</guid><description>Requested by our Apprentices, and hosted by Thanh Pham - our Head of Web. Understanding an Application Design is the upfront work for every web project. An application design consists of different main parts, which we highlighted a few below.
Type of Web Project Admin dashboard Client app(almost Listing app) Landing page Important Factors The critical factors that helps define the right framework
Type of Project Required SEO support State of Design: Sketch, Mockup, or Final design Cost for development Number of end-users: 10-100, 100-1000, &amp;gt;1000 Required Responsive Rendering Technique The process of taking HTML code and interprets it into visual results and interactive web pages.</description></item><item><title>Sql Practices Orm Vs Plain Sql</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sql-practices-orm-vs-plain-sql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sql-practices-orm-vs-plain-sql/</guid><description>The Definition Raw: make all query by self from scratch ORM: Object relational mapping: programing technique for converting data between incompatible type systems using OOP SQL Generator: utility sql tool for generate Entity model, query. Factors that affects the technique decision Productivity: spend time for development and maintain. Work with many different DB system, can replace in future Security: SQL injection Performance Practice Use ORM for almost case, with DEEP understanding the library.</description></item><item><title>Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</guid><description>In brief
Momos is a pre-seed startup operating in Singapore, whose founder was an ex-Grab They look to ship the first MVP with a web platform to test the market and onboard promising users. Our team of 3 join them to bring development timeline up to speed as well as improving the core tech foundation to pave the way for a scalable, future-proof system. The collaboration happens remotely since March 2021.</description></item><item><title>Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</guid><description>In brief Attrace is a Netherland decentralized affiliate marketing network that audits action and bridges e-commerce websites to merchants. The core concept is applying referral for different blockchain product use cases They seek to launch MVP for market validation and early user acquisition Our team of 3 join them to contribute to Attrace&amp;rsquo;s core function with custom-made blockchain technology Highlight Blockchain solutions for multiples use-cases Golang for Backend system: Solidity and index blockchain data IPFS as files sharing system GDPR standard for data privacy Fraud detection &amp;amp; verification network The Context Attrace&amp;rsquo;s concept is a marketing platform that helps merchants feature and advertise their products.</description></item><item><title>Supercharged Setel Malaysias First Pay Pump Go Super App</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</guid><description>In brief First introduced by PETRONAS in 2018, Setel is the first e-payment solution for fuel purchases directly from mobile devices. They head to unlock a bigger market by providing a super-app with on-the-go function and platform integration. Our team of 7 partners to involve in their engineering team in Unified Loyalty Platform, specialized in “Conversion” of new potential users. We focus on deals, vouchers, the front-landing page as well as Marketing tracking &amp;amp; integration.</description></item><item><title>What I Learned On Design Thinking And Software Development</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-i-learned-on-design-thinking-and-software-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-i-learned-on-design-thinking-and-software-development/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Huyen Le - newcomer of Dwarves Foundation. Last week, I was taught under the instruction of Khai Le about design thinking and how it works in a design process of a software project. So I decided to write a recap of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
According to my knowledge, the basic definition of design thinking is an iterative process in which we understand the user&amp;rsquo;s needs and problems. Define the problems to bring out the most ideal solutions, then we prototype the idea and test.</description></item><item><title>Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2019, Para is a platform connecting hospitals with medical professionals. Continuing with Go microservices, we have shipped numerous features, markedly workshift management and candidate screening. We partnered and helped unburden Para from the financial stress during the early stage of their MVP development. Our Covid-19 program was launched in early 2020. We aim to provide software development, technical support for startups and businesses to help them stay stable during and progress forward despite the pandemic.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</guid><description>We started the 1st volume a year ago, mostly about assessing all the tech indexes we have adopted for 5 years. Then we moved to the 2nd volume, where we figured ways to simplify the workflow and complete our project toolkit.
And here we go again, another version of tech radar at Dwarves Foundation. 2021 has just gone through its first quarter, and we&amp;rsquo;ve left with some new toys to trial and see if they create any impact.</description></item><item><title>Support Relay In Shipping Their Mvp Product For Us Market Testing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</guid><description>In brief Relay is an extension tool that decreases micromanagement by automating workflows. Relay&amp;rsquo;s first engagement with Dwarves aims to ship their MVP to market as quick as possible for early user acquisition. We dive in with 2 quickly adapt engineers. We keep a stable pace of feature shipment and adjust along with the requirements. Highlights
Slack app &amp;amp; Chrome extension. Custom semantic versioning for chrome extension. Combine flipper, sidekiq for A/B testing and gradually roll out new version.</description></item><item><title>Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</guid><description>Being in a remote team is dope. Manage your own stuff, remove the time and cost of commuting, select your work ambiance, and got equipped with all types of supporting tools.
Basecamp, for example.
Our path with Basecamp didn&amp;rsquo;t cross by accident. Years ago, we embarked on the Slack community and had it applied for internal communication. And project management on another tool, where documents &amp;amp; files are in G-suite.</description></item><item><title>Succeed Naru A Browser Focus Web Extension For Us Market</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</guid><description>In brief Being a digital designer who looks for inspiration and digital trends, Matt hopes for a productivity tool that could lend well to his browsing habit. Matt got in contact with us via a connection of a friend. We were surprised by the opportunity he provides: A browser extension for works management. We did explore web extension - but never had an opportunity for real trial. We take the chance to help bring it to market.</description></item><item><title>Six Things I Extracted From Design Thinking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/six-things-i-extracted-from-design-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/six-things-i-extracted-from-design-thinking/</guid><description>I’m Minh Truong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a UI/UX Design for 2 years. I&amp;rsquo;m currently part of the Dwarves Foundation team. My intention has always been to become a better problem solver, with creativity and productivity being my main goals and focus.
Being a self-learned designer, I research and read a lot. One of my all-time favorite articles is Design Thinking for everyday life by Amira Budi Mutiara. This piece broadened my perspective about Design Thinking and made me curious about the possibility of using Design Thinking to solve problems in everyday life.</description></item><item><title>Gitflow Pull Request</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/gitflow-pull-request/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/gitflow-pull-request/</guid><description>Git is one of the most popular source control. Github is one platform built over the top of Git and well adapted by lots of companies. Knowing the right workflow will help to increase the team productivity. In this post, I will try to cover some of the best practices from the community and the way we applied them at Dwarves Foundation.
Git branching mode Source: https://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/
In sort, you will organize your repository into 5 types of branches:</description></item><item><title>Git Commit Message Convention</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/git-commit-message-convention/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/git-commit-message-convention/</guid><description>I bumped into an article a few days ago. It was short and simple, related enough to make me wonder if we have the same thing in the team. How a git commit message should look like.
From the article The blog post states out what a typical git commit message looks like
&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;(&amp;lt;scope&amp;gt;): &amp;lt;subject&amp;gt; in which
type: stands for the main action scope: stands for the codebase section subject: short description on the commit and</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Ventures Fund 0</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-ventures-fund-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-ventures-fund-0/</guid><description>It all started when us, a couple of product people realized with our expertise in technology, our passion for outstanding software, we have the ability to uplift like-minded founders by helping them build and launch their startups. The idea became clearer when our network of makers, industry experts and investors broadened steadily.
We had every signal that a VC, by makers and for makers, would be the right path for us.</description></item><item><title>From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</guid><description>In brief
Mudah.my is a Malaysian 12-years-old online marketplace. A product derives from a partnership between Telenor ASA of Norway and 701Search Singapore. Currently holds 19.8% Internet share, Mudah meets the increase of customers demand, which led to an overload in the current system. We partnered to help migrating the monolithic architecture into microservices - Unlocking a scalable and feature-extendable platform We spent a month working on-site at Malaysia to directly participate in the work and speed up productivity Technical Highlight Massive migration from monolithic to microservice architecture.</description></item><item><title>Are We Really Engineers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-we-really-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/are-we-really-engineers/</guid><description>Is software engineering &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; engineering? As the Dwarves asked this question during the Apprenticeship Training Program, we had a chance to dig more into the topic. Many professionals discuss this, but there&amp;rsquo;s not a full answer. The engineers strictly follow the engineering process, apply math to solve the problem, and build products. We software engineers don&amp;rsquo;t feel like the same as described. I found the originated articles from Hillel Wayne, and it perfectly answers the question.</description></item><item><title>Beyond The Title</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/beyond-the-title/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/beyond-the-title/</guid><description>The Common Dilemma You&amp;rsquo;re only paid that much to do that much We only pay you that much if you can do only that much It&amp;rsquo;s the scenario that people measure and expect their effort should be traded into paychecks. Employers issue fixed rates for labors, while employees refuse to do things that are not in the job description. It gradually forms a mindset where people decide to work &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to get paid and miss out on the chance to discover their self-limitation.</description></item><item><title>How We Setup Cicd</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-setup-cicd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-setup-cicd/</guid><description>Before we dig through a detailed process, let&amp;rsquo;s set some grounded knowledge about the CI/CD:
CI stands for continuous integration. It involves linting, testing, building, and merging developers&amp;rsquo; various code changes into a shared repository such as GitHub, Gitlab, or pushing software images to a container registry, usually multiple times per day.
On the other hand, CD refers to either continuous delivery or continuous deployment, which are sometimes used interchangeably. Either way, this typically refers to later stages of the software pipeline, and especially to how new code moves into production.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 1997 and has having 22 years in the market, Reapit is the largest CRM and Client Accounting software provider to the UK residential real estate sector. Reapit got acquired by Accel KKR in 2017 - which powered them to accelerate their growth and innovation potential in products and technology expansion Reapit wants to migrate the app from desktop-based to Cloud-based. They want to develop a PaaS to support an expandability for SME customer.</description></item><item><title>2020 In A Flashback</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2020-in-a-flashback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2020-in-a-flashback/</guid><description>Wrapping up 2019 with the first 5th-year milestone, many ideas popped up for the next steps. Heading to a new decade means we get to wrap up the old and in with the new. For us, the utmost target is to focus on territory expansion and team bootstrapping. Reinvest on the current foundation. Make it stable and make it impactful.
It handed us the chance to come up with more cool stuff.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Webflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/getting-started-with-webflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/getting-started-with-webflow/</guid><description>No-code platform has becoming a thing recently. With convenient and user-friendly workflow, no-code platform is a must to pick up for design and operation process, to shorten the development time and remove the misunderstanding between them with developers.
What is Webflow In short, Webflow is a web design tool, CMS, and hosting platform. Each aspect of the platform is represented by a particular product/feature set:
The Designer A visual web design tool firmly grounded in web standards and best practices, the Designer translates design decisions into clean, production-ready code.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</guid><description>Once every month, we gather for Radar update to round up the cool techs and assess if we should adopt that to the team. Road to a wider and more diversified rings, Dwarves Tech Radar v2 contains the practices to simplify the workflow, new techniques/ approach methods to upgrade our current standards, and **expand the domain knowledge. **
Trial Earthly: The combination Dockerfile + Makefile https://earthly.dev/
A repeatable syntax builds to untangle the debugging process between the local environment and the CI platform.</description></item><item><title>The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Aharooms wants to be a remarkable Vietnamese brand in franchised hotel chains. They look to enter the affordable hotel market to support business owners. Their vision was to build an MVP for market testing in no time. Aharooms&amp;rsquo;s system had almost 2 years in development. It demands high effort to balance new feature development with technical debt. We step in as product team and venture builder. We take on the development stage that supercharges their product development.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</guid><description>One of the factors that could make or break a project is the process of communication between designers and developers. Designers and developers have their own working “languages.”
It’s important to find a protocol in which a mutual language can bridge the gap between designers and developers. This protocol helps everyone in the team understand the ultimate objective of the project, minimize the guesswork, save time and effort, ensuring the high-quality standard outcomes we promised to deliver to clients.</description></item><item><title>Xpc Services On Macos App Using Swift</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/xpc-services-on-macos-app-using-swift/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/xpc-services-on-macos-app-using-swift/</guid><description>Before XPC we used to pick up Sockets and Mach Messages (Mach Ports).
XPC for communicating processes The XPC mechanism offers an alternative to sockets (or Mach Services using MIG) for IPC. We could have, for example, a process that acts as a “server” waiting for clients to access its API and provide some service.
XPC Services on applications When we talk about XPC Services (capital ‘S’), we are referring to the bundle called XPC Service.</description></item><item><title>The Correct Way To Build Kpi</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-correct-way-to-build-kpi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-correct-way-to-build-kpi/</guid><description>I have taken a week off from my office, packed up and headed to Dalat for a full-week meditation retreat. This method has been my sweet escape for the past 4 years, get-away from the chaotic pop-ups, notifications, messages, deadlines from work and normal life, to find the right balance for my energy and my mind as well. Yes, even meditation facilitators need their time to recover and enhance their vibes too.</description></item><item><title>A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</guid><description>In brief CJC Ptd is a 20-year expert in providing market data consultancy &amp;amp; professional services for global financial sector. They want to make a new data ecosystem: Public and private cloud, containerization, software orchestration, AI to support the growth of DevOps We team up with them to develop Voconic - a cloud PaaS for CJC’s clients, aiming to make cloud deployment seamless across cloud providers and environment. Technical Highlight Backend, Frontend and CLI tools are built from scratch by engineers specialized in Cloud development Golang heavy backend integrated with Google Cloud Platform for 1-click deployment experience Deep integration with multiple cloud providers (Google &amp;amp; AWS) Complex system auto-deployment and configuration function CLI support for repetitive tasks and complex operation Separated services for file upload.</description></item><item><title>Domain Insight Research Framework</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/domain-insight-research-framework/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/domain-insight-research-framework/</guid><description>As a designer working in the Digital Product industry, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we all hear about UX Research once at least. In this field, we learn about the business&amp;rsquo;s strategy, users&amp;rsquo; behaviors, needs, pain points, etc. to build a product that meets the business&amp;rsquo;s goal and solves users&amp;rsquo; existing problems. There are multiple ways to do UX research; our team also has one. However, there is a higher level, which helps UX Researchers process their works much faster, empathize with target users much easier, and save more effort and time; it is called Domain Insight Research.</description></item><item><title>Setting The Budget</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setting-the-budget/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setting-the-budget/</guid><description>One of the most important questions at the start of a project is how much it will cost. It is vital to make sure that enough budget is available to allow for the development of a viable product.
The difficulty with setting a budget at the start of a project is that everyone is at the point of maximum ignorance. At the beginning of a project, all of the requirements have not matured.</description></item><item><title>Asking As A Junior</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/asking-as-a-junior/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/asking-as-a-junior/</guid><description>Switching from schooling to the working world is not easy. New people, new culture, new workflow. The urge to learn quickly, prove one&amp;rsquo;s self, and build up self-worth.
Being a junior is where everyone once began. It&amp;rsquo;s the point where we start discovering things to learn and develop. And there comes a roadblock: When to raise a question?
But more importantly. Should or Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t? And how?
The Hesitation Of course, the upfront hesitance can fall into these three common thoughts.</description></item><item><title>Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</guid><description>In brief Founded by Desmond Goh - a Singaporean dental surgeon, Dental Marketplace is an online platform for dental professionals to stay active in dentistry and simplify operation process. Web and App development as MVP release for marketing testing and user feedback. We support them with tech solution and market-fit product design. We work according with Desmond to extract business problem and propose suitable solution. Technical Highlight Product-fit Design: Design Thinking Method &amp;amp; Design UX research for Golang-backend: Steady and microservices-extendable system Startup-centric: Scalable system &amp;amp; cost-efficient solution Microservice architecture Agile process and Scrum framework for product iteration The Context Singapore dentists faces bottlenecks to practice dentistry and operates dental clinic with SDC rules licensed regulated by MOH.</description></item><item><title>Infinite Image Gallery With R3f An Approach</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/infinite-image-gallery-with-r3f---an-approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/infinite-image-gallery-with-r3f---an-approach/</guid><description>As I was looking for inspiration on Awwwards, I came across this beautiful little site: Bien Joué. The site features an infinite image gallery in a 3D space, with some amazing WebGL effects on user interactions.
The infinite gallery fascinated me, and I wondered if I could re-implement the gallery-part with react-three-fiber. After some experiment &amp;amp; fumbling around, I was able to put out a small “demo-able” app:
DEMO****.</description></item><item><title>Go The Extra Mile</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-the-extra-mile/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-the-extra-mile/</guid><description>A couple days ago, I was asked if I were ever a product person, what would I do to make the best out of it.
It took me a while. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;ve never walked in this shoe before. Wth is a product person? I wondered. And I started digging. Here it is, &amp;ldquo;Making sure your product/ thing shipped out flawlessly.&amp;rdquo; A perfectionist mindset.
Sounds a bit crazy, yet a lil intrigued.</description></item><item><title>The Dwarves Runs By Ideas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-runs-by-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-runs-by-ideas/</guid><description>Minimal human intervention Our operations runs on four branches: Account for client happiness arrangement - PeopleOps for resource allocation - Human Resource for recruitment and employee experience, &amp;amp; Communication for info transmission across the platforms.
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit different from other operations flows out there. But we do it on purpose.
We figure a small team is easier to share perspectives, update on what&amp;rsquo;s happening and discuss different work aspects.</description></item><item><title>An Overview Of Micro Investment In Real Estate</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-overview-of-micro-investment-in-real-estate/</guid><description>How is the real estate market moving? When an industry begins this journey of digital transformation depends largely on the specific nature of its offering. As a rule of thumb, the more product-oriented and direct-to-customer an industry is, the sooner its digital transformation journey begins. The first important question is: why do industries go through this transformation process? What is the overall purpose? One common misconception is that fear is a major driver of transformation - the fear of being disrupted, the fear of becoming obsolete, the fear of losing out.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</guid><description>The Dwarves have their tradition to explore the tech scene and learn new things. Dwarves Tech Radar kicked the initial step since January of 2020.
It is the first time we sit down and do it in written form. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard for the engineers at first, but we managed to complete the volume with ten reports.
Besides volume 01, we have an opportunity to sort out our current technology index and put it at https://d.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</guid><description>Our Perspective on Technology Technology is eating the world. The technology we used yesterday may be deprecated today. New technology has enabled us to create new things. With the existing set of problems, new solutions will emerge along with new technologies.
Over five years of working as an innovative software firm, other than the energetic tech-savvy workforce, we shape the team day by day with the core values that move towards the engineering culture.</description></item><item><title>Grid And Layout</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/grid-and-layout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/grid-and-layout/</guid><description>To almost fresher who started in Graphic design and Digital design, who wants to make our model look beautiful and right. When we - fresher receive brief directly from the client or leader, we start to search online for ideas. Honestly, those projects look pretty good, super clean, and all you want is your project look the same way as them, but you just CAN’T. That’s because you don’t do the same way they did.</description></item><item><title>Go In Software Engineering</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-in-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-in-software-engineering/</guid><description>Go is a type-safe, cloud-native language designed for simplicity
with first-class support for concurrency.
The software community has been hungering for a small, simple, easy-to-learn and pragmatic programming language. Go fits the bill with:
Simplicity Go&amp;rsquo;s beauty lies in its powerful simplicity. A list of NO&amp;rsquo;s in Go design contains generics, ternary operation, pointer arithmetic,…. These features are missing because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit, and it affects compilation speed, and end up making the language too complicated.</description></item><item><title>A Tips Of Hiring Dont</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-tips-of-hiring-dont/</guid><description>Many companies out there get lured by the vision of &amp;ldquo;scaling up&amp;rdquo;. An unwritten rule of &amp;rsquo;the more man we have, the better output we create&amp;rsquo;. But no, hiring with no motivation only leads to one thing: A waste of resource.
Hire without plan bored talent people out. There&amp;rsquo;s no good to put people in a place where they can&amp;rsquo;t create any impact. And we? We tend to fall for creating unnecessary job, which results in a waste of money and training resource.</description></item><item><title>The Dwarves Culture Handbook</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-dwarves-culture-handbook/</guid><description>For the past 5 years, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have something called &amp;lsquo;Culture Book&amp;rsquo;. Whenever a newbie steps in, it&amp;rsquo;s natural to pick up the job and go with the flow. We hardly force them into other periodical office traps like team-bonding activities or late night drinks. It&amp;rsquo;s likely to be &amp;lsquo; Hey it&amp;rsquo;s your birthday give us a treat&amp;rsquo;; and next thing you know, 30 milk tea or coffee orders are on the way.</description></item><item><title>Startups Vs Junior Designers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startups-vs-junior-designers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startups-vs-junior-designers/</guid><description>Now, before you throw bricks at me for hindering the opportunities for new aspiring designers to &amp;ldquo;explore the world&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;m a designer myself, and I stand by my community. I write this not just for startup founders. I write this also for designers to make better judgments before deciding to join a startup environment.
This might upset us designers, but reality hurts, and truths need to be told. Toughen up, read through and you might find me probably know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.</description></item><item><title>Fixed Budget Scope Controlled</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fixed-budget-scope-controlled/</guid><description>Fixed-Budget, Scope-Controlled (FBSC) is applied at Atomic Object. They build custom software for our customers. Because of the complexity involved in building a great software product, software development projects are always more difficult to price than a product.
﻿
As a result two different strategies for pricing services, such as building software, have traditionally been used by most companies. These are called “Fixed Price” and “Time And Materials”.
Fixed Price A Fixed Price strategy locks in the total price of the project upfront.</description></item><item><title>Gestalt Principles In Ui Design</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/gestalt-principles-in-ui-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/gestalt-principles-in-ui-design/</guid><description>Take a second to look at the image above. How do you feel? Do you see that it is similar to an owl face? The answer to this phenomenon is called Isomorphism which is part of the 12 Gestalt rules. Just like Isomorphism, you will sometimes feel that a cloud is similar to a horse or a branding logo which is created by different shapes that can finally turn out to be a meaning object.</description></item><item><title>The Adjacent Possible</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-adjacent-possible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-adjacent-possible/</guid><description>During our study about innovation, we find the topic of adjacent possible. Innovation happens but not many people can point out clearly. Getting to know the foundation of innovation helps understanding its natures and could lead to further exploration. Enjoy your reading.
Innovation deepens our knowledge and understanding of the world, it extends our reach and access to resources. More importantly, innovation expands the realm of what we can do with all our knowledge and resources: deliver new goods and products, bring forward new types of organisations and services, and in more general terms develop new ideas and concepts.</description></item><item><title>Aarrr Framework In A Nutshell</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/aarrr-framework-in-a-nutshell/</guid><description>We could find a bunch of AARRR frameworks definition across the internet (Thanks to Google). I don’t intend to create another one here.
Today I just want to share the simplest definition of this framework and how we have done here at Dwarves. It is a jumping-off point to brainstorming what AARRR does, and why it’s the important step that needs to be done.
What is AARRR framework by the way AARRR is a revenue-driven funnel, what makes it different than other funnels?</description></item><item><title>How People Matter Should Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-people-matter-should-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-people-matter-should-work/</guid><description>We get to read many articles these days that states &amp;lsquo;People are the Core of the Business&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;Why People are the Key to Success&amp;rsquo;, or something like that. Something that polishes the importance of human to the company. Something that emphasizes how HR should do their best to nurture the talents.
But here&amp;rsquo;s the funny thing. Most of those talks drive the audience back to tips. How to make people happy.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Intro To Webassembly</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-quick-intro-to-webassembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-quick-intro-to-webassembly/</guid><description>If you haven’t heard of WebAssembly yet, then you will soon. It’s one of the industry’s best-kept secrets, but it’s everywhere. It’s supported by all the major browsers, and it’s coming to the server-side, too. It’s fast. It’s being used for gaming. It’s an open standard from the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), the main international standards organization for the web.
Format Definition WebAssembly (abbreviated Wasm) is a binary instruction format for a stack-based virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>Delegation And Believe It Will Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegation-and-believe-it-will-work/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t always make things (or everything) on our own. If that somehow truly happens, then Inc, Corp, Enterprise or Group won&amp;rsquo;t stand a chance with Freelancers.
So why delegating? At least, in business, delegation means having extra people to help distribute the stress, provides a gathered source of information, and a couple of extra hands to slap when our thought goes wrong. Delegation also gives delegator more time &amp;amp; effort to focus on other things, or sometimes just a perfect excuse to grab a beer instead of burying their heads in the sand.</description></item><item><title>Constructive Feedback</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/constructive-feedback/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/constructive-feedback/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s in human nature to instantly lose their mind when things get hard, and somehow they split nasty things that can&amp;rsquo;t be undone. So, to reduce the ratio of unnecessary conflicts, let&amp;rsquo;s make the feedback great again.
Know the Time Define the frame for listening and for questioning. Talk blocking isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to express how you feel. If you don&amp;rsquo;t respect other&amp;rsquo;s time of present, they have no reason to give a shit about what you think on their idea.</description></item><item><title>Transparency</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/transparency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/transparency/</guid><description>***How much do you know about this woodland?*** → is the question we all get during the first interview. Sure, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to nail the final offer; you&amp;rsquo;re likely to get a better chance on gradually discovering the company&amp;rsquo;s essential information.
But then what?
You step on the project. You get swiped away in work. You check up the daily to-do. And you have no idea what&amp;rsquo;s happening in other places.</description></item><item><title>Sdk Event Sourcing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sdk-event-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sdk-event-sourcing/</guid><description>Software Development Kit (SDK) SDK stands for Software Development Kit: the tools and software to develop application through a specific platform. SDK provides libraries, document, templates, code sample, debugging, supportive documentation or additional document for developers to integrate into their software/ application. SDK can also be a combination of many APIs under the form of libraries to interact with the operating system.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a cellphone for an example. Every cellphone has an operating system with programmed API, and many underlying connected libraries.</description></item><item><title>Software Development Life Cycle 101</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/software-development-life-cycle-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/software-development-life-cycle-101/</guid><description>This workshop contains the basic knowledge on Software Development Life Cycle, provides people with a step-to-step guideline and the artifacts which will be created on the way. We don&amp;rsquo;t dive in the details. Instead, we treat it as an overview look on how to build software successfully.
Table of Content What is Software Project? Software Development Life Cycle SDLC Models What is Software Project? We build software, and we need a planned undertaking.</description></item><item><title>Introduce To Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/introduce-to-dwarves-memo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/introduce-to-dwarves-memo/</guid><description>Every company has a story. We just decide to have more than one.
As the years go by, our stories get piled up. A story of how we build a team from scratch. A story of how we live, how we work, or how we survive the first milestone and get ready for the next chapter.
The purpose of every story is to bring the audience a little closer to the author, to feel related at some kind of level.</description></item><item><title>Daemons And Services Programming Guide</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/daemons-and-services-programming-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/daemons-and-services-programming-guide/</guid><description>About Daemons and Services Many kinds of tasks that do not require user interaction are most effectively handled by a process that runs in the background. You can use a daemon or service to:
Provide server functionality, such serving web pages. Coordinate access to of a shared resource, such as a database. Perform work for a foreground application, such as file system access.
Terminology Note: The terms service and daemon have several meanings in different contexts, with further variation over time and from one development community to another.</description></item><item><title>Remote Moderated Usability Testing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-moderated-usability-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-moderated-usability-testing/</guid><description>Intro It&amp;rsquo;s a given that the Usability Test is one of the most fundamental undertakings in building a product, which assists with approving the product before launching, reducing effort, and money. Notwithstanding, in the Covid-19 pandemic, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to direct a convenience testing up close and personal. Many agencies, including Dwarves Design, are new to the remote testing methods. During the last Work From Home session, our team had an opportunity to make a remote moderated usability testing, although it was the very first time we try this method, the testing went smoothly and we really had an interesting experiment.</description></item><item><title>An Alternative To Tm</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-alternative-to-tm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/an-alternative-to-tm/</guid><description>Vendors may use the phrase &amp;ldquo;time and materials&amp;rdquo; (T&amp;amp;M) to describe how they engage in projects and invoice their clients.
The phrase t&amp;amp;m has been laid to rest at Atomic for several reasons. First, the phrase doesn’t accurately describe how we engage with our clients. At Atomic, we certainly don’t work without profit. And we have an innate desire to be more efficient.
T&amp;amp;M is an inaccurate way of describing our business relationships and ignores a lot of other work we do.</description></item><item><title>How A Design System Work</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-a-design-system-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-a-design-system-work/</guid><description>This talk is created from my experiences &amp;amp; lesson learnt, the rule and self-code I&amp;rsquo;ve built and believe to be applicable. So I can guarantee you may not find some of it in any other places on the internet.
Table of Content Color Style &amp;amp; Text Style Naming Convention Component Naming Convention &amp;amp; Component Structure Auto Layout Application Description of Design System Naming Convention Color Style Naming Convention There are 2 types of color: Flat &amp;amp; Gradient.</description></item><item><title>Software Modeling</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/software-modeling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/software-modeling/</guid><description>Agenda Why do we need Software Modeling What is Software Modeling How to do Software Modeling This is how I approach a new topic or knowledge, starts with why, understand the concept and figure out how to make it happen.
Why do we need Software Modeling This can be summed up into 2 definitions:
Maintainability: Software Modeling helps to maintain a system, or a project. It ensures the based document for newbies to approach and get to know the system thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Reusability In Software Development</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/reusability-in-software-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/reusability-in-software-development/</guid><description>Introduction In the previous century, when the software market was also immature, the economy was grown with a large scale lead to more and more new business problems appear that demands software to solve such as management, automatic. So a lot of new ideas about software were imagined and implement from the roots to resolve the corresponding matter. Because of this original, the reuse of software was uncommon.
Nowadays, after a long time for deeping in building something new to solve classic problems.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain For Designers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blockchain-for-designers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blockchain-for-designers/</guid><description>Intro Recently, Bitcoin and Blockchain become popular, they are the trending and media’s favorite topics. Blockchain is buzzing with the capability of solving trust issues in not only the technology but also other domains like economies and even government regulators. Though people are talking about this promising technology, it’s too complicated for everyone to understand what precisely it is and how it works. The complexity of Blockchain and what it does make users feel confused and suspicious, which builds a huge barrier between users and products.</description></item><item><title>Design Better Mobile Application</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-better-mobile-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-better-mobile-application/</guid><description>This workshop wraps up the useful information on 2 types of operating system for UX/UI designers, based on the personal research on iOS and Android. The purpose is to create an application that brings comfortability and a great experience to the end user.
Table of Content Introduction to iOS &amp;amp; Android The platforms to build application Useful tips to create an effective mobile application Introduction to iOS &amp;amp; Android Adjustment &amp;amp; Privacy iOS has better privacy protection since it belongs exclusively to iOS, but this leads to the limitation of function adjustment.</description></item><item><title>Introduction To Software Craftsmanship</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/introduction-to-software-craftsmanship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/introduction-to-software-craftsmanship/</guid><description>Craftsmanship has been our motto since the first day. But to the newbies and even some current Dwarves, the real definition of software craftsmanship is still vague, or being understood in different ways.
Most of us have been working in software industry for a long time. For newbies, it might be unfamiliar to catch up the term of Craftsmanship and how it is applied into our industry. So to make sure everyone is on the same page &amp;amp; using the same brush, this talk aims to cover our point of view on this term and why it matters that much to land a seat on our core values.</description></item><item><title>Domain Glossary</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/domain-glossary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/domain-glossary/</guid><description>T1: Retail 2.0 Definition
Enhancing consumer engagement within brick and mortar - online/using mobile devices, moving beyond simply blending in the online and the mobile experience, all driven at the heart by sophisticated big data tools that truly enable contextual, personalized and real-time conversations between brands, retailers and consumers. [1] Made up of AR (augmented reality), VR (virtual reality), in-store apps, new payment methods and artificial intelligence. Personalized Exp Designing or producing services and products to meet customer&amp;rsquo;s individual requirements.</description></item><item><title>Bric A Brac</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bric-a-brac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bric-a-brac/</guid><description> Outsource things which are super important but we are not excellent at. Spend time selecting a vendor and occasionally spend time reevaluating other vendors. Automate repetitive tasks. Give everyone &amp;ldquo;admin&amp;rdquo; access to as much as possible to avoid bottlenecks. Our problems are not unique. We will try manual processes first. When we do build something, it is usually after using other things for years</description></item><item><title>Architecture Decision Record</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</guid><description>There is an issue that every team will inevitably bump into. Newbies might get confused when a project is being developed. They wonder how that code was written, how we ended up choosing that architecture. It somehow leads to finger-point, and even the decision-maker himself can&amp;rsquo;t remember how that decision was taken.
That happens in a long-term project, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. We believe we&amp;rsquo;re not the only one who gets that, so we&amp;rsquo;d like to gather you all and tackle this today by a practice called Architecture Decision Record (ADR)</description></item><item><title>Build An Assistant On The Terminal</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/build-an-assistant-on-the-terminal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/build-an-assistant-on-the-terminal/</guid><description>Introduction When coding, developers look for references constantly. &amp;ldquo;What does this snippet of code do?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;How to implement something in this programming language?&amp;rdquo;, etc. According to the StackOverflow blog[1], the page itself saw more than 9 billion page views in 2019. There is also an unrecorded amount of views on other developer blogs and tutorials online. That was an enormous amount of developers searching for supports.
Terminal assistant is a tool that brings the supports that developers searching for to your terminal.</description></item><item><title>Account</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/account/</guid><description>Planning
Many people would say in order to have a good plan; you need to write out all vibrant details. A good plan needs lots of details, they said. But in real life, where nothing is certain and is filled with sudden surprises, a good plan should prioritize its flexibility and simplicity.
Start with the main goals of the week, then expand on the actual required actions to achieve those desired goals.</description></item><item><title>Create Circular Text Using Swiftui</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/create-circular-text-using-swiftui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/create-circular-text-using-swiftui/</guid><description>This is what we have when finished.
Fire up your Xcode and create new SwiftUI Project.
Create new SwiftUI file and named it CircularText.
The first two attributes for our control of course is String and Radius for our circular.
Add 2 Attribute named
To make a circle text we split out string to array of character, each character will have it own Text control then we going to rotate the text to match circle.</description></item><item><title>Draw Watch Face Using Swiftui</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/draw-watch-face-using-swiftui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/draw-watch-face-using-swiftui/</guid><description>SwiftUI are nice and fun to working with. You can read my previous article to get a bit knowledge about create circular control, it will make you easy to working with this article. This article also use Shape and Path, if you have worked with CoreGraphic before you will find it similar With CALayer, CAShapeLayer and UIBezierPath.
Create Circular Text using SwiftUI
First of all, let split watch to small components for easy coding.</description></item><item><title>Avoid Burn Out</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/avoid-burn-out/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/avoid-burn-out/</guid><description>Just to be clear, this term has nothing to compare with the emotional crisis you go through daily - stress. No, burn-out isn&amp;rsquo;t stress.
It describes the state of physical and emotional exhaustion. Burnout reduces and sucks out your productivity. As it develops, it beats every single reason that once was your working motto. The interest, the creativity and motivation gets faded away. Your job might be done, but you no longer feel satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Applied Security Basis</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applied-security-basis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/applied-security-basis/</guid><description>Security plays a vital role in software, maybe in any field of work. But when the coverage of software expands, the importance of security gets taken for granted, as it&amp;rsquo;s embed and supported in frameworks and other low-level layers of the tech stacks. Hence, developers tend to spend time on the top-level layers. They buy in the fact that frameworks and libraries solve security issues. Consequently, security stays in a black box.</description></item><item><title>Writing Management Objectives In Smart</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/writing-management-objectives-in-smart/</guid><description>S.M.A.R.T. goals are a relatively new idea. In 1981, George T. Doran, a consultant and former director of corporate planning for Washington Water Power Company, published a paper called, “There’s a S.M.A.R.T. Way to Write Management’s Goals and Objectives.” In the document, he introduces S.M.A.R.T. goals as a tool to create criteria to help improve the chances of succeeding in accomplishing a goal
S – Specific When setting a goal, be specific about what you want to accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Building A Solid High Performing Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-a-solid-high-performing-team/</guid><description>Sustainable growth companies are built by teams of shining constellations rather than just several bright stars
It all starts with recruiting. Many successes and disasters start with recruiting. Recruiting is the most important job for any real leader in the company
The second step is all about the right placement of the stars in your constellation. No matter what bullshit motivational book you may have read, people do not change. Yes, people do evolve, and yes, those not capable of evolution should never become a part of your team, but for Pete’s sake, do not confuse skill evolution with personality change.</description></item><item><title>Swiftui</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/swiftui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/swiftui/</guid><description>Introduces by Apple in WWDC 2019, Swift UI impressed the technophiles with its convenience, as Apple aimed to help developers conduct code easier and spend more time working on other modified functions. This blog outlines my opinion about SwiftUI, such as how to layout views, handle user input, making a custom view, making a cross Apple platform apps, underlying architecture, integrate with UIKit (the old Apple UI framework). It won&amp;rsquo;t be expanded on an advanced level like fancy animation or proposing any best architecture we should follow.</description></item><item><title>Bunk License Check</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bunk-license-check/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bunk-license-check/</guid><description>License detector tool: Glice Golang license and dependency checker. Prints list of all dependencies (both from std and 3rd party), number of times used, their license and saves all the license files in /licenses.
Build Clone Glice to your local workspace: $go get github.com/ribice/glice Go install to your $GOBIN: $ go install github.com/ribice/glice Run $ glice</description></item><item><title>Hiring For Operations Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-for-operations-team/</guid><description>Operations is a very sensitive area of the company, so be very picky. A great ops person can dramatically improve the way your company works and make your life a lot easier
Operations is operations, no matter the industry
Operations problems are almost the same everywhere (in ultra-specialized and regulated industries we just surround ourselves with specialists and attorneys). Industry experience is helpful, but not as much as you think</description></item><item><title>Looking Back 2019</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/looking-back-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/looking-back-2019/</guid><description>Another year has gone by. And we just celebrated the 5th year that we survived all the challenges. Everyone was facing their own, but I have seen many of you reaching new stages and achieve new targets.
We have been growing up together. As for your recall, end of 2018, we were about 30s. End of this year, we are about 50s. End of 2018, we were young and inexperienced. End of this year, we are just inexperienced (j/k).</description></item><item><title>Well Crafted Software</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/well-crafted-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/well-crafted-software/</guid><description>This post ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna be a speech of Uncle Bob&amp;rsquo;s Software Craftsmanship Manifesto. We&amp;rsquo;ve all known that. And to people who don&amp;rsquo;t, for God&amp;rsquo;s sake. Google.
Well crafted software means that regardless how old the application is, developers can understand it easily, side effects are well known and controlled, high test coverage, clean design, business language well expressed in the code and adding or changing features does not take longer than it used to take at the beginning of the project when the codebase was small.</description></item><item><title>Objective</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/objective/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/objective/</guid><description>Operating a company is not much different from operating a machine or a system. The company has departments and people working together towards a goal as a car has many components connected by gears moving towards a destination.
The ultimate objective of operations is making sure the gears rolling smoothly and the car always move forward without any glitch.</description></item><item><title>Project Management</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/project-management/</guid><description>A Project Manager (PM) job starts right after a new project has been sealed and assigned with a starting date, a deadline and a Team. As a PM it is absolutely fundamental you are an expert about our working methodologies, processes and communication
Be organised
Keep everything neat and things where they are supposed to be. Being organised and keeping track of everything will make your life much easier.
Create tasks and document them straight away.</description></item><item><title>Go Concurrency</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-concurrency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/go-concurrency/</guid><description>Golang concurrency When we talk about Golang, its most basic and popular characteristic is concurrency-support. Unlike other languages what is quite complex to build an concurrency system, Go concurrency primitives via Goroutines and channels make concurrent programming easy. So i am going to talk about Goroutines and similar things in other programming languages.
Firstly, we need to know Go is a concurrent language and not a parallel one. So what is the difference from concurrency and parallelism?</description></item><item><title>Delegate Work Not Responsibility</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/delegate-work-not-responsibility/</guid><description>We can bring in all the technology in the world, but if we can’t delegate properly, our companies have no chance of scaling well
Delegating work does not absolve you of responsibility. In the case of a failure, the blame is all yours. Investors will go after the CEO, even if an intern made the mistake that hurt the company. If a failure occurs due to person you delegated work to lacking skills, it is your fault you delegated work to the wrong person.</description></item><item><title>Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</guid><description>In brief Getting the early funding for over 40M US dollar, beGroup focuses to roll out all 4 products by the end of 2018. By that time, there were only 6 months before the debut. beCorporate is a module to manage and optimize in-house business transports for employee.
They look to ship in short timeline. The current engineering team was working on the 1st release of ride-hailing app. Wrap-up beCorporate adds a step in perfecting their service.</description></item><item><title>Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</guid><description>In brief AirWatt is an IoT solution that integrates and monitors electricity usage using AI/ML. AirWatt&amp;rsquo;s vision is to help businesses track electric usage status of electrical equipment. Hence, they can save electricity and money, even avoid disaster. They seek for product development support, with insight on business to provide suitable product design The MVP must be done fast to prove the product&amp;rsquo;s concept. We built Airwatt system from zero with other teams: Business, Hardware, and AI.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Helm 101</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/kubernetes-helm-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/kubernetes-helm-101/</guid><description>In recent years, Kubernetes has exploded tremendously. At the same time, it creates new communities including ecosystems that make it easier to develop and deploy complex applications. If Kubernetes means the shipman of the ship, then Helm is the steering wheel of that shipman in the career of every DevOps and Developer.
Helm is a Package Manager for Kubernetes, analogous to NPM or YARN. However, it’s not just the Package Manager, it is also a Deployment Management for Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>What Is Kubernetes</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-is-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/what-is-kubernetes/</guid><description>What is Kubernetes Kubernetes is a portable, extensible, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation. It has a large, rapidly growing ecosystem. Kubernetes services, support, and tools are widely available.
Traditional Deployment Era Early on, organizations ran applications on physical servers. There was no way to define resource boundaries for applications in a physical server, and this caused resource allocation issues. For example, if multiple applications run on a physical server, there can be instances where one application would take up most of the resources, and as a result, the other applications would underperform.</description></item><item><title>Traits To Assess During An Interview</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/traits-to-assess-during-an-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/traits-to-assess-during-an-interview/</guid><description>GRIT: Look for a time the candidate wanted something so badly, they were unstoppable in pursuing it. Or a time they overcame an obstacle. RIGOR: Ask candidates to tell you about a time they used data to make a decision. Look for details about the complexity of the data and how the thinking happened, rather than focusing on the right answer IMPACT: Have your candidate tell you about a time they had a measurable (read: quantitative) impact on a job or an organization.</description></item><item><title>Recursively Export File Pattern In Javascript Es6 Application</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/recursively-export-file-pattern-in-javascript-es6-application/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/recursively-export-file-pattern-in-javascript-es6-application/</guid><description>Introduction Imagine you have a lot of components and you imported it like this:
Instead of importing component like above. You would want to import your components like this:
The pros of this style are
Your project structure now grouped into multiple namespaces. You can image It’s like C# namespace. Each namespace is a root folder in our project. Don’t have to remember exactly path of your components. The cons are</description></item><item><title>Playaround With Clojure</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-clojure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-clojure/</guid><description>Definition Clojure is a dynamic, general-purpose programming language, combining the approachability and interactive development of a scripting language with an efficient and robust infrastructure for multithreaded programming. Clojure is a compiled language, yet remains completely dynamic – every feature supported by Clojure is supported at runtime. Clojure provides easy access to the Java frameworks, with optional type hints and type inference, to ensure that calls to Java can avoid reflection.</description></item><item><title>Playaround With Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-rust/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-rust/</guid><description>Mozilla intends to use Rust as a platform for prototyping experimental browser architectures.
Specifically, the hope is to develop a browser that is more amenable to safe and parallel than the existing ones, while also being less prone to common C++ coding errors.
What makes Rust special Ownership Each value in Rust has a variable that&amp;rsquo;s called its owner, there can only be one owner at a time When the owner goes out of scope, the value will be dropped Variable scope is a range within a program for which an item is valid Let’s take this example:</description></item><item><title>Overview On Broker Pattern In Distributed System</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/overview-on-broker-pattern-in-distributed-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/overview-on-broker-pattern-in-distributed-system/</guid><description>Definition The broker pattern is an architectural pattern that can be used to structure distributed software systems with decoupled components that interact by remote procedure calls. A broker component is responsible for coordinating communication, such as forwarding requests, as well as for transmitting results and exceptions.
Component Clients: implements user functionality, send requests to server through a client-side proxy Server: Implements services, registers itself with the local broker, send responses and exceptions back the client through a server-side proxy Broker(a messenger that is responsible for the transmission of requests from clients to servers): registers server, offers interface(APIs, &amp;hellip;), transfer messages, error recovery, interoperates with other brokers through bridges, locates servers Client-side proxy(a layer between clients and the broker): encapsulates system-specific functionality, mediates between the client and the broker Server-side proxy: calls services within the server, encapsulates system-specific functionality, mediates between server and the broker Bridge( responsible for communication among brokers): encapsulates network-specific functionality, mediates between the local broker and the bridge of a remote broker The role of Broker Patter Our system need to be dynamically removing or adding new agent(server, client) The agents in our system need the ability to be independent of each other( scalable, partition functionality into independent agents) The ability of Broker Pattern In the decoupled behavior, Broker acts like an interface, when a new server was adding on the system, it just like add a new object, and the only thing we need to do is to register the new server with Broker.</description></item><item><title>Using Correct Html Element To Increase Website Accessibility</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/using-correct-html-element-to-increase-website-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/using-correct-html-element-to-increase-website-accessibility/</guid><description>Website Accessibility Website Accessibility is a term for approaching a website of which the potential user are people with disabilities (eye disorders or illiterate). This audience type can’t be able to approach a visualize website. They must depend on keyboard or Screen Reader supporting tool instead.
Website Accessibility is also a factor to evaluate the website quality of Google Lighthouse. Developers can enhance the accessibility of a website by categorizing the current elements, as long as the reader system can identify and have those elements delivered to readers.</description></item><item><title>Fundamental End To End Frontend Testing With Cypress</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fundamental-end-to-end-frontend-testing-with-cypress/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fundamental-end-to-end-frontend-testing-with-cypress/</guid><description>Introduction End-to-end testing is a methodology used to test whether the flow of an application is performing as designed from start to finish. It’s like testing as a user perspective and not involve thing like assert internal code state or mock… etc
Cypress is an e2e testing framework that offers simplicity API and performant test runner https://www.cypress.io/
Application being tested The application that we are going to test against is autocomplete textbox.</description></item><item><title>Uidynamicanimator</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/uidynamicanimator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/uidynamicanimator/</guid><description>Definition A dynamic item is any iOS or custom object that conforms to the UIDynamicItem protocol. The UIView and UICollectionViewLayoutAttributes classes implement this protocol in iOS 7 and later. You can implement this protocol to use a dynamic animator with custom objects for such purposes as reacting to rotation or position changes computed by an animator.
To use dynamics, configure one or more dynamic behaviors—including providing each with a set of dynamic items—and then add those behaviors to a dynamic animator.</description></item><item><title>Reproduce Apple Find Me Bottom Menu View</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/reproduce-apple-find-me-bottom-menu-view/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/reproduce-apple-find-me-bottom-menu-view/</guid><description>Today we are going to recreate Find Me Bottom Menu view in few lines of code.
Device list Bottom Menu has three states: Collapsed, HalfExpanded and Expanded like images below
What we should do:
Bottom View can update itself height follow user finger position when dragging (Pan Gesture) Bottom View can automatically resize its height base on the direction of dragging and position compare to “half position” Create an XCode project, add a new UIView and named it to BottomMenuView.</description></item><item><title>Build A Passcode View With Swift</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/build-a-passcode-view-with-swift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/build-a-passcode-view-with-swift/</guid><description>The highlights before we are write our code.
Our Passcode view can “becomeFirstResponder” and “resignFirstResponder” to show and hide virtual keyboard if needed. =&amp;gt; Our Passcode nearly same with TextField.
Define our passcode view:
By default, to show keyboard on the screen user should touch in TextField or TextView to edit. We can make our custom view as keyboard input view by override “canBecomeFirstReponder” method and conform to UIKeyInput Protocol</description></item><item><title>Istio</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/istio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/istio/</guid><description>Istio is an implementation of the Service mesh architecture, which is a network of microservices that interactive with each other to form an application. Besides Istio, there are several concept applying service mesh architecture such as Linkerd, Consul.
Service mesh vs API gateway Service mesh has been really a hot term recently, comparing to another microservice architecture, API gateway, which is considered simpler and a more mature solution. Therefore before digging into Istio, it is necessary to have a comparison between Service mesh and API gateway, to find out the pros/cons and the use case of each architecture, thus have a better overview for Istio.</description></item><item><title>Different Ways To Test React Application</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/different-ways-to-test-react-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/different-ways-to-test-react-application/</guid><description>Introduction There are 2 practical types of testing a front end application: test its implementation details (unit test, integration test combine with assert states of the component being tested) or testing its behavior base on perspective (e2e, integration test).
The content below assumes you already know about React hook (which is a new feature of React 16.08)
This is a repository link: https://github.com/phmngocnghia/TestReactComponent
This repository contains source code for the carousel component which we gonna test.</description></item><item><title>Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</guid><description>Introduction BHD is one of the biggest cinema chains in Vietnam with hundreds of thousands tickets sold monthly. However, its mobile application is a complete drawback; users cannot book tickets online, it feels and looks outdated, inconsistent and cluttered.
Mission BHD’s new app covers all the basic needs of movie-goers, in an intuitive and pleasant way. Meaning, users can easily scan screening schedules, view movie details and book tickets online.</description></item><item><title>Federated Byzantine</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/federated-byzantine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/federated-byzantine/</guid><description>Stellar is all about trust (validators). After all, when you have to trust somebody, you&amp;rsquo;d trust the reputated nodes, rather than a random stranger node on the internet.
You can imagine Quorum as a list of validators. Every Stellar node has its chosen validators in its own Quorum. For new nodes (e.g. by domestic users like me), we tend to choose the official/reputated nodes (e.g. nodes at SDF/IBM) to trust / to be the validators in our Quorum.</description></item><item><title>Fabric Hyperledger Architecture Explanation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fabric-hyperledger-architecture-explanation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/fabric-hyperledger-architecture-explanation/</guid><description>What is Hyperledger Hyperledger is an open source community focused on developing a suite of stable frameworks, tools and libraries for enterprise-grade blockchain deployments.
It serves as a neutral home for various distributed ledger frameworks including Hyperledger Fabric, Sawtooth, Indy, as well as tools like Hyperledger Caliper and libraries like Hyperledger Ursa.
Key concept of Blockchain in Hyperledger A Distributed Ledger Records all the transactions that take place on the network</description></item><item><title>Setup React Project With Webpack And Babel</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setup-react-project-with-webpack-and-babel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/setup-react-project-with-webpack-and-babel/</guid><description>Introduction create-react-app is an official CLI to create react application sometime you need to customize it such as add an alias or add plugin babel config, you end up ejected.
In this article, i’m going to demonstrate how to create simple webpack config to run react app. After reading this article, you will be able to create your own react webpack config and tweak it as you liked
Setup projects First you need to config three file such as:</description></item><item><title>Split And Reuse Code In React Application</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/split-and-reuse-code-in-react-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/split-and-reuse-code-in-react-application/</guid><description>Introduction Sometimes you found that some piece of code that is very repetitive in your react application such as:
Modal: declare modal state and function to set modal state Fetch: declare fetch states such as loading and error In some Vue.js, you got the feature that allows you to encapsulate state and methods into the package that you can easily insert to your component logic called mixins. What have we got in React.</description></item><item><title>Hoc Renderprops And Hook In Reactjs</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hoc-renderprops-and-hook-in-reactjs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hoc-renderprops-and-hook-in-reactjs/</guid><description>Introduction HOC, Render-props, hook are different techniques to create reusable or composable logic in React.js.
Take a look at the use case where we have a button to toggle the visibility of some text:
import React, { Component } from 'react'; class App extends Component { constructor() { super() this.state = { isTextABCVisbible: true } } togggleTextABC = () =&amp;gt; { this.setState((state) =&amp;gt;({ isTextABCVisbible: !state.isTextABCVisbible })) } render() { return ( &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;App&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;button onClick={this.</description></item><item><title>Resource Assignment</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/resource-assignment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/resource-assignment/</guid><description>With the nature of consulting team, one member could be assigned to multiple projects at once or handle the work of a member in one project that take more than 100% of his/her time per week.
Based on the Quality Software Management book of Gerald Weinberg, the resource context switching cost is shown as below:
The column &amp;ldquo;Loss to Context Switching&amp;rdquo; is a total loss for your productivity. Therefore, one person should only be assigned to maximum 3 projects at the same time, and the total working hour of that person should NOT exceed 120% (meaning not more than 12 hours per day).</description></item><item><title>Remove Unused Css Styles From Bootstrap Using Purgecss</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remove-unused-css-styles-from-bootstrap-using-purgecss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remove-unused-css-styles-from-bootstrap-using-purgecss/</guid><description>Introduction Reducing assets size is one of the most practical ways to speed up your web application. I have a simple use case, lets imagine your HTML file looks like this
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;X-UA-Compatible&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;ie=edge&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Bootstrap&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;./bootstrap-grid.min.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-sm-4&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.col-sm-4&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-sm-4&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.col-sm-4&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-sm-4&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.col-sm-4&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; Now look at
bootstrap-grid.min.css Quite huge isn’t it?</description></item><item><title>2018 Wrapping Up</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2018-wrapping-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/2018-wrapping-up/</guid><description>2018 was the memorable year with lots of achievements.
We adapted the new team structure.
We defined things we value and live that culture tediously.
We moved to new office. We welcomed the new dwarves to join us.
We scaled up from 15 to 30ish with all the smart people gathering around and commit to the dream of building our first global software company.
We learned how to do things right and started using it to help deliver quality software.</description></item><item><title>The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-2/</guid><description>1. Vertical spacing Spacing within each paragraph Firstly, I start the simplest content type — paragraph. One of the atoms decides aesthetic design. So you need to focus on them. You commonly depend on default line-height of the font to design the content. I have increased line by 2px to 3px in this way because they are too tight.
Everything almost has a proportional so line-height also it. 1.5 is a suggestion for you to have a good starting point.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</guid><description>Introduction The following case study is my first app design project. In this project, I have gone through the design process, including interviews, analysis, user flows, wireframes, prototyping, and user testing.
The mobile app Sol is a travel app focused on some highlight features: planning trips, managing members and expenses, and tracking/sharing location. In facts, when traveling by groups, we often face some troubles: getting lost, confusing with plans, hard-communicating and the most challenging thing: managing expenses.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</guid><description>Introduction Today we shall continue our series of designing “Sol-Travel Planning” app. As we mentioned our process on UX research and UI design in the last two articles, Sol’s target users are the young so keeping the app fun with interaction is a must.
Main Motions According to Issara Willenskomer from UxinMotion, motion implementation in UX design can greatly help improving usability in four noticeable ways: fulfilling expectation from the users, maintaining continuity among a set of scenes, inventing narrative — story-telling flow throughout the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</guid><description>Following the previous article on UX case study of Sol — Travel App, an app that was tailored to meet the needs of groups on traveling days. In this article, we will describe our creative process of the UI for it. We choose iOS as our platform to be presented, considering that it is the more favored devices being used.
As we have gone through the UX research tasks in the last article, we started brainstorming about how the mobile application should look.</description></item><item><title>Finite State Machine</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/finite-state-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/finite-state-machine/</guid><description>A Finite State Machine is a model of computation based on a hypothetical machine made of one or more states. Only one single state of this machine can be active at the same time. It means the machine has to transition from one state to another in to perform different actions
Above image is a simple FSM, each circle is a state and arrow is an event or action.
Pros and Cons Pros</description></item><item><title>Card Sorting And A Glimpse At Experimental Sorting Session</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/card-sorting-and-a-glimpse-at-experimental-sorting-session/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/card-sorting-and-a-glimpse-at-experimental-sorting-session/</guid><description>As part of our team’s weekly activities is a knowledge sharing session. So, in this article I’d like to share a UX technique we practiced recently — Card Sorting.
And plus, a real lesson learned with our team’s workshop.
A brief intro to Card Sorting Definition Card sorting is a method used to help design or evaluate the information architecture of a site and broader a digital product (web-app and mobile app).</description></item><item><title>Types Of Employees</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/types-of-employees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/types-of-employees/</guid><description>There are 2 types of employees:
There are employees who think of the company like a job. They come in, they work hard, and they do their job. Some excel at doing their job. But ultimately, it’s a job. They want to make sure they’re fairly compensated for their work, and have interesting projects to work on. As long as they believe those things are in balance and the compensation arbitrage they can get by going to another company is within a certain bound, they’re stable and stay.</description></item><item><title>About Devops</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/about-devops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/about-devops/</guid><description>What is DevOps actually? DevOps is a culture with only one goal which is &amp;ldquo;improving the software lifecycle&amp;rdquo; (bug fixes, features, configurations) to end-users more frequently but still keep software&amp;rsquo;s reliable.
It is a continuous process and contains various stages such as :
Continuous Integration Continuous Development Continuous Testing Continuous Deployment Continuous Monitoring The main role of DevOps is to increase the quality of product to a great extent and to increase the collaboration of Development and Operation team as well so that the workflow within the organization becomes smoother.</description></item><item><title>Our Daily Standup Format</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-daily-standup-format/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-daily-standup-format/</guid><description>Report Template Team: Your team Yesterday + [Task ID] : What did you work on the task yesterday and what is the status of the task + The other things (no name tasks) that you worked on or participated in Today + [Task ID]: What are you going to work on today? + The other things (no name tasks) that you are going to work or participate in Blockers + [Task ID]: What is blocking you?</description></item><item><title>Conduct A Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/conduct-a-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/conduct-a-meeting/</guid><description>Meeting has always played an integral part in every corporate office. To optimize a productive meeting, it is vital to conduct individuals gathering without wasting time and directly get to the point, to deliver new information or discuss crucial issues.
And that begins with a smooth collaboration between these following essential aspects.
1. Timeline Announce meeting time at least one day before the meeting happens. Create Google Meet link Sync on Basecamp schedule Notify all related participants.</description></item><item><title>Hiring Approach</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-approach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hiring-approach/</guid><description>Philosophy Hire people who tell us what to do, not the other way around. Company culture is who you Hire, Fire &amp;amp; Promote. Short term vs. long term evaluation Values fit &amp;amp; culture fit Principles Hiring means we failed to execute and need help Startup employee effectiveness follows a power law False Positives are ok, False Negatives are not Culture is defined by who we hire The best thing you can do for employees — a perk better than foosball or free sushi — is hire only “A” players to work alongside them.</description></item><item><title>Good Design Understanding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/good-design-understanding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/good-design-understanding/</guid><description>Good design is not just what looks good. It also needs to perform, convert, astonish, and fulfill its purpose. It can be innovative or it might just get the job done.
A good design cannot be measured by a finite way – multiple perspectives are needed.
What is a good UX design? User experience (UX) focuses on having a deep understanding of users, what they need, what they value, their abilities, and also their limitations.</description></item><item><title>Competency Mapping</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/competency-mapping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/competency-mapping/</guid><description>We identified skills and actions showing someone has one competency or not.
Six levels to measure the level of knowledge:
0 – Completely unfamiliar: Doesn’t understand the competency.
1 – Novice: Understands the competency and its importance.
2 – Advanced Beginner: Demonstrates this competency under supervision or with encouragement.
3 – Competent: Demonstrates this competency independent of supervision or encouragement.
4 – Proficient: Encourages or supervises others in this competency.</description></item><item><title>Design Resourcestools</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-resourcestools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-resourcestools/</guid><description>Besides learning the UI design, the most important thing is to learn UX design to create a good user experience. Helps the user get the goal when in your app.
This compilation is synthetic all the websites or tools to help you improve your knowledge of UX Design. All of these websites where UX designers around the world often go to learn, just as you usually do on Behance or Dribbble to find trends, styles or ideas.</description></item><item><title>Design Tips Tricks</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-tips-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-tips-tricks/</guid><description> https://uxplanet.org/the-18-must-do-principles-in-the-form-design-fe89d0127c92 https://blog.prototypr.io/4-common-mistakes-ux-designers-should-avoid-during-product-design-process-cace92d8b8b3 https://uxplanet.org/why-is-online-checkout-so-difficult-and-how-to-simplify-it-eeb3da2ea530</description></item><item><title>Design System</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-system/</guid><description>Now having a Design System in place unites product teams around a common visual language, accelerates your design process ten-fold and gives you a strong foundation to build any project. Learn how you can create a design system and help your team improve product quality when increase the speed of your workflow.
INTRODUCE Today there are many the companies products compete with each other, the company should have one of the conditions:</description></item><item><title>Design Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/design-workflow/</guid><description>1. Project Research The goal of this step is to figure what the problems you need to solve using your design from asking the people involved such as our customers (businesses owners) and the users, the people who will use your design outcome directly. We don&amp;rsquo;t guess or assume things.
There are 2 types of research you can do to figure this out:
Quantitative: These are the things we can measure.</description></item><item><title>Three Levels Of Design</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/three-levels-of-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/three-levels-of-design/</guid><description>Don Norman in his book titled The Design of Everyday Things talks about three levels of design — Visceral Level, Behavioral Level and Reflective Level — on how they work together and play an important role in determining how people like or dislike the product. In other words, these three levels together determine whether your product is successful or not.
1. Visceral Level Visceral level is about first impression First impression is the best impression.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Fundamental</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-fundamental/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-fundamental/</guid><description>When you design UI for an app or a website, the first thing that the designer needs to determine the purpose of the product and the target audience. You should plan and calculate for your UI design.
Creativity does not exceed the limits of design goals.
Differentiate between customer and user: Put more on the role of the user than the customer
Identify the user who will use your app, identify the behavior, user characteristics.</description></item><item><title>Ux Model</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ux-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ux-model/</guid><description>What is good UX? Useful A new product should first be designed to solve the users&amp;rsquo; problems. It should be the solution users expected. It is necessary to define the users&amp;rsquo; problem and search for ways to resolve it. Failure of defining the problem exactly will lead to failure of getting the right solution to users&amp;rsquo; expectation. Thus, the product will not be useful to them.
Usability A product should be designed that it is easy to use.</description></item><item><title>Slice And Array In Golang</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/slice-and-array-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/slice-and-array-in-golang/</guid><description>Array In Go language, the terminology Array has a bit different from another language like C, JS, &amp;hellip; In Go, the array has a fixed length and type Take a look of array implementation in Go.
Its length is part of its type ([4]int and [5]int are distinct, incompatible types). For example, you can compare two arrays have the same type [4]int.
a := [4]int{1,1,1,1} b := [4]int{0,0,0,0} c := [4]int{} fmt.</description></item><item><title>The Principle Of Spacing In Ui Design Part 1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-principle-of-spacing-in-ui-design-part-1/</guid><description>Why is spacing important? Before I talk about spacing principle, you should know how spacing important is with our design.
In design have four main factors in such as:
Content Graphic Navigation Identify Spacing has not only an impact directly on this factors but also on aesthetics design. Even more, it gives the page a united harmonic look. It decides you want them to pay attention to what. If you know the principle of spacing, you can use it in all your products.</description></item><item><title>Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/be-careful-with-your-code-splitting-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/be-careful-with-your-code-splitting-setup/</guid><description>I thought I have been through hell this evening. Took me 6 hours debugging in the deep dark of hell. Oh right.
The app I have been worked on was a mobile-first PWA built with React, so naturally there is an infinite/virtual list somewhere in the app.
When I created Explore component, which basically a version of ItemList— an infinite list using react-virtualized — with list items inside, sounds good and all.</description></item><item><title>Qc Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</guid><description>1. GENERAL WORKFLOW Click on attached URL below to get more details about our general workflow:
https://www.draw.io/?lightbox=1&amp;amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;amp;edit=_blank&amp;amp;layers=1&amp;amp;nav=1#G1jtKnGw5mpmGt31dFIoDOcGxVQrqxexF7
2. ACCESS TO TESTING RESOURCES After you have a permission on Team&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive.
Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents to get resource files including:
Test Planning Template Test Cases Template Defect Summary Report Template 3. Task Assigning Flows 4. Tools Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents/Tools to get gitlab-issues-tools file
After that, Run this command in your terminal to get help:</description></item><item><title>Dcos Series Part 5 Gitlab</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-5---gitlab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-5---gitlab/</guid><description>Gitlab an open source developer tool (like Github) that allows you to host git repositories, review code, track issues, host Docker images and perform continuous integration, and it is very compatible for a small team wit CE version.
DC/OS supports us to run our own private Gitlab to manage source code in house. This article will let you know how to setup Gitlab with HTTPS.
Installing You just need to go Universe &amp;gt; Packages and choose Gitlab to install it with Advanced Installation.</description></item><item><title>Dcos Series Part 4 Deploy Simple Application With Backend Database</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-4---deploy-simple-application-with-backend-database/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-4---deploy-simple-application-with-backend-database/</guid><description>Create an Application with Golang First of all, we will go with Golang because Go is easy to implement backend server and deploy in 1 min. So we will have a few code to initialize todolist application that provide GET tasks.
func main() { // connect DB db, err := gorm.Open(&amp;quot;postgres&amp;quot;, fmt.Sprintf(&amp;quot;user=%v password=%v host=%v dbname=%v sslmode=disable&amp;quot;, os.Getenv(&amp;quot;DB_USER&amp;quot;), os.Getenv(&amp;quot;DB_PASSWORD&amp;quot;), os.Getenv(&amp;quot;DB_HOST&amp;quot;), os.Getenv(&amp;quot;DB_NAME&amp;quot;))) if err != nil { panic(fmt.Sprintf(&amp;quot;Failed to open sql connection: %v&amp;quot;, err.</description></item><item><title>Dcos Series Part 3 Service Discovery And Load Balancing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-3---service-discovery-and-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-3---service-discovery-and-load-balancing/</guid><description>The Mesosphere Datacenter Operating System (DCOS) provides useful tooling for service discovery and load balancing. One of the primary tools is Marathon Load Balancer, which will be the focus of this post.
After you boot a DCOS cluster, all tasks can be discovered by using Mesos-DNS. Discovery through DNS, however, has some limitations that include:
DNS does not identify service ports, unless you use an SRV query; most apps are not able to use SRV records “out of the box.</description></item><item><title>Dcos Series Part 2 Deploy Simple Applications</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-2---deploy-simple-applications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-2---deploy-simple-applications/</guid><description>There are so many interesting things in DC/OS GUI (Dashboard with useful metrics/status from all nodes, Services tab help us to know which application/service is running on which node, its status, etc.).
In this article, we will try to deploy applications to DC/OS and run it.
Universe packages The Universe tab shows all of the available DC/OS services from package repositories. You can install packages from the DC/OS Universe with a single click.</description></item><item><title>Dcos Series Part 1 Quick Look Installation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-1---quick-look-installation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dcos-series-part-1---quick-look-installation/</guid><description>What is DC/OS ? DC/OS - Data center OS is based on the production proven Apache Mesos distributed systems kernel, combining years of real-life experience with best practices for building and running modern applications in production.
A DC/OS cluster is composed of three types of nodes: masters, private agents, and public agents.
There are some nodes that we will talk about:
Bootstrap: we use this node to setup some configurations, to initialize a file which is called dcos_generate_config.</description></item><item><title>Skill Of Software Engineer</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/skill-of-software-engineer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/skill-of-software-engineer/</guid><description>Read Code The ability to understand an existing code base in order to analyze its behavior and make fixes or enhancements to it.
Write Code This does not include any significant amount of design – just the basics of coding. An example is being able to write a method given the desired behavior (inputs, outputs, pre-conditions and post-conditions).
Use of Integrated Development Environments The ability to effectively use modern IDEs and an understanding of their strengths and weaknesses.</description></item><item><title>Docker Registry</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/docker-registry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/docker-registry/</guid><description>Summary The Docker toolset to pack, ship, store, and deliver content.
This repository’s main product is the Docker Registry 2.0 implementation for storing and distributing Docker images. It supersedes the docker/docker-registry project with a new API design, focused around security and performance.
To be simple Server Simply, just run below command:
$ docker run -d -p 5000:5000 --restart=always --name registry registry:2 Client Get any image from the hub and tag it to point to the registry</description></item><item><title>Use Go Selenium To Crawl Data</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/use-go-selenium-to-crawl-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/use-go-selenium-to-crawl-data/</guid><description>Crawl data Crawl is a widespread issue occurring in making software. News, discount news, film ticket, etc are some examples of crawl. To be simple, it is analytics HTML, read cards, and extract data. The Go library I usually use is goquery.
However, crawling an original HTML will not work in some cases: data loaded by ajax (when reading HTML, we will only see wrapper, not data), or must login when entering a page need crawl.</description></item><item><title>Agile Using Clickup As Agile Management Tool</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/agile-using-clickup-as-agile-management-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/agile-using-clickup-as-agile-management-tool/</guid><description>ClickUp is the powerful tool that we decided to stop by after Trello and the whole bundle of similar tool for Agile Management. With the fact that we pay ClickUp $9 per month because of their feature-rich platform, we still don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use it to optimize our workflow.
Introduction ClickUp divides the structure as follow
Space Project List Ticket and support following Views
Board as Kanban Board with columns showing the statuses.</description></item><item><title>Agile How To Create Clickup Tickets</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/agile-how-to-create-clickup-tickets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/agile-how-to-create-clickup-tickets/</guid><description>To make sure everyone in the hood can understand the state of company task, the below fields are required to be filled:
Task Creation The task is in progress, it has to be assigned to an assignee.
The task is in progress, it has be specified the due date.
Template CONTEXT
Why we need the ticket What goal to achieve? What results of the ticket fits in the picture DESCRIPTION</description></item><item><title>The Okr</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-okr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-okr/</guid><description>What is OKR OKR (Object and Key Result) is a management methodology, an outcome-driven tracking framework.
Object : is a goal we want to achieve
**Key Results : **are a set of explaination for how will we know we are getting there.
For example
In Q1/2018 DF&amp;rsquo;s objective is want to build a strong backend team, so &amp;ldquo;**build a strong backend team&amp;rdquo; **is an object, to accomplish that, we will hire 2 senior backend developers and **organize 1 training session per week, **each of them is a key result to let us know whether we are getting to our objective or not.</description></item><item><title>Our Metrics For Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-metrics-for-performance-review/</guid><description>$$ P = f(r, t, c, r) $$
Performance - P Performance is a final value that will be calculated from other metrics. This value will help to indicate how good all the activities we&amp;rsquo;ve done to make the company could grow.
Metrics will be marked from the scale from 1 to 5:
1 is bad 3 is normal 5 is outstanding 1 ---- 2 ---- 3 ---- 4 ---- 5 bad good outstand Context of example</description></item><item><title>Considering Factors For Performance Evaluating</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/considering-factors-for-performance-evaluating/</guid><description>Fire quickly False positives: people who you thought fit your values, but don’t once they’re hired False negatives: people who you thought would not fit your values, but would have if you had hired them If you get some false positives anyway, the solution is to fire quickly. To follow the &amp;ldquo;No Asshole Rule&amp;rdquo;, we need to strictly apply this despite the common excuses:
for that one bad trait, he has four good traits going for him.</description></item><item><title>How We Contribute To Homebrew</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-contribute-to-homebrew/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/how-we-contribute-to-homebrew/</guid><description>Homebrew Homebrew (or brew) is one of the biggest repo on Github with more than 29k stars, 14k forks and 1k watches. It was started by Max Howell in 2009 to build the missing package manager for OS X. Back to before 2009, in Mac OSX, if we wanted to install something, we had to install it via pkg files or bin files. We didn’t have anything fancy like apt-get in Ubuntu or yum in Fedora.</description></item><item><title>The 10x Engineer</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-10x-engineer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-10x-engineer/</guid><description>10x engineer is a concept sometimes used in Silicon Valley to describe an engineer that is 10x more productive than an average engineer although the 10x metric is figurative. Sometimes referred to as &amp;ldquo;Ninjas&amp;rdquo;, these engineers are highly sought after by all tech companies.
Jim: You gave me 100 resumes but none of these guys are 10x engineers. Why hire a few of these guys to slow us down when a 10x engineer is so much more productive?</description></item><item><title>Definition Of Done</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/definition-of-done/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/definition-of-done/</guid><description>Definition of done also known as DoD is a list of criteria which must be met before a product increment (story) is considered &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;.
Failure to meet these criteria at the end of a sprint normally implies that the work should not be counted toward that sprint&amp;rsquo;s velocity nor released.
Verifying that our team’s DoD meets these criteria will ensure that we are delivering features that are done both in terms of functionality and quality.</description></item><item><title>Estimation In Agile</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/estimation-in-agile/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/estimation-in-agile/</guid><description>Estimation (or estimating) is the process of finding an estimate, or approximation, which is a value that is usable for some purpose even if input data may be incomplete, uncertain, or unstable.
The value is nonetheless usable because it is derived from the best information available. [1]
Estimation units In our workflow we use two different units that are explained below.
Story points Story points are a unit of measure for expressing an estimate of the overall effort that will be required to fully implement a product backlog item or any other piece of work.</description></item><item><title>Sprint Lifecycle</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sprint-lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sprint-lifecycle/</guid><description>Sprint &amp;ldquo;milestones&amp;rdquo; Below listed are the rules for each step of the sprint lifecycle. No exceptions will be made for any of the points.
Start of the sprint
The sprint will start at the end of the sprint planning. Before the start of the sprint planning, engineers will be focused on the same set of actions as on the Friday of the second week of the sprint. (See below) End of the sprint</description></item><item><title>Docker Microcontainers</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/docker-microcontainers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/docker-microcontainers/</guid><description>When using Docker, you will quickly realize that the image using to run a project takes a big capacity. A simple image ubuntu took nearly 200MB, but you don’t take full advantage of its available tools. Other images like Node, Go, etc almost run in Ubuntu, debian and only set up more environments to easily deploy. However, downloading a new image takes more time because of its big capacity and it seems to be not necessary at all.</description></item><item><title>Make Remote Working Works</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/make-remote-working-works/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/make-remote-working-works/</guid><description>Being office-present keeps you effective. Firms lean on that. It explains why companies are down to invest a fortune on building creative office with other benefit packages. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about that. I&amp;rsquo;m just saying there are others ways to keep people excited without costing too much operation cost.
The Dwarves lives with some principles. First, we feel no need to manage your chairs. We have better things to do with our time.</description></item><item><title>Remote Prepare And Get Going</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-prepare-and-get-going/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-prepare-and-get-going/</guid><description>Checklist What is woking remotely Why to work remotely When to work Where to work Setup &amp;amp; Tooling Performance Review Philosophy With the deeply understanding that WORK - LIFE BALANCE is the real shit. We decided to pick this style of Remote Working as a main way to work for the whole company. And everyone can choose to follow it or not. It’s optional but highly recommended.
We believe that a happy person can deliver 10x quality output compared to others.</description></item><item><title>Blocking Distraction</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blocking-distraction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blocking-distraction/</guid><description>Finding solitude in information overwhelming world
Nowadays, we are connected 247, every minute passes by there are new things happens, new notifications, endless distractions. Sometimes, it is too hard to focus and it affect our life quality a lot.
So there are couple things that we can do to avoid this problem.
Spend time to be alone everyday It can be 1–2 hours and you can truly focus on what ready matter.</description></item><item><title>Effective Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/effective-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/effective-meeting/</guid><description>To increase flexibility in how and where employees at Dwarves work, we agree on a shared set of constraints for group work and meetings.
Meeting Etiquette Meetings start on time
If you&amp;rsquo;re leading a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to start the meeting on time. If you&amp;rsquo;re attending a meeting, you are responsible for showing up on time.
Meetings happen in regular hours
All team members should make themselves available for face-to-face meetings between 10:30am - 1:00p, as long as they are scheduled at least 24 hours in advance.</description></item><item><title>Our Policy For Remote Working</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-policy-for-remote-working/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-policy-for-remote-working/</guid><description>Some useful practices we adopted to keep the remote working system goes smoothly.
This policy is written in the context of our current company setup. Specifically, this document addresses working from home on a regular basis. It goes valid for
A full-remote team. Individuals that manages and responsible for their work. Even when we aren&amp;rsquo;t in the office, our teammates are still counting on us and it is our responsibility to make sure we are exceeding their expectations.</description></item><item><title>Connecting Vim With Golang</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/connecting-vim-with-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/connecting-vim-with-golang/</guid><description>An introduction to Vim and how to use Vim with Golang Vim is a powerful text-editor, usually used server environments with no graphical interfaces. In this post, I will layer a basic foundation of Vim and show you how to use Vim as an IDE for Go. What is Vim Vim is a highly configurable text editor built to enable efficient text editing, the next version of Vi (Vim = Vi Improved), written by Bram Moolenaar, first released in 1991.</description></item><item><title>Architect Frontend Site And Mobile Development For Crypto Investment Ecosystem</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/architect-frontend-site-and-mobile-development-for-crypto-investment-ecosystem/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 as an innovation arm of INDODAX, Tokenomy is a crypto investment network through blockchain-enabled tokens. Currently reached the seed round funded by LazyLedger, Tokenomy aims to reach a broader customer segment through web platforms and mobile apps. We fully support a team of Senior Frontend Engineer, Android Mobile Engineer, and UX Designer to help them stay on track with the release timeline. Technical Highlight MVVM for mobile application architecture WebSocket for real-time trading support Reactivex to bind data and process asynchronous tasks Biometric authentication approach for data encryption Custom-built Android module to support different APIs Weekly product changelog apply for the team synergy The Context They came to us at first to refactor the frontend foundation.</description></item><item><title>Development Journey With Searchio Australia Ai Power Search Solutions</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/development-journey-with-searchio---australia-ai-power-search-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2017 and reached a total seed funding of $4M by 2020, Search.io, formerly Sajari, is an AI-powered search and product discovery platform that helps eCommerce brands and retailers maximize their revenue and conversion rates through outcome-focused, real-time search result optimization. The Dwarves partnered with Search.io to help with their Console dashboard app, improve open-source packages quality and tailor the brand UI for plugin consumers. Search.io is one of those matured projects that requires stability over speed.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Ventures Fund 1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-ventures-fund-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-ventures-fund-1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Responsibility</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/responsibility/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Team Up With Basehq Us First Ever Platform Built For Assistants</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/team-up-with-basehq---us-first-ever-platform-built-for-assistants/</guid><description>In brief Base launched in 2019 out of High Alpha Venture Studio, with a $2.6M funding round led by Matchstick Ventures with participation from Revolution&amp;rsquo;s Rise of the Rest Seed Fund, High Alpha Capital, and Slack Fund. Base is a software platform built specifically for executive assistants. Focus on smoothing out assistants&amp;rsquo; daily work. They demand a high integration between different platforms. We stepped in to make it happen. Through 2 years straight, they engaged with Dwarves to develop various new modules and features.</description></item></channel></rss>