<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>internal on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/internal/</link><description>Recent content in internal on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/internal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item><item><title>Estimation Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/estimation-guidelines/</guid><description>When we conduct an estimation, it is recommended to abandon the transitional “exact hours” assessment method, instead, use the story point based on the Fibonacci number (1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21…). The number expresses an estimation of the overall effort required to fully implement a backlog item or any piece of work.
Below’s an example of an estimation table based on the matrix of complexity, uncertainty, and effort:</description></item><item><title>Project Delivery Schedule and Guidelines</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/project-delivery-schedule-and-guidelines/</guid><description>Dwarves Foundation Team&amp;rsquo;s guide on our project delivery process. This post will serve as your go-to resource for understanding our weekly, bi-weekly, and monthly activities, ensuring that we stay on track and excel in our deliveries.
Weekly Activities 1. Weekly Points/Effort Report Every Friday
Action: Fill out the weekly points/effort report. Link: Weekly Report Spreadsheet. Deadline for Data Sync: Data is sync by EOD next Tuesday. Outcome: Weekly leaderboard on delivery.</description></item><item><title>Labs - Who we are</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-who-we-are/</guid><description>At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies. We are a diverse group of individuals, each with unique backgrounds and personalities, but our common ground lies in our dedication to exploring and understanding emerging technologies. Our goal is to investigate and learn about advancements that have the potential to enhance our lives and contribute to a better future.
Our beliefs Our culture at Labs is a confluence of diverse backgrounds, personalities, and perspectives, yet united by core beliefs:</description></item><item><title>DuckDB demo and showcase</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 23/11/2023 🎙・labs-stage Internal DuckDB has been an emerging OLAP database for analytical needs. Use cases for analytics usually use around 1GB-10GB of data, not enough to take advantage of the full potential of databases in data warehouses. The use case of analyzing data in small chunks is enough to pop up startups such as MotherDuck.
Agenda: DuckDB is a great starting point for modern stacks that don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about scalability, but want to derive hard analytics from the data that they have.</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>💠 df protocol, $icy and $dfg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/df-protocol-icy-dfg/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s our draft internal map/v0 for 🧊 $icy play, based on our current activities at this borderless software firm.
Context:
Back in 2018, when i envisioned doing something unconventional with our setup, we introduced 💎 $dfg.
It came with a dream that everyone on the team can help build next generation software, stay cool making money and own something. I planned to step down and give more ownership to those who actually implement our projects by gradually distributing $dfg to our grind chads.</description></item><item><title>How R&amp;D contributes to Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</guid><description>Our organization values the research and development (R&amp;amp;D) efforts of our team members and aims to incorporate these contributions into performance reviews. It&amp;rsquo;s important that individual R&amp;amp;D activities not only pursue personal growth but also align with our team and organizational objectives.
Key Assessment Factors For R&amp;amp;D activities, there are a few factors will contribute to your performance:
Alignment with Team Objectives: Your research should be aligned with topics identified as crucial for the future growth and success of our team.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Journey</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</guid><description>Our process for evaluating and integrating technology is designed to be thorough yet efficient, ensuring we adopt only the most effective tools into our operations. It consists of four key stages: Assess, Trial, Adopt, and Hold.
Assess: is the initial state where a technology is being evaluated. The objective is to understand the potential and limitations of the technology before committing more resources. Trial: is where the technology is tested in projects.</description></item><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item></channel></rss>