<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marketing on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/marketing/</link><description>Recent content in Marketing on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partners Network</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/partners-network/</guid><description>We seek for Partners, individuals and companies likewise, to develop a co-creation system driven by mutual purposes and interests.
With our average deal size at $30,000, a partner can generate at least $2,400 per project. Commission is paid from project start, every month until project end.
Partner perks Partnering with Dwarves is not just a collaboration, it’s a strategic investment in trust, network and business growth. Being our partners mean sharing opportunities, resources, connections and scaling up together.</description></item><item><title>Marketing and Communications Specialist</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/marketing-and-communications-specialist/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Specialists to join Dwarves and work remotely. The ideal candidate will have a passion for technology, a strong understanding of the software development industry, and excellent communication skills.
This role will involve developing and implementing marketing strategies, creating compelling content, managing social media presence, and maintaining effective communication with both internal and external stakeholders.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
Dwarves is research-focused technology firm Since 2015, we have helped companies build &amp;amp; ship top-notch software, operate tech teams and invest in ambitious people who are after world&amp;rsquo;s next big things.</description></item></channel></rss>