<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New in February 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-february-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-february-2024/</guid><description>Before you dive in
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Reporting tech signals - Latest findings on Serverless Computing, AI &amp;amp; ML, FinOps and CyberSecurity Research Topics 2024 - 40 topics on the most promising technologies. Dwarves&amp;rsquo; Reward System - Developing our community reward system Calling for Partners - One of the rare event where Dwarves and community members gather.</description></item><item><title>What's New in January 2024</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-january-2024/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
In this first month of 2024, we kept tap of what&amp;rsquo;s brewing in the tech market, while reviewing what we went through in 2023.
Reporting tech signals - Updates on the stage of React, Rust, AI, Cybersecurity, Rust.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Community</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community/</guid><description>Dwarves Community is melting pot for software engineers, thinkers, learners and techies who are to explore, learn and master the latest advancements in technology.
Technology is moving at the speed of light, and we want to stay at the forefront. Background or experience doesn’t matter to us, we are more keen on the mindset of always being curious about what’s next in tech, collaborating for the better, learning profusely and sharing unconditionally.</description></item><item><title>What's New in October 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-october-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Each month, we release a recap noting all the significant changes in our company and our team. October&amp;rsquo;s highlights include:
note.d.foundation - The wiki of how we work, learn, and operate the team at Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Community Bounty</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/dwarves-community-bounty/</guid><description>As you may know, Dwarves Discord network is where we connect with our friends, alumni, and like-minded people.
Bounties are rewards (in ICY - Dwarves’ token) given out to community members for work that encourages community developers to get more involved in the development outside of their core skills.
Who can join
We offer a platform for those seeking development work and a dynamic environment to connect with skilled developers capable of building new tools, new features.</description></item><item><title>Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</guid><description>I had my fair share of interviews. Most of them are &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; QnA sessions, and unpaid take-home projects, and coding assessments. Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s paid project is different and left a good impression on me.
The Beginning At the time, I had been looking for a new job for a while, and somehow found Dwarves, which is a rare functional programming (Elixir) shop in Vietnam. Skimming the site and what people wrote, I found the organization fascinating: they value learning and craftsmanship.</description></item></channel></rss>