<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Data Fusion</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/brainery/google-data-fusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/brainery/google-data-fusion/</guid><description>Introduction Google Data Fusion is a fully managed, cloud-native data integration service that enables users to efficiently build and manage ETL/ELT data pipelines. It is designed to streamline data engineering tasks for enterprise users and is built on top of the open-source project CDAP
. Key features and benefits of Google Data Fusion include:
Graphical User Interface: Data Fusion offers a convenient drag-and-drop interface for building data pipelines, making it easier for users to focus on insights and actions rather than writing code.</description></item><item><title>Google Dataproc</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/brainery/google-dataproc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/brainery/google-dataproc/</guid><description>Introduction Google Dataproc is a fast and easy-to-use, fully managed cloud service for running Apache Spark and Hadoop workloads. It allows users to process and analyze large-scale data efficiently and at scale. Key features and benefits of Google Dataproc include:
Fast and Scalable Processing: Dataproc enables users to run Apache Spark and Hadoop workloads on Google Cloud Platform, taking advantage of its scalable infrastructure and resources. Integration with Google Cloud Services: Dataproc integrates seamlessly with other Google Cloud services, such as BigQuery, Cloud Storage, and Cloud Spanner, allowing users to access and analyze data in a centralized manner**1** Data Analytics and Machine Learning: Dataproc supports data scientists and engineers in building and deploying machine learning models, as well as analyzing data using custom-built applications and open-source libraries.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Our View On Fullstack Engineering</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/our-view-on-fullstack-engineering/</guid><description>In tackling challenges in the world of software development, the term &amp;ldquo;full-stack engineer&amp;rdquo; often evokes a sense of wonder. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of my school days when our chemistry teacher explained the fundamental principles behind chemical reactions. Just as every chemical reaction is governed by the behavior of atoms, there&amp;rsquo;s an underlying principle in software development that defines full-stack engineering.
At its core, full-stack engineering is more than just a developer who works on both the backend and frontend.</description></item><item><title>Adoption Of Pnpm</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adoption-of-pnpm/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share that the Dwarves team has officially decided to switch to pnpm as our primary package management tool. After careful evaluation, we found that pnpm is widely embraced by the development community and has been successfully used by great teams at Vercel, Nx, and Chakra UI.
Previously, we were using Yarn V1 classic, but as our projects grew, we faced challenges with disk space and slow installations.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Working On A Project Interview Assessment At Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/working-on-a-project-interview-assessment-at-dwarves/</guid><description>I had my fair share of interviews. Most of them are &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; QnA sessions, and unpaid take-home projects, and coding assessments. Dwarves&amp;rsquo;s paid project is different and left a good impression on me.
The Beginning At the time, I had been looking for a new job for a while, and somehow found Dwarves, which is a rare functional programming (Elixir) shop in Vietnam. Skimming the site and what people wrote, I found the organization fascinating: they value learning and craftsmanship.</description></item><item><title>Life At Dwarves Software Design Group</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/life-at-dwarves-software-design-group/</guid><description>The idea: A path to better software “Everything in software architecture is a trade-off, and the why is more important than how.&amp;quot; Neal Ford is a Director and software architect at ThoughtWorks
At Dwarves, we believe that growth is our universal language, and we always strive to improve ourselves, individual-wise and team-wise.
At the end of 2021, starting with engineering practices, the core idea behind creating a software design group is to enable engineers to develop the skills required to become software architects.</description></item><item><title>How We Created An Ai Powered Interview System Using Openais Chatgpt</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-we-created-an-ai-powered-interview-system-using-openais-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-we-created-an-ai-powered-interview-system-using-openais-chatgpt/</guid><description>The Idea While ChatGPT has garnered a lot of attention over the last few months, Ngoc Thanh, our senior software engineer, has been exploring how OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s API can expedite and elevate job interviews by distilling key candidate insights through an interactive chat interview. The system automatically constructs a question set based on the candidate&amp;rsquo;s position, such as fresher, mid-level, or senior, to provide relevant questions based on their expertise.</description></item><item><title>Approaches To Manage Concurrent Workloads Like Worker Pools And Pipelines</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/approaches-to-manage-concurrent-workloads-like-worker-pools-and-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/approaches-to-manage-concurrent-workloads-like-worker-pools-and-pipelines/</guid><description>Introduction Go provides us great and convenient ways to write concurrent programs with high performance to execute tasks concurrently (perhaps in parallel if the program is run on a machine with multiple physical cores, GOMAXPROCS are automatically set to the number of physical cores of the machine that the program is running on)
While the Go concurrency primitives are easy to work with (it means it&amp;rsquo;s easy to create the Go concurrency primitives and start using them), but they don&amp;rsquo;t prevent us the developers to write something incorrectly or buggy.</description></item><item><title>Easy Prompt Engineering For Business Use And Mitigating Risks In Llms</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/easy-prompt-engineering-for-business-use-and-mitigating-risks-in-llms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/easy-prompt-engineering-for-business-use-and-mitigating-risks-in-llms/</guid><description>Preface At Dwarves, we&amp;rsquo;ve begun creating apps with ChatGPT for some of our clients. One common problem we face is what techniques of prompt engineering should we use for cases like avoiding political interactions and defending against data leaks. We have been exposed to jailbreaks for ChatGPT such as DAN and Mango Tom, but only recently have figured out how to engineer these kinds of prompts for our research. There are quite a lot of prompt engineering techniques, but below is a collection of common techniques we think you might need the most when creating business apps.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Machine Learning Approaches For Fine Tuning Llama Models</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/exploring-machine-learning-approaches-for-fine-tuning-llama-models/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/exploring-machine-learning-approaches-for-fine-tuning-llama-models/</guid><description>At Dwarves, we&amp;rsquo;ve been increasingly exposed to more state-of-the-art news coming from AI than ever before, of course, related to Large Language Models (LLM). We&amp;rsquo;ve had a taste of what AI has to offer with Stable Diffusion and more commercial apps, and have been eager to learn and hone our skillsets in applying these new AI breakthroughs in our everyday lives and our apps.
Introduction If 2021 was the year of blockchain, it&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to say that 2023 is the year of generative AI.</description></item><item><title>Message Queues And Streaming Platforms Eg Kafka Nats Rabbitmq</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/message-queues-and-streaming-platforms-eg-kafka-nats-rabbitmq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/message-queues-and-streaming-platforms-eg-kafka-nats-rabbitmq/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, we host a few learning sessions to understand some of the technology around us. We regularly pick up topics we find interesting to dive deeper into to understand them better and present our findings. One topic that piqued my interest was the use of message brokers, due to how prevalent their use case is in our projects.
In today&amp;rsquo;s digital world, the exchange of information between different systems and applications is becoming increasingly important.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned From Concurrency Practices In Blockchain Projects</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-concurrency-practices-in-blockchain-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/lessons-learned-from-concurrency-practices-in-blockchain-projects/</guid><description>This article covers some lessons learned from working on blockchain projects, with a team that was often optimistic about transparent distributed concurrency. Our API server was scaled to 3 replicas, which introduces a lot of concurrency nuance and race conditions in our app. This post mentions one of those problems, which we tackled with advisory locks. All examples are written in Go.
Introduction This story comes from a few projects with our teams optimistically setting more than one replica for a server on Kubernetes (heck, this still happens now).</description></item><item><title>Continuous Translation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/continuous-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/continuous-translation/</guid><description>Introduction Continuous Translation (CT) is a modern approach to translation management that involves synchronizing software development and translation workflows. This means that developers, translators, and product owners work together in a continuous cycle to ensure that all translations are up-to-date and aligned with the latest software developments.
Unlike traditional translation workflows, Continuous Translation eliminates the need for file and space synchronization between different stakeholders, streamlining the translation process and promoting better collaboration.</description></item><item><title>Database Designs For Multilingual Apps</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/database-designs-for-multilingual-apps/</guid><description>This story comes from the necessity of multi-language support across our applications. Dwarves Foundation handles a lot of international clients and there is always some level of concern for supporting multiple languages for certain apps. This is a concern not just from our clients, but also from us, which motivated our research for multilingual support.
Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s globalized world, many applications need to support multiple languages to reach a broader audience.</description></item><item><title>Unit Testing Best Practices In Golang</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/unit-testing-best-practices-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/unit-testing-best-practices-in-golang/</guid><description>One common issue we often tackle in backend engineering is writing test cases. In this article, we will explore the techniques for crafting effective tests in Go, discussing best practices for writing unit tests and utilizing mocks to achieve better isolation. Although our primary focus lies in unit testing-related practices, it is important to note that Golang also supports integration testing. We will also tackle the subject of integration testing in a future article, where we will examine the details and best practices for integration testing in Golang.</description></item><item><title>What Is Pnpm Compare To Npmyarn</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/what-is-pnpm-compare-to-npmyarn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/what-is-pnpm-compare-to-npmyarn/</guid><description>What is PNPM? At Dwarves Foundation, we are always on the lookout for new tech. Researching PNPM was originally from research on what package manager Next.js uses. We then tried to experiment with it for dwarves/react-toolkit, which has given us some insights into some of the cost-benefits of using the package manager.
Introduction PNPM is a package manager for Node.js which stands for “Performant NPM”. It was introduced in 2016, the same year Yarn was released.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Accelerate Project Initiation With Advanced Nextjs Boilerplate React Toolkit</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/accelerate-project-initiation-with-advanced-nextjs-boilerplate-react-toolkit/</guid><description>Accelerate Project Initiation with Advanced NextJS-Boilerplate &amp;amp; React-Toolkit In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world of software development, project initiation can often be a challenging and time-consuming process, with teams facing issues such as inconsistent code quality, slow setup times, and suboptimal workflows. To address these obstacles and streamline the project initiation process, we&amp;rsquo;ve developed two powerful libraries, NextJS-Boilerplate and React-Toolkit, that can help teams get started quickly and efficiently.
Challenges in Project Initiation Software development teams often face several challenges during project initiation, including:</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>How Blue Green Deployment Helped Mochi</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/how-blue-green-deployment-helped-mochi/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, our team has always faced some bit of friction when deploying apps for our clients. We’ve known about blue-green deployments for a while and were recently given the chance to evaluate and demonstrate them for one of our Discord bot projects.
Applying Blue-green deployment for Mochi Bot Introducing Mochi Bot to the Web3 space, our team has developed a flexible and user-friendly product with features like NFT rarity queries, sales alerts on Discord and Twitter, and showing various tips.</description></item><item><title>I18n Frontend Guideline</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/i18n-frontend-guideline/</guid><description>In a front-end web application, locales are used to determine the language and geographic location of the user and to display the appropriate content to them.
When a user visits a web page, the application will first detect their locale, then use this information to determine which version of the content to display.
To support multiple languages and locales, the application needs to have the necessary content available for each locale.</description></item><item><title>Radio Talk 61 Monorepo</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-61-monorepo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/radio-talk-61-monorepo/</guid><description>Demystifying Monorepos: A Recap of Our Recent Sharing Session During our recent sharing session, we delved into the world of monorepos, exploring their benefits, challenges, and the tools available to manage them effectively. This recap aims to summarize the key points of the discussion and highlight some potential business outcomes of adopting monorepos.
Introduction A monorepo is a version control strategy where all the code for an organization&amp;rsquo;s projects is stored in a single repository.</description></item><item><title>From Multi Repo To Monorepo A Case Study With Nghenhan Turbo Monorepo</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/from-multi-repo-to-monorepo-a-case-study-with-nghenhan-turbo-monorepo/</guid><description>In this case study, we share our experience of transitioning from multi-repository structure to a monorepo using Turbo in our project. This migration led to numerous benefits, including a 60% reduction in build times, a 40% increase in developer productivity, and simplified dependency management. Our goal is to offer valuable insights and lessons learned throughout our journey to help others considering a similar transition.
Introduction Over the past two years, we have developed NgheNhan - a trading platform that not only enables users to manage their accounts efficiently but also allows them to analyze market data and trading performance in realtime.</description></item><item><title>Why Micro Frontend</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/why-micro-frontend/</guid><description>Micro-Frontend - What &amp;amp; Why? As web applications become more complex and feature-rich, traditional frontend architectures such as monolithic will become harder to maintain, scale, and evolve. Micro-frontend is an emerging front-end architecture that aims to address these challenges by breaking down the front-end into small, independent and reusable modules.
In this article, we will explore the concept of micro-frontend, its benefits, design principles, tools and technologies, implementation strategies, and challenges.</description></item><item><title>Why We Chose Our Tech Stack Accelerating Development With A Robust Frontend Solution</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/why-we-chose-our-tech-stack-accelerating-development-with-a-robust-frontend-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/why-we-chose-our-tech-stack-accelerating-development-with-a-robust-frontend-solution/</guid><description>At Dwarves Foundation, we pride ourselves on being a team of seasoned technology experts, passionate about crafting innovative solutions for our clients. With years of experience in the technology industry, we understand the importance of selecting the right tools and technologies to deliver exceptional results. In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, staying ahead of the competition requires building and deploying features quickly without sacrificing quality or stability. When selecting a technology for our frontend tech stack, the foremost question we ask is: &amp;ldquo;Has this technology achieved a certain level of stability and maturity?</description></item><item><title>Focus On Software Delivery</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/focus-on-software-delivery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/focus-on-software-delivery/</guid><description>Focus on shipping when you are struggling with what to do next to be better as a software engineer. When you ship something new, users will try out your build and give you feedback. It may contain bugs. It may ship with the wrong flow implemented. It may ship with known issues. You may feel bad but and frustrated but those emotions will save you ton of time. The point is: Users will let you know.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>The Key Of Security Mechanisms In Tackling Cyber Threats</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-key-of-security-mechanisms-in-tackling-cyber-threats/</guid><description>Hosted by Thanh Pham - Engineering Manager, Dwarves had a great time with the best minds in cybersecurity- Mr. Hieu PC to share his knowledge and experience. As someone who is always looking to improve skills, this event is extremely valuable. We learned a lot about the different elements of cybersecurity and how to better protect our code.
Hieu PC was a pro ex-hacker who made headlines and is now a Security Expert at Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s National Cybersecurity Centre (NCSC).</description></item><item><title>Data Analyst In Retail Trading</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/data-analyst-in-retail-trading/</guid><description>I am Bach Phuong and I work at Dwarves Foundation as a Data Analyst, helping partner companies realize insights and understand their business better.
What does a Data Analyst do? A Data Analyst is a gatekeeper for an organization’s data. They are tasked to explore, transform, aggregate data to create business insights from that data to then create reports to stakeholders. Thanks to these reports, companies can make more informed business decisions.</description></item><item><title>React Native New Architecture</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-native-new-architecture/</guid><description>📖 Introducing react-native&amp;rsquo;s new architecture changes that boost performance, bringing react-native back into the race with Flutter
Introduction of react-native 📱 React Native is a JavaScript framework for writing high-performance mobile apps that leverage iOS and Android native components. It is based on React, and is very accessible to React Web developers
After a long announcement, planned from 2018, appeared in 2020, merged in 2021 and officially published in April 2022, react-native has a new architecture that improves performance dramatically.</description></item><item><title>React 18</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/react-18/</guid><description>React 18 was released in March 2022. This release focuses on performance improvements and updating the rendering engine.
React 18 Feature Quick Guide Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these updates in more detail.
Concurrency in React Concurrency is not a feature, per se. It’s a new behind-the-scenes mechanism that enables React to prepare multiple versions of your UI at the same time. A key property of Concurrent React is that rendering is interruptible.</description></item><item><title>Remix Versus Nextjs</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/remix-versus-nextjs/</guid><description>📖 A brief comparison between Remix and Next.js frameworks
Introduction of Remix Remix describes itself as:
Remix is an edge native, full-stack JavaScript framework for building modern, fast, and resilient user experiences. It unifies the client and server with web standards so you can think less about code and more about your product.
Compared to Next.js, which is one of the most React frameworks used for server-side rendering and has been there for a significant time, Remix appears as a new strong competitor.</description></item><item><title>Are We Really Engineers</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/are-we-really-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/are-we-really-engineers/</guid><description>Is software engineering &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; engineering? As the Dwarves asked this question during the Apprenticeship Training Program, we had a chance to dig more into the topic. Many professionals discuss this, but there&amp;rsquo;s not a full answer. The engineers strictly follow the engineering process, apply math to solve the problem, and build products. We software engineers don&amp;rsquo;t feel like the same as described. I found the originated articles from Hillel Wayne, and it perfectly answers the question.</description></item><item><title>Go In Software Engineering</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/go-in-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/go-in-software-engineering/</guid><description>Go is a type-safe, cloud-native language designed for simplicity
with first-class support for concurrency.
The software community has been hungering for a small, simple, easy-to-learn and pragmatic programming language. Go fits the bill with:
Simplicity Go&amp;rsquo;s beauty lies in its powerful simplicity. A list of NO&amp;rsquo;s in Go design contains generics, ternary operation, pointer arithmetic,…. These features are missing because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit, and it affects compilation speed, and end up making the language too complicated.</description></item><item><title>Reusability In Software Development</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/reusability-in-software-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/reusability-in-software-development/</guid><description>Introduction In the previous century, when the software market was also immature, the economy was grown with a large scale lead to more and more new business problems appear that demands software to solve such as management, automatic. So a lot of new ideas about software were imagined and implement from the roots to resolve the corresponding matter. Because of this original, the reuse of software was uncommon.
Nowadays, after a long time for deeping in building something new to solve classic problems.</description></item><item><title>Introduction To Software Craftsmanship</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/introduction-to-software-craftsmanship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/introduction-to-software-craftsmanship/</guid><description>Craftsmanship has been our motto since the first day. But to the newbies and even some current Dwarves, the real definition of software craftsmanship is still vague, or being understood in different ways.
Most of us have been working in software industry for a long time. For newbies, it might be unfamiliar to catch up the term of Craftsmanship and how it is applied into our industry. So to make sure everyone is on the same page &amp;amp; using the same brush, this talk aims to cover our point of view on this term and why it matters that much to land a seat on our core values.</description></item><item><title>Architecture Decision Record</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/architecture-decision-record/</guid><description>There is an issue that every team will inevitably bump into. Newbies might get confused when a project is being developed. They wonder how that code was written, how we ended up choosing that architecture. It somehow leads to finger-point, and even the decision-maker himself can&amp;rsquo;t remember how that decision was taken.
That happens in a long-term project, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. We believe we&amp;rsquo;re not the only one who gets that, so we&amp;rsquo;d like to gather you all and tackle this today by a practice called Architecture Decision Record (ADR)</description></item><item><title>Well Crafted Software</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/well-crafted-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/well-crafted-software/</guid><description>This post ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna be a speech of Uncle Bob&amp;rsquo;s Software Craftsmanship Manifesto. We&amp;rsquo;ve all known that. And to people who don&amp;rsquo;t, for God&amp;rsquo;s sake. Google.
Well crafted software means that regardless how old the application is, developers can understand it easily, side effects are well known and controlled, high test coverage, clean design, business language well expressed in the code and adding or changing features does not take longer than it used to take at the beginning of the project when the codebase was small.</description></item><item><title>Finite State Machine</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/finite-state-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/finite-state-machine/</guid><description>A Finite State Machine is a model of computation based on a hypothetical machine made of one or more states. Only one single state of this machine can be active at the same time. It means the machine has to transition from one state to another in to perform different actions
Above image is a simple FSM, each circle is a state and arrow is an event or action.
Pros and Cons Pros</description></item><item><title>Be Careful With Your Code Splitting Setup</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/be-careful-with-your-code-splitting-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/be-careful-with-your-code-splitting-setup/</guid><description>I thought I have been through hell this evening. Took me 6 hours debugging in the deep dark of hell. Oh right.
The app I have been worked on was a mobile-first PWA built with React, so naturally there is an infinite/virtual list somewhere in the app.
When I created Explore component, which basically a version of ItemList— an infinite list using react-virtualized — with list items inside, sounds good and all.</description></item><item><title>Skill Of Software Engineer</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/skill-of-software-engineer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/skill-of-software-engineer/</guid><description>Read Code The ability to understand an existing code base in order to analyze its behavior and make fixes or enhancements to it.
Write Code This does not include any significant amount of design – just the basics of coding. An example is being able to write a method given the desired behavior (inputs, outputs, pre-conditions and post-conditions).
Use of Integrated Development Environments The ability to effectively use modern IDEs and an understanding of their strengths and weaknesses.</description></item><item><title>The 10x Engineer</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-10x-engineer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/the-10x-engineer/</guid><description>10x engineer is a concept sometimes used in Silicon Valley to describe an engineer that is 10x more productive than an average engineer although the 10x metric is figurative. Sometimes referred to as &amp;ldquo;Ninjas&amp;rdquo;, these engineers are highly sought after by all tech companies.
Jim: You gave me 100 resumes but none of these guys are 10x engineers. Why hire a few of these guys to slow us down when a 10x engineer is so much more productive?</description></item></channel></rss>