<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Pipeline Design Framework</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/data-pipeline-design-framework/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/data-pipeline-design-framework/</guid><description>Motivation of Designing Data Pipeline Framework To improve and strongly go-live the data pipeline, besides apply best practices and pillar for Data Pipeline Native Solution, a design framework and pattern are robustly help us in:
Follow typical data pipeline Organize pipeline and adopt market Refer the other people use besides yours Its easy to follow if we will discuss the pattern and solution with SWAT and pros/cons analysis and aks ourself for initiative questions such as: when to use and when not to use.</description></item><item><title>Quick Learning Vector Database</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/quick-learning-vector-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/quick-learning-vector-database/</guid><description>Motivation of Vector Database The motivation of this thoughts that trying to discover the LLMs and Generative AI In order to create or build, train any models there are multiple factors will need to be considered: lakes of data, metadata, data management, infrastructure, etc. Vector Databases are used like underlying of Gen AI Where everything are tokenized, vectorized and serialized into a single language Explored blog posts, articles from What is a AWS Vector Database?</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/consulting/case-study/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>Focus On Software Delivery</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/focus-on-software-delivery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playbook/operations/focus-on-software-delivery/</guid><description>Focus on shipping when you are struggling with what to do next to be better as a software engineer. When you ship something new, users will try out your build and give you feedback. It may contain bugs. It may ship with the wrong flow implemented. It may ship with known issues. You may feel bad but and frustrated but those emotions will save you ton of time. The point is: Users will let you know.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>MapReduce</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/mapreduce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/playground/engineering/data/mapreduce/</guid><description>What is MapReduce? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with an example.
We are the head of census bureau for the state of California and tasked with finding the finding the population of all cities in California. All the resources we want are ready but we have only four months to finish the task. Calculating the population of all cities for a big state like california is not an easy task. The sensible thing to do is to divide the state by city and make individuals in charge of each city to calculate the population of each city where he is in charge of.</description></item></channel></rss>