<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rust on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/rust/</link><description>Recent content in rust on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #5</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-5/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 03/01/2024 🍎 apple Internal Our fifth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Auto pass reCAPTCHA by @Toan Ho Passkey demo by @Tay Github Trending Analyzer use-case discussion by @Hieu Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #5 - 03/01/2024:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #4</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 27/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our fourth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Broadway in elixir to handle million messages by @Hieu Using WebAuthn API to implement passkeys by @Vincent Labeling image using openAI vision and embedding flow by @Lap Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #4 - 27/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 20/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our third weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Rise on chatbot alternatives, LibreChat to use OpenAI and custom LLMs by @Tom Bypass reCaptcha using self-hosted AI model by @Toan Shared query processing through DuckDB WASM by @Tom Build desktop app with Tauri by @Vy Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #3 - 20/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 13/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>November Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>Implement a rust game through WASM</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</guid><description> Design a simple game concept suitable for implementation in Rust. Develop the game logic and user interface in Rust. Compile and optimize the Rust code for WASM. Test game performance and compatibility across various browsers.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a game server on Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</guid><description>Develop a robust and efficient game server using Rust.
Design the server architecture with a focus on scalability and performance. Implement core server functionalities like player management, real-time communication, and game logic. Test for concurrency and load handling.</description></item><item><title>Playaround With Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-rust/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/playaround-with-rust/</guid><description>Mozilla intends to use Rust as a platform for prototyping experimental browser architectures.
Specifically, the hope is to develop a browser that is more amenable to safe and parallel than the existing ones, while also being less prone to common C++ coding errors.
What makes Rust special Ownership Each value in Rust has a variable that&amp;rsquo;s called its owner, there can only be one owner at a time When the owner goes out of scope, the value will be dropped Variable scope is a range within a program for which an item is valid Let’s take this example:</description></item></channel></rss>