<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Culture on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/culture/</link><description>Recent content in Culture on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Manifesto</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/the-manifesto/</guid><description>Aim for Quality Quality exists in every piece of work. We thrive to deliver the best because we can.
Well-crafted Software
We humbly imply our expertise and experience into well-crafted software. We take pride in high quality products and perfect solution. We can&amp;rsquo;t stand preventable defects. Quality Pays
Quality outweighs everything else. Once it isn&amp;rsquo;t managed, the entire project goes down as well. Crafting solid software requires time, efforts, disciplines and proper methods.</description></item><item><title>Growth Is Our Universal Language</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/growth-is-our-universal-language/</guid><description>At Dwarves, the core team live and breathe growth. We believe that growth is our universal language, and we&amp;rsquo;re always striving to improve ourselves, both personally and professionally. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a job for us; it&amp;rsquo;s a way of life. We&amp;rsquo;re hustlers with an extra hat, always pushing ourselves to be better and earn more.
Every time we hire, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for like-minded individuals who share our growth mindset. We want to be with people who are willing to challenge themselves and reach new heights.</description></item><item><title>Ogif</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ogif/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ogif/</guid><description>I would like to introduce to you our new initiative called OGIF — Oh God It&amp;rsquo;s Friday. Moving forward, our Friday Showcase will have a broader range of topics to discuss and share.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to reflect on our achievements from the past week, and look forward to the next with optimism and enthusiasm.
The tradition At Dwarves, we value work-life balance and believe that it comes after fulfilling our responsibilities.</description></item></channel></rss>