<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>continuous-learning on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/continuous-learning/</link><description>Recent content in continuous-learning on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/continuous-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</guid><description>In a recent collaborative discussion between key members of the Labs and Consulting teams, we&amp;rsquo;ve made decisive strides in pinpointing key topics and potential projects for development. Each topic is paired with specific challenges to ensure we engage deeply with the technology, understanding its practical applications. The focal point for the coming month is WebAssembly (WASM), alongside a range of exciting use-cases we plan to implement and demonstrate.
Our discussions have led to the identification of several intriguing topics, each with its own set of challenges.</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. To encourage andensive nomination system. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item></channel></rss>