<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>growth on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/growth/</link><description>Recent content in growth on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consultant Growth Track</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/consulting/consultant-growth-track/</guid><description>While there is no fixed path in the consulting field, we do have a structured growth guidance for career development, skill enhancement, and professional advancement.
Tier 1: Associate Consultant What you do:
Participate in client engagements, assisting senior consultants Gain exposure to various projects and technologies Learn company methodologies, tools, and best practices Perform research, analysis, and contribute to project documentation Skills needed:
Expert technical skills Client needs and project requirements gathering Project management basics Communication and presentation skills Reward:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item></channel></rss>