<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>home on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/home/</link><description>Recent content in home on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consulting Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/consulting/</guid><description>Who we are Dwarves Consulting is team of individuals who possess a combination of technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and strong communication abilities. Our culture Ahead of the market: we continuously learn and discover about the market and technology so we can participate in new, cool challenges, strive for high-quality deliverables and maintaining high standards Tech to solve problems: first we understand the problems, we provide solutions before any hard coding Network matters: we welcome collaborations with everyone who has the same goals and believe as we do How we work Our working environment is dynamic.</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This note repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges, new tech, hiring, bounty, etc.</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/home/</guid><description>Welcome to Dwarves Notes, a collection of notes for everything we do and operate at Dwarves. Dwarves are a group of technology innovation advocates. This project is a part of our information engine, where we consolidate know-how and expertise from and for our team as part of our MMA system: Mastery, Meaning, and Autonomy.
We believe that behind every success comes great preparation, accumulation and compound every single day. This note repo contains our notes and studies for any upcoming challenges, new tech, hiring, bounty, etc.</description></item><item><title>Labs Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/</guid><description>Latest from Labs Team Labs Weekly Catchup 2 Labs - Who we are Labs Weekly Catchup 1 DuckDB demo and showcase Reward Model &amp;amp; Nomination Labs x Consulting Workflow Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update) Labs - Topic proposal &amp;amp; progress tracking Labs - New Member Onboarding Knowledge Journey Forward Engineering Publications Forward Engineering November 2023 Forward Engineering October 2023 Forward Engineering August 2023 Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) Who we are At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Memo</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/</guid><description>Our newest memos This is where we keep our internal updates, learned and curated by our engineers.
Consulting - Who should join us: Consulting teams consists of anyone who&amp;rsquo;s hungry for more than just coding; those who are curious about the trends, the market, who can introduce new projects / challenges, who care about providing sensible solutions, and who take great care of projects. Consulting - Who We Are: Dwarves Consulting is team of individuals who possess a combination of technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and strong communication abilities.</description></item></channel></rss>