<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>discussion on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/discussion/</link><description>Recent content in discussion on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/discussion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #4</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 27/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our fourth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Broadway in elixir to handle million messages by @Hieu Using WebAuthn API to implement passkeys by @Vincent Labeling image using openAI vision and embedding flow by @Lap Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #4 - 27/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 20/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our third weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Rise on chatbot alternatives, LibreChat to use OpenAI and custom LLMs by @Tom Bypass reCaptcha using self-hosted AI model by @Toan Shared query processing through DuckDB WASM by @Tom Build desktop app with Tauri by @Vy Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #3 - 20/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 13/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>DuckDB demo and showcase</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 23/11/2023 🎙・labs-stage Internal DuckDB has been an emerging OLAP database for analytical needs. Use cases for analytics usually use around 1GB-10GB of data, not enough to take advantage of the full potential of databases in data warehouses. The use case of analyzing data in small chunks is enough to pop up startups such as MotherDuck.
Agenda: DuckDB is a great starting point for modern stacks that don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about scalability, but want to derive hard analytics from the data that they have.</description></item></channel></rss>