<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>process on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/process/</link><description>Recent content in process on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure The Company Email</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</guid><description>1. Make sure you have 2FA enabled For this method to work, you need to have two factor authentification enabled for your Google account. If it’s not, follow the link below and set it up.
https://www.google.com/landing/2step/
2. Create an App Password Google will verify your ownership with this app password. Select “Mail” under app, and “Mac” under device. Hit “Generate”. Copy and keep for later!
3. Add your email to Gmail Go to Gmail -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Accounts and Import.</description></item><item><title>Making Decision As A Team Member</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</guid><description>Democracy in a Nutshell Sure we all heard of democracy. Mostly, this term appears in erhm, election?
However, from what I understand, democracy is maintained by giving decision-making power to the people. And not just &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; people. Your people.
We make sure they all feel respected. We all work in the same boat. It&amp;rsquo;s their benefit to care of, too. Letting people know the direction means sharing the responsibility, and sharing the responsibility equals reducing the risk.</description></item><item><title>Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</guid><description>Being in a remote team is dope. Manage your own stuff, remove the time and cost of commuting, select your work ambiance, and got equipped with all types of supporting tools.
Basecamp, for example.
Our path with Basecamp didn&amp;rsquo;t cross by accident. Years ago, we embarked on the Slack community and had it applied for internal communication. And project management on another tool, where documents &amp;amp; files are in G-suite.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</guid><description>One of the factors that could make or break a project is the process of communication between designers and developers. Designers and developers have their own working “languages.”
It’s important to find a protocol in which a mutual language can bridge the gap between designers and developers. This protocol helps everyone in the team understand the ultimate objective of the project, minimize the guesswork, save time and effort, ensuring the high-quality standard outcomes we promised to deliver to clients.</description></item><item><title>Qc Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</guid><description>1. GENERAL WORKFLOW Click on attached URL below to get more details about our general workflow:
https://www.draw.io/?lightbox=1&amp;amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;amp;edit=_blank&amp;amp;layers=1&amp;amp;nav=1#G1jtKnGw5mpmGt31dFIoDOcGxVQrqxexF7
2. ACCESS TO TESTING RESOURCES After you have a permission on Team&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive.
Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents to get resource files including:
Test Planning Template Test Cases Template Defect Summary Report Template 3. Task Assigning Flows 4. Tools Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents/Tools to get gitlab-issues-tools file
After that, Run this command in your terminal to get help:</description></item></channel></rss>