<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Process on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/tags/process/</link><description>Recent content in Process on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs---new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs---new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs---topic-proposal--progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs---topic-proposal--progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/reward-model--nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/labs/reward-model--nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item><item><title>Configure The Company Email</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/configure-the-company-email/</guid><description>1. Make sure you have 2FA enabled For this method to work, you need to have two factor authentification enabled for your Google account. If it’s not, follow the link below and set it up.
https://www.google.com/landing/2step/
2. Create an App Password Google will verify your ownership with this app password. Select “Mail” under app, and “Mac” under device. Hit “Generate”. Copy and keep for later!
3. Add your email to Gmail Go to Gmail -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Accounts and Import.</description></item><item><title>Making Decision As A Team Member</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/making-decision-as-a-team-member/</guid><description>Democracy in a Nutshell Sure we all heard of democracy. Mostly, this term appears in erhm, election?
However, from what I understand, democracy is maintained by giving decision-making power to the people. And not just &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; people. Your people.
We make sure they all feel respected. We all work in the same boat. It&amp;rsquo;s their benefit to care of, too. Letting people know the direction means sharing the responsibility, and sharing the responsibility equals reducing the risk.</description></item><item><title>Adjust The Way We Work In Basecamp Style</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/adjust-the-way-we-work-in-basecamp-style/</guid><description>Being in a remote team is dope. Manage your own stuff, remove the time and cost of commuting, select your work ambiance, and got equipped with all types of supporting tools.
Basecamp, for example.
Our path with Basecamp didn&amp;rsquo;t cross by accident. Years ago, we embarked on the Slack community and had it applied for internal communication. And project management on another tool, where documents &amp;amp; files are in G-suite.</description></item><item><title>Ui Design Best Practices Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/ui-design-best-practices-dwarves/</guid><description>One of the factors that could make or break a project is the process of communication between designers and developers. Designers and developers have their own working “languages.”
It’s important to find a protocol in which a mutual language can bridge the gap between designers and developers. This protocol helps everyone in the team understand the ultimate objective of the project, minimize the guesswork, save time and effort, ensuring the high-quality standard outcomes we promised to deliver to clients.</description></item><item><title>Qc Onboarding</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/memo/qc-onboarding/</guid><description>1. GENERAL WORKFLOW Click on attached URL below to get more details about our general workflow:
https://www.draw.io/?lightbox=1&amp;amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;amp;edit=_blank&amp;amp;layers=1&amp;amp;nav=1#G1jtKnGw5mpmGt31dFIoDOcGxVQrqxexF7
2. ACCESS TO TESTING RESOURCES After you have a permission on Team&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive.
Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents to get resource files including:
Test Planning Template Test Cases Template Defect Summary Report Template 3. Task Assigning Flows 4. Tools Open ~/Dwarves Foundation/Document/QA Documents/Tools to get gitlab-issues-tools file
After that, Run this command in your terminal to get help:</description></item></channel></rss>