<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hiring on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/hiring/</link><description>Recent content in hiring on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/hiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend Engineer, Go/Elixir/Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/backend-engineer-go-elixir-rust/</guid><description> Requirements A Linux or Mac user Familiar with Agile development process, esp. Scrum framework Experience with Golang/Elixir/Rust Experience in shipping web applications to production, CI/CD with docker centric workflow Familiar with running large scale web services Understanding of system performance and scaling Possess excellent communication, sharp analytical abilities with proven design skills, able to think critically of the current system regarding growth and stability Experience in writing good unit test Responsibility Define and shape the fundamentals of engineering at Dwarves Foundation Design and write maintainable code at scale Continuously discuss, debate with other team members to propose optimal solutions for different problems Maintain and monitor the systems to make sure there is no disruption in our services</description></item><item><title>React Native Developer</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/hiring/open-positions/react-native-developer/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for talented developer with experience in React Native to join Dwarves and work remotely, on a fast-growing US startup.
🤘 Apply now (We respond within three days)
🤝 As an engineer at Dwarves, you will be working closely with a team of talented, kind people and working directly with our clients. There is a lot of freedom to contribute to the quality of the project and improve, or prove yourself.</description></item></channel></rss>