<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>labs on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/labs/</link><description>Recent content in labs on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Applying MPC for authentication for web3 Console</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</guid><description>Use Multi-Party Computation for secure authentication in a Web3 console environment:
Research and implement MPC protocols suitable for authentication. Integrate MPC into the Console app for secure user authentication</description></item><item><title>Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</guid><description>Implement biometric authentication for web applications via external devices:
Research and select appropriate biometric hardware compatible with web applications. Develop a secure method for connecting and communicating with the external device. Integrate biometric authentication into the web authentication flow.</description></item><item><title>Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-magic-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-magic-links/</guid><description>Implement a &amp;lsquo;Magic Link&amp;rsquo; system for passwordless authentication:
Develop an email-based authentication system where users receive a unique, time-sensitive link to log in. Ensure the security of the magic link generation and verification process.</description></item><item><title>Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</guid><description>Create a QR code-based login system for easy and secure access to web applications:
Design the QR code generation and scanning process. Implement a secure system for QR code validation and user authentication.</description></item><item><title>Implement a rust game through WASM</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</guid><description> Design a simple game concept suitable for implementation in Rust. Develop the game logic and user interface in Rust. Compile and optimize the Rust code for WASM. Test game performance and compatibility across various browsers.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a game server on Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</guid><description>Develop a robust and efficient game server using Rust.
Design the server architecture with a focus on scalability and performance. Implement core server functionalities like player management, real-time communication, and game logic. Test for concurrency and load handling.</description></item><item><title>Realtime memory knowledge updates (RAG updates)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/realtime-memory-knowledge-updates-rag-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/realtime-memory-knowledge-updates-rag-updates/</guid><description>Implement real-time updates to the memory knowledge base of an AI system:
Develop a system for continuous learning and updating of the AI&amp;rsquo;s knowledge base. Ensure the updates occur in real-time without impacting the AI&amp;rsquo;s performance. Test and validate the accuracy and relevance of the updated knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Self-host AI model in the browser</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/self-host-ai-model-on-the-browser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/self-host-ai-model-on-the-browser/</guid><description>Deploy an AI model directly in the browser for applications like OCR for security cameras or private browser chatbots.
Research and select suitable AI models for the intended applications. Use WASM to integrate the models into a browser environment, ensuring privacy and efficiency.</description></item><item><title>How R&amp;D contributes to Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</guid><description>Our organization values the research and development (R&amp;amp;D) efforts of our team members and aims to incorporate these contributions into performance reviews. It&amp;rsquo;s important that individual R&amp;amp;D activities not only pursue personal growth but also align with our team and organizational objectives.
Key Assessment Factors For R&amp;amp;D activities, there are a few factors will contribute to your performance:
Alignment with Team Objectives: Your research should be aligned with topics identified as crucial for the future growth and success of our team.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Journey</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/knowledge-journey/</guid><description>Our process for evaluating and integrating technology is designed to be thorough yet efficient, ensuring we adopt only the most effective tools into our operations. It consists of four key stages: Assess, Trial, Adopt, and Hold.
Assess: is the initial state where a technology is being evaluated. The objective is to understand the potential and limitations of the technology before committing more resources. Trial: is where the technology is tested in projects.</description></item><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</guid><description>In a recent collaborative discussion between key members of the Labs and Consulting teams, we&amp;rsquo;ve made decisive strides in pinpointing key topics and potential projects for development. Each topic is paired with specific challenges to ensure we engage deeply with the technology, understanding its practical applications. The focal point for the coming month is WebAssembly (WASM), alongside a range of exciting use-cases we plan to implement and demonstrate.
Our discussions have led to the identification of several intriguing topics, each with its own set of challenges.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. To encourage andensive nomination system. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item><item><title>Data processing and visual infographics through DuckDB WASM</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/data-processing-and-visual-infographics-through-duckdb-wasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/data-processing-and-visual-infographics-through-duckdb-wasm/</guid><description>Leverage DuckDB-WASM for efficient in-browser data processing and create dynamic visual infographics.</description></item></channel></rss>