<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>labs on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/labs/</link><description>Recent content in labs on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #4</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-4/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 27/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our fourth weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Broadway in elixir to handle million messages by @Hieu Using WebAuthn API to implement passkeys by @Vincent Labeling image using openAI vision and embedding flow by @Lap Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #4 - 27/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-3/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 20/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our third weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Rise on chatbot alternatives, LibreChat to use OpenAI and custom LLMs by @Tom Bypass reCaptcha using self-hosted AI model by @Toan Shared query processing through DuckDB WASM by @Tom Build desktop app with Tauri by @Vy Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup weekly meeting #3 - 20/12/2023:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-2/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 13/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our second weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Kick-off topic - Self-hosted AI model in browsers with a quick demo by Thanh Phan and Toan Ho Elixir cluster problem: scalability, broadcast messaging, leader election by Hieu Phan Compare Rust 101 vs Go with experience in running Rust classes with the team by Hieu Rust and understanding monadic error handling by Khac Vy AI trending and understanding model and runtime architectures in LLMs by Tom Nguyen Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 Self-hosted AI model in browsers:</description></item><item><title>Labs Weekly Catchup #1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/labs-weekly-catchup-1/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 06/12/2023 🍎 apple Internal Our first weekly catchup. We organize an agenda the day beforehand and consolidate our findings, notable research progress, possibly new tech, insight or technique everyone should know.
Agenda: Among the topics we will cover, there will be a short topic discussion and demonstration on AI Realtime memory knowledge updates by Tom. this will include:
New approaches to memory consolidation A small preview demo of what it looks like Output: Understand the research progress and passions of the labs team Understand any shortcomings or things to improve for the next weekly catchup Notes from the catchup 🧠 AI - Realtime Memory</description></item><item><title>What's New in November 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/newsletter/whats-new-november-2023/</guid><description>[!Before you dive in]
Dwarves is operated as a 50% company, 50% community. Everything we learn along the way of work, we transform into knowledge and distribute back to our tech community.
If you want to get in touch, visit Dwarves Network
Last November, we kicked off the Labs team, introduced Salary Advance for the Dwarves, upgraded note.d.foundation, supported Golang meetup, and demonstrated craftsmanship through various case studies and demos.</description></item><item><title>Labs - Who we are</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-who-we-are/</guid><description>At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies. We are a diverse group of individuals, each with unique backgrounds and personalities, but our common ground lies in our dedication to exploring and understanding emerging technologies. Our goal is to investigate and learn about advancements that have the potential to enhance our lives and contribute to a better future.
Our beliefs Our culture at Labs is a confluence of diverse backgrounds, personalities, and perspectives, yet united by core beliefs:</description></item><item><title>Labs Team</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/</guid><description>Latest from Labs Team Labs Weekly Catchup 4 Labs Weekly Catchup 3 Labs Weekly Catchup 2 Labs Weekly Catchup 1 Labs - Who we are DuckDB demo and showcase Reward Model &amp;amp; Nomination Labs x Consulting Workflow Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update) Labs - Topic proposal &amp;amp; progress tracking Forward Engineering Publications Forward Engineering November 2023 Forward Engineering October 2023 Forward Engineering August 2023 Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) Who we are At Labs, our team is united by a shared passion for new technologies.</description></item><item><title>November Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/forward-engineering-november-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>Applying MPC for authentication for web3 Console</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/applying-mpc-for-authentication-for-web3-console/</guid><description>Use Multi-Party Computation for secure authentication in a Web3 console environment:
Research and implement MPC protocols suitable for authentication. Integrate MPC into the Console app for secure user authentication</description></item><item><title>Demo: Biometrics on the web (through external device connection)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-biometrics-on-the-web-through-external-device-connection/</guid><description>Implement biometric authentication for web applications via external devices:
Research and select appropriate biometric hardware compatible with web applications. Develop a secure method for connecting and communicating with the external device. Integrate biometric authentication into the web authentication flow.</description></item><item><title>Demo: Magic Links</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-magic-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-magic-links/</guid><description>Implement a &amp;lsquo;Magic Link&amp;rsquo; system for passwordless authentication:
Develop an email-based authentication system where users receive a unique, time-sensitive link to log in. Ensure the security of the magic link generation and verification process.</description></item><item><title>Demo: QR Code based Login</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/demo-qr-code-based-login/</guid><description>Create a QR code-based login system for easy and secure access to web applications:
Design the QR code generation and scanning process. Implement a secure system for QR code validation and user authentication.</description></item><item><title>Implement a rust game through WASM</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implement-a-rust-game-through-wasm/</guid><description> Design a simple game concept suitable for implementation in Rust. Develop the game logic and user interface in Rust. Compile and optimize the Rust code for WASM. Test game performance and compatibility across various browsers.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a game server on Rust</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/earn/implementing-a-game-server-on-rust/</guid><description>Develop a robust and efficient game server using Rust.
Design the server architecture with a focus on scalability and performance. Implement core server functionalities like player management, real-time communication, and game logic. Test for concurrency and load handling.</description></item><item><title>DuckDB demo and showcase</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/events/duckdb-demo-and-showcase/</guid><description>Event Date Discord Channel Type 23/11/2023 🎙・labs-stage Internal DuckDB has been an emerging OLAP database for analytical needs. Use cases for analytics usually use around 1GB-10GB of data, not enough to take advantage of the full potential of databases in data warehouses. The use case of analyzing data in small chunks is enough to pop up startups such as MotherDuck.
Agenda: DuckDB is a great starting point for modern stacks that don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about scalability, but want to derive hard analytics from the data that they have.</description></item><item><title>How R&amp;D contributes to Performance Review</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/how-rd-contributes-to-performance-review/</guid><description>Our organization values the research and development (R&amp;amp;D) efforts of our team members and aims to incorporate these contributions into performance reviews. It&amp;rsquo;s important that individual R&amp;amp;D activities not only pursue personal growth but also align with our team and organizational objectives.
Key Assessment Factors For R&amp;amp;D activities, there are a few factors will contribute to your performance:
Alignment with Team Objectives: Your research should be aligned with topics identified as crucial for the future growth and success of our team.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Journey</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/knowledge-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/knowledge-journey/</guid><description>Our process for evaluating and integrating technology is designed to be thorough yet efficient, ensuring we adopt only the most effective tools into our operations. It consists of four key stages: Assess, Trial, Adopt, and Hold.
Assess: is the initial state where a technology is being evaluated. The objective is to understand the potential and limitations of the technology before committing more resources. Trial: is where the technology is tested in projects.</description></item><item><title>Labs - New Member Onboarding</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-new-member-onboarding/</guid><description>New members joining our Labs team can be recommended either personally by an existing team member or through a development plan survey. Once onboarded, each new member is paired with a mentor who provides guidance on our operational practices within the team, specifically in relation to a chosen research topic. The initial probation period for new members is set to one month.
During this probation, we expect two main deliverables from the new team member:</description></item><item><title>Labs - Topic proposal &amp; progress tracking</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-topic-proposal-progress-tracking/</guid><description>Selecting the right R&amp;amp;D topics is crucial for our organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Currently, we are inviting topic proposals specifically from members of our labs, consulting and operation teams. These team members are chosen for their deep understanding of our business and their ability to envision the application of new technologies.
Recording and Prioritizing Topics Our Labs team&amp;rsquo;s key members will prioritize the proposed topics. These selected topics should be recorded on Basecamp within the Research project Hillchart.</description></item><item><title>Labs Roadmap (Nov 23 update)</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-roadmap-nov-23-update/</guid><description>In a recent collaborative discussion between key members of the Labs and Consulting teams, we&amp;rsquo;ve made decisive strides in pinpointing key topics and potential projects for development. Each topic is paired with specific challenges to ensure we engage deeply with the technology, understanding its practical applications. The focal point for the coming month is WebAssembly (WASM), alongside a range of exciting use-cases we plan to implement and demonstrate.
Our discussions have led to the identification of several intriguing topics, each with its own set of challenges.</description></item><item><title>Labs x Consulting Workflow</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/labs-x-consulting-workflow/</guid><description>This workflow consolidates how new tech is introduced through the Labs team and how it gets processed to Consulting team to apply for projects and bring awareness of our tech expertise.
Labs:
Be able to introduce new tech to help enrich our engineers’ expertise Be able to understand what tech is trending and how we can use them Consulting:
Be able understand landscape of tech expertise across engineers Be able to use our engineer’s tech expertise in helping to get new deals Operations:</description></item><item><title>Reward Model &amp; Nomination</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/labs/reward-model-nomination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/labs/reward-model-nomination/</guid><description>Our Tech Labs is a hub of continuous learning and application of advanced technologies. This program is designed to celebrate contributions at various levels, from enhancing knowledge to contributing to business growth.
Reward Levels Level 1: Knowledge Enrichment
Eligibility: Team members enriching our knowledge base with notes, analysis, or demonstrations. Reward: Between 10 to 50 ICY Level 2: Project Application
Eligibility: Those implementing new technologies or solutions in projects, whether internal, open-source, or client-focused.</description></item></channel></rss>