<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Remote on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/remote/</link><description>Recent content in Remote on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/remote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make Remote Working Works</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/make-remote-working-works/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/make-remote-working-works/</guid><description>Being office-present keeps you effective. Firms lean on that. It explains why companies are down to invest a fortune on building creative office with other benefit packages. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about that. I&amp;rsquo;m just saying there are others ways to keep people excited without costing too much operation cost.
The Dwarves lives with some principles. First, we feel no need to manage your chairs. We have better things to do with our time.</description></item><item><title>Remote Prepare And Get Going</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-prepare-and-get-going/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/remote-prepare-and-get-going/</guid><description>Checklist What is woking remotely Why to work remotely When to work Where to work Setup &amp;amp; Tooling Performance Review Philosophy With the deeply understanding that WORK - LIFE BALANCE is the real shit. We decided to pick this style of Remote Working as a main way to work for the whole company. And everyone can choose to follow it or not. It’s optional but highly recommended.
We believe that a happy person can deliver 10x quality output compared to others.</description></item><item><title>Blocking Distraction</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blocking-distraction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/blocking-distraction/</guid><description>Finding solitude in information overwhelming world
Nowadays, we are connected 247, every minute passes by there are new things happens, new notifications, endless distractions. Sometimes, it is too hard to focus and it affect our life quality a lot.
So there are couple things that we can do to avoid this problem.
Spend time to be alone everyday It can be 1–2 hours and you can truly focus on what ready matter.</description></item><item><title>Effective Meeting</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/effective-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/effective-meeting/</guid><description>To increase flexibility in how and where employees at Dwarves work, we agree on a shared set of constraints for group work and meetings.
Meeting Etiquette Meetings start on time
If you&amp;rsquo;re leading a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to start the meeting on time. If you&amp;rsquo;re attending a meeting, you are responsible for showing up on time.
Meetings happen in regular hours
All team members should make themselves available for face-to-face meetings between 10:30am - 1:00p, as long as they are scheduled at least 24 hours in advance.</description></item><item><title>Our Policy For Remote Working</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-policy-for-remote-working/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/our-policy-for-remote-working/</guid><description>Some useful practices we adopted to keep the remote working system goes smoothly.
This policy is written in the context of our current company setup. Specifically, this document addresses working from home on a regular basis. It goes valid for
A full-remote team. Individuals that manages and responsible for their work. Even when we aren&amp;rsquo;t in the office, our teammates are still counting on us and it is our responsibility to make sure we are exceeding their expectations.</description></item></channel></rss>