<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>_base on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in _base on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2024 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>November Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-november-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>October Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-october-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-october-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of October, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been for the most part very exciting, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;Full-stack engineering’ Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is prolific and always true: Open-source.
Open-source has always been the foundation for many hobby projects, learning experiences, startups, and enterprises. It has stayed true to the idea for the rights to use, study, change, and distribute the software and its source code to anyone and for any purpose - originally helping to fix bugs and later accelerating state-of-the-art tech and AI.</description></item><item><title>The stage of Growth at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/growth-stages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/growth-stages/</guid><description>Hello, It’s Han &amp;amp; Nikki.
Since you last heard from us, we have been going through a lot of changes. There are both good changes and so-so changes. In this update, we are excited to share the real journey of growth and transformation that our team has embarked upon, as we continue to strive to become a more skilled and knowledgable software team.
Shifting focus towards techniques Going full-stack engineering Growing a support system for the community Building stronger bonds through collaboration Nurturing relationships for shared success Shifting focuses towards techniques It’s a bold decision the team has taken.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering August 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-august-2023/</guid><description>As we step into the exciting opportunities of August, we are at a crucial point in the ever-changing world of technology. Our adventure until now has been incredibly thrilling, with a strong focus on &amp;lsquo;LLM in Production.&amp;rsquo; Now, we shift our attention to a topic that is always important and never outdated: Fullstack Engineering.
In a world where new businesses and product teams are always changing, there is a high demand for engineers who are skilled in many areas and can handle both sides of the development process.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering June 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-june-2023/</guid><description>As we usher in the month of June, we embrace the ever-changing landscape of technological innovation, recognizing that every twist and turn propels us forward into a world of limitless possibilities. We continue to chart our course through this vast expanse, driven by a mission to remain at the forefront of our industry and deliver unparalleled value to our clients. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we reflect on our achievements and share our visions for the future, focusing on a central theme: &amp;ldquo;LLM in Production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering May 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-may-2023/</guid><description>The technological landscape is vast, brimming with opportunities for exploration and growth. As we stand on the brink of May, we pause to reflect on our journey thus far and chart our course forward. In this month&amp;rsquo;s report, we bring you the fruit of our endeavors and the promise of our vision.
Tech Radar As we advance into a new phase, our engineering team is setting its sights on a new strategic focus - &amp;ldquo;Exploring Large Language Models (LLM)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering March 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-march-2023/</guid><description>At the intersection of technology and innovation, our engineering team at Dwarves Foundation has been driving change and pushing boundaries. As we continue to navigate the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, we remain steadfast in our commitment to seeking out the latest technologies and practices to deliver exceptional results.
With our eyes fixed firmly on the future, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated an engineering culture that values continuous learning and collaboration. Through initiatives like our Tech Radar, Brainery, and R&amp;amp;D challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ve created opportunities for our team to learn, grow, and share their knowledge with the wider community.</description></item><item><title>December Forward Engineering 2023</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-december-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-december-2023/</guid><description>This month, we have focused on revamping how we learn, familiarize, and work with tech. We are excited to announce that we have updated our Forward Engineering to better reflect the feedback and insights from our Labs team, Operations Team, and Consulting Team.
This is to hopefully provide you with a more comprehensive publication that not only keeps you informed about the latest technologies and where they are applied, but also foster collaboration and innovation within our organization.</description></item><item><title>Forward Engineering Year 2022</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/forward-engineering-year-2022/</guid><description>What is Learning at Dwarves? At Dwarves Foundation, we believe that learning is one of the most important aspects of any organization. We also believe in creating a culture that fosters learning and innovation.
We want to demonstrate and encourage individual and organizational learning, where both gaining and sharing knowledge is prioritized, valued, and rewarded. Learning is an ongoing process that never ends in our fast-moving industry. The concept of continued learning at Dwarves Foundation has become synonymous with having a growth mindset — a belief in your own ability to change or grow through experience or study.</description></item><item><title>The Next Leading Chairs</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/the-next-leading-chairs/</guid><description>OUR VISION FOR GROWTH Last Jan 2020, we got the chance to celebrate our first milestone - Dwarves Foundation reached 5 years old. The remarkable moment contained the proudest thing we delivered.
**Remote Culture - **That enables us to make things work without any physical constraints. We were able to focus on what we value: Knowledge and People. To name a few: The Handbook** **- To demonstrate our culture, the future we pursue and what portrays the Dwarves.</description></item><item><title>The future is blockchain and data</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/blockchain-and-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/blockchain-and-data/</guid><description>It’s Han and Nikki here,
Plus an extra fresh voice we’re bringing to Dwarves Updates, in hope we can offer you more engineering-related insights and thoughts.
If you’re a part of our Discord server, you probably have noticed #blockchain is our most busy channel. It’s partially because of all the fusses within the crypto scene, but mainly because we’re aggressively learning, experimenting, and evolving on our blockchain expertise.
The data study group is also getting exciting.</description></item><item><title>The stages of hiring at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/hiring-stages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/hiring-stages/</guid><description>Hey,
It’s Han and Nikki, back in your inbox for another Dwarves Updates.
First, we are delighted to share that Dwarves placed top 100 in the Financial Times’ Asia-Pacific High-Growth Company.
When we hustle daily, sometimes we forget to look back and pat ourselves in the back. This achievement serves as a reminder that we’re pretty darn good at what we’re doing.
Huge appreciation to our team, alongside our friends and partners, we’re lucky to have you move along with us.</description></item><item><title>It’s a wrap: 2021 in Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/2021-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/2021-in-review/</guid><description>Hey, it’s Han and Nikki in your inbox again. On behalf of the entire Dwarves team, happy 2022!
For us 2021 is eventful, and memorable. It was full of changes and challenges, but our can-do mindset made us gritty. While we didn’t have all the answers, we decided to just try and do. As we state in our Agile Minifesto: fail fast, learn often, and it&amp;rsquo;s okay to start over.</description></item><item><title>Engineering organizational structure</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineering-org-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineering-org-structure/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. We&amp;rsquo;re almost at the end of this year. While we know everyone is busy wrapping up 2021, we hope you&amp;rsquo;re taking care of yourself and staying safe.
Remember last month when we mentioned refining our engineering ladder? Executing this one initiative was our main focus for the whole November. With this new way of looking at growth, we hope to be able to expand the team on top of a scalable foundation.</description></item><item><title>The path to growth at Dwarves</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/path-to-growth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/path-to-growth/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. We&amp;rsquo;re here with the fifth edition of our Dwarves Updates. October has been a wild ride for us as a company. Most of our effort was spent on rethinking growth paths for our engineers.
The common scenarios with growth for engineers Growth is pretty easy during the first few years; conquer technical skills, discover tools and become proficient in using them, getting things done better and faster.</description></item><item><title>Engineer Performance Review</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineer-performance-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/engineer-performance-review/</guid><description>Greetings,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and Nikki from Team Dwarves. Time does fly when we get to do something we love. As we keep working on building up the team and producing codes for our clients, we didn&amp;rsquo;t even notice it&amp;rsquo;s already the end of September. Here&amp;rsquo;s another update from Dwarves for you. Throughout September, we have completed our bi-annual performance review.
How we approach engineer performance review We all have our fair share of performance reviews, be it reviewing others or being reviewed.</description></item><item><title>Project Compliance</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/project-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/project-compliance/</guid><description>Hey,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han &amp;amp; Nikki from Team Dwarves. This email is the third month we share about our journey to Software Craftsmanship. The last two issues were in June and July. And we received quite a little feedback from our friends and past clients. Thanks for supporting.
This month, we share about how we do project delivery compliance.
How we do compliance If there&amp;rsquo;s something that we try to minimize at all costs, it&amp;rsquo;s risks.</description></item><item><title>Da Lat Office</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dalat-office/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dalat-office/</guid><description>Hey,
It&amp;rsquo;s Han and the Dwarves team again. We work as a borderless software firm by crafting world-class products that bring great impacts for various industries.
Dwarves Updates notes down how we move toward that goal. You&amp;rsquo;re receiving this because we would love to have you as a part of the journey. It contains our lessons learned, our adoption, our investment in the team, and how we turn those experiences into our client&amp;rsquo;s success.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Updates</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dwarves-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/dwarves-updates/</guid><description>Hi, this is Han, the CEO of Dwarves Foundation. This month the Dwarves score 40th client that we have the honor to serve. And for that, we decide to launch the Dwarves Updates.
As we build this company like we build a product, when we think about this approach, we ask different questions: Do people work here know how to use the company? Is it simple? Is it obvious how it works?</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 03</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-03/</guid><description>We started the 1st volume a year ago, mostly about assessing all the tech indexes we have adopted for 5 years. Then we moved to the 2nd volume, where we figured ways to simplify the workflow and complete our project toolkit.
And here we go again, another version of tech radar at Dwarves Foundation. 2021 has just gone through its first quarter, and we&amp;rsquo;ve left with some new toys to trial and see if they create any impact.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 02</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-02/</guid><description>Once every month, we gather for Radar update to round up the cool techs and assess if we should adopt that to the team. Road to a wider and more diversified rings, Dwarves Tech Radar v2 contains the practices to simplify the workflow, new techniques/ approach methods to upgrade our current standards, and **expand the domain knowledge. **
Trial Earthly: The combination Dockerfile + Makefile https://earthly.dev/
A repeatable syntax builds to untangle the debugging process between the local environment and the CI platform.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar Volume 01</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-volume-01/</guid><description>The Dwarves have their tradition to explore the tech scene and learn new things. Dwarves Tech Radar kicked the initial step since January of 2020.
It is the first time we sit down and do it in written form. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard for the engineers at first, but we managed to complete the volume with ten reports.
Besides volume 01, we have an opportunity to sort out our current technology index and put it at https://d.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves Tech Radar The Introduction</title><link>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://memo.d.foundation/newsletter/forward/dwarves-tech-radar-the-introduction/</guid><description>Our Perspective on Technology Technology is eating the world. The technology we used yesterday may be deprecated today. New technology has enabled us to create new things. With the existing set of problems, new solutions will emerge along with new technologies.
Over five years of working as an innovative software firm, other than the energetic tech-savvy workforce, we shape the team day by day with the core values that move towards the engineering culture.</description></item></channel></rss>