<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>case study on Dwarves Foundation</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/tags/case-study/</link><description>Recent content in case study on Dwarves Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 Dwarves Foundation.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.d.foundation/tags/case-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Droppii x Dwarves: Transforming E-Commerce with Innovative Dropshipping Solutions</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/droppii-dwarves-case-study/</guid><description>Industry
E-Commerce
Location
Vietnam and SEA
Business Context
Need for an advanced e-commerce platform to streamline drop shipping operations
Solution
Revamped and technologically advanced online system development by Dwarves Foundation
Outcome
Launch of Droppii for Business v3.0, providing a scalable, user-friendly platform for business clients and enhancing customer interaction
Our Service
Full-Stack Development / Agile Project Management
In brief Droppii, in collaboration with Dwarves Foundation, revamps its e-commerce platform, enhancing dropshipping operations with the launch of Droppii for Business v3.</description></item><item><title>Konvoy X Dwarves</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/konvoy-x-dwarves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/konvoy-x-dwarves/</guid><description>**Industry: **
Logistics, Supply Chain Management
Location:
Australia,
**Business Context: **
An innovative company providing beverage industry with a unique keg rental solution, emphasizing sustainability and ease of use.
Solution:
A tech-driven rental system with real-time keg tracking and analytics ensuring security and transparency.
Outcome:
Increase the operational efficiency and profitability of breweries with a flexible, secure, and eco-friendly keg supply chain.
Our Service:
Product Consulting, Staff Augmentation
In brief Konvoy, a pioneering force in the keg management industry, first surfaced in Australia and New Zealand in October 2019.</description></item><item><title>Cimb Dwarves X Netizen Initiating A Digital Wealth Management Experience</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/cimb-dwarves-x-netizen-initiating-a-digital-wealth-management-experience/</guid><description>Industry
Fintech
Tech stack
MySQL, JAVA Spring Boot, and Angular
Location
South East Asia
Solution
Fast recruiting senior engineers to collaborate with CIMB’s tech team.
Deliver quality and collaboration control through out the project to hit targeted timeline.
Outcome
In charge of the backend foundation, we marked a milestone in CIMB&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation journey, with a streamlined, customer-focused experience contributed to CIMB&amp;rsquo;s forward-looking vision.
Our Service
Tech Consulting, Staff Augmentation</description></item><item><title>A Case Study Interview Into Micro Frontends Building Design System For E Commerce Platform</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-case-study-interview-into-micro-frontends-building-design-system-for-e-commerce-platform/</guid><description>A Case Study Interview into Micro-Frontends: Building Design System for E-commerce Platform Previously on Why Micro-Frontend, we took a look into what is Micro-Frontend architecture, as well as some core concepts behind it. For some of you that have missed the memo, here’s a tl;dr:
Micro frontend architecture is an approach to building web applications by splitting the user interface into smaller, independent, and reusable parts. Each part is owned and developed by a separate team, and they are brought together in the browser to create a single, seamless user experience.</description></item><item><title>Open Fabric Set The Tech Foundation And Built An Mvp From Scratch</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/open-fabric-set-the-tech-foundation-and-built-an-mvp-from-scratch/</guid><description>Founded and led by veterans from fintech players like Paypal &amp;amp; Grab, Open Fabric is a BNPL platform, built to enable an open commerce network for customers and credit providers in South East Asia to radically simplify merchant integrations for digital payment methods.
With a team of 8 engineers, Dwarves helped set the tech foundation and together built an MVP from scratch. Within a year, Dwarves helped ship the system to onboard and configure payment methods for companies to the Open Fabric commerce network.</description></item><item><title>Spike Inu Engineering A Seamless Experience For Cross Chain Swap And Decentralized Exchange</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/spike-inu-engineering-a-seamless-experience-for-cross-chain-swap-and-decentralized-exchange/</guid><description>In brief When blockchain becomes the new tech blockbuster, worldwide blockchain networks such as Ethereum, Polygon, Avalanche, Fantom, or Binance Smart Chance started to develop their own tokens. They all possess the same vision: Empower crypto users to transfer their assets in multiple chains hassle-free and effective. The core engine of those products is building a secured bridging solution between chains, enabling tokens to move back and forth, and transferring tokens on the same network.</description></item><item><title>Hedge Foundation A Customized All In One Trading Platform For Pro Traders</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/hedge-foundation-a-customized-all-in-one-trading-platform-for-pro-traders/</guid><description>In brief Hedge Foundation is a powerful dashboard to support users in managing crypto account positions, balance, PNL and works on bulk orders for profit and loss tracking.
Move alongside the crypto era, Hedge Foundation works to be part of the industry by providing practical tools for crypto users in terms of automating, syncing &amp;amp; managing accounts by utilizing the most out of market database.
Technical Highlight
AG Grid to optimize big table with fast update real-time data.</description></item><item><title>Startupvn</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startupvn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/startupvn/</guid><description>[startup.vn](http://startup.vn/) was founded 10 years ago, when the concept of "startups" was still fairly new in Vietnam. A handful of people from diverse backgrounds joined hands to create a homeland for Vietnamese who aim at building and growing their own businesses. 💡 Fostering innovation and entrepreneurship in Vietnam since 2011.
What started out as a weekend passion project quickly progressed into a strong, proud, aspiring community. 10 years in, startup.</description></item><item><title>Help Momos Team Build An Mvp Shopify For Fb Merchandises In Sg</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/help-momos-team-build-an-mvp-shopify-for-fb-merchandises-in-sg/</guid><description>In brief
Momos is a pre-seed startup operating in Singapore, whose founder was an ex-Grab They look to ship the first MVP with a web platform to test the market and onboard promising users. Our team of 3 join them to bring development timeline up to speed as well as improving the core tech foundation to pave the way for a scalable, future-proof system. The collaboration happens remotely since March 2021.</description></item><item><title>Adopt Blockchain On Netherlands Affiliate Marketing Platform</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/adopt-blockchain-on-netherlands-affiliate-marketing-platform/</guid><description>In brief Attrace is a Netherland decentralized affiliate marketing network that audits action and bridges e-commerce websites to merchants. The core concept is applying referral for different blockchain product use cases They seek to launch MVP for market validation and early user acquisition Our team of 3 join them to contribute to Attrace&amp;rsquo;s core function with custom-made blockchain technology Highlight Blockchain solutions for multiples use-cases Golang for Backend system: Solidity and index blockchain data IPFS as files sharing system GDPR standard for data privacy Fraud detection &amp;amp; verification network The Context Attrace&amp;rsquo;s concept is a marketing platform that helps merchants feature and advertise their products.</description></item><item><title>Supercharged Setel Malaysias First Pay Pump Go Super App</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/supercharged-setel-malaysias-first-pay-pump-go-super-app/</guid><description>In brief First introduced by PETRONAS in 2018, Setel is the first e-payment solution for fuel purchases directly from mobile devices. They head to unlock a bigger market by providing a super-app with on-the-go function and platform integration. Our team of 7 partners to involve in their engineering team in Unified Loyalty Platform, specialized in “Conversion” of new potential users. We focus on deals, vouchers, the front-landing page as well as Marketing tracking &amp;amp; integration.</description></item><item><title>Advancing Us Healthcare Platform Joinpara As Covid 19 Support</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/advancing-us-healthcare-platform-joinpara-as-covid-19-support/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 2019, Para is a platform connecting hospitals with medical professionals. Continuing with Go microservices, we have shipped numerous features, markedly workshift management and candidate screening. We partnered and helped unburden Para from the financial stress during the early stage of their MVP development. Our Covid-19 program was launched in early 2020. We aim to provide software development, technical support for startups and businesses to help them stay stable during and progress forward despite the pandemic.</description></item><item><title>Support Relay In Shipping Their Mvp Product For Us Market Testing</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/support-relay-in-shipping-their-mvp-product-for-us-market-testing/</guid><description>In brief Relay is an extension tool that decreases micromanagement by automating workflows. Relay&amp;rsquo;s first engagement with Dwarves aims to ship their MVP to market as quick as possible for early user acquisition. We dive in with 2 quickly adapt engineers. We keep a stable pace of feature shipment and adjust along with the requirements. Highlights
Slack app &amp;amp; Chrome extension. Custom semantic versioning for chrome extension. Combine flipper, sidekiq for A/B testing and gradually roll out new version.</description></item><item><title>Succeed Naru A Browser Focus Web Extension For Us Market</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/succeed-naru---a-browser-focus-web-extension-for-us-market/</guid><description>In brief Being a digital designer who looks for inspiration and digital trends, Matt hopes for a productivity tool that could lend well to his browsing habit. Matt got in contact with us via a connection of a friend. We were surprised by the opportunity he provides: A browser extension for works management. We did explore web extension - but never had an opportunity for real trial. We take the chance to help bring it to market.</description></item><item><title>From Monolithic To Microservice Sharpen Malaysias Largest Online Marketplace</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/from-monolithic-to-microservice-sharpen-malaysias-largest-online-marketplace/</guid><description>In brief
Mudah.my is a Malaysian 12-years-old online marketplace. A product derives from a partnership between Telenor ASA of Norway and 701Search Singapore. Currently holds 19.8% Internet share, Mudah meets the increase of customers demand, which led to an overload in the current system. We partnered to help migrating the monolithic architecture into microservices - Unlocking a scalable and feature-extendable platform We spent a month working on-site at Malaysia to directly participate in the work and speed up productivity Technical Highlight Massive migration from monolithic to microservice architecture.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration With Uk Residential Cloud Based Paas</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/collaboration-with-uk-residential-cloud-based-paas/</guid><description>In brief Founded in 1997 and has having 22 years in the market, Reapit is the largest CRM and Client Accounting software provider to the UK residential real estate sector. Reapit got acquired by Accel KKR in 2017 - which powered them to accelerate their growth and innovation potential in products and technology expansion Reapit wants to migrate the app from desktop-based to Cloud-based. They want to develop a PaaS to support an expandability for SME customer.</description></item><item><title>The Development Journey With Aharooms Vietnam Hospitality Growth Solutions</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/the-development-journey-with-aharooms---vietnam-hospitality-growth-solutions/</guid><description>In brief Aharooms wants to be a remarkable Vietnamese brand in franchised hotel chains. They look to enter the affordable hotel market to support business owners. Their vision was to build an MVP for market testing in no time. Aharooms&amp;rsquo;s system had almost 2 years in development. It demands high effort to balance new feature development with technical debt. We step in as product team and venture builder. We take on the development stage that supercharges their product development.</description></item><item><title>A Web Based Cloud Tool Developed In Partnership With Google</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/a-web-based-cloud-tool-developed-in-partnership-with-google/</guid><description>In brief CJC Ptd is a 20-year expert in providing market data consultancy &amp;amp; professional services for global financial sector. They want to make a new data ecosystem: Public and private cloud, containerization, software orchestration, AI to support the growth of DevOps We team up with them to develop Voconic - a cloud PaaS for CJC’s clients, aiming to make cloud deployment seamless across cloud providers and environment. Technical Highlight Backend, Frontend and CLI tools are built from scratch by engineers specialized in Cloud development Golang heavy backend integrated with Google Cloud Platform for 1-click deployment experience Deep integration with multiple cloud providers (Google &amp;amp; AWS) Complex system auto-deployment and configuration function CLI support for repetitive tasks and complex operation Separated services for file upload.</description></item><item><title>Digitalize Dental Marketplace The Singapore Dentistry Operation Process</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/digitalize-dental-marketplace---the-singapore-dentistry-operation-process/</guid><description>In brief Founded by Desmond Goh - a Singaporean dental surgeon, Dental Marketplace is an online platform for dental professionals to stay active in dentistry and simplify operation process. Web and App development as MVP release for marketing testing and user feedback. We support them with tech solution and market-fit product design. We work according with Desmond to extract business problem and propose suitable solution. Technical Highlight Product-fit Design: Design Thinking Method &amp;amp; Design UX research for Golang-backend: Steady and microservices-extendable system Startup-centric: Scalable system &amp;amp; cost-efficient solution Microservice architecture Agile process and Scrum framework for product iteration The Context Singapore dentists faces bottlenecks to practice dentistry and operates dental clinic with SDC rules licensed regulated by MOH.</description></item><item><title>Augmented Begroup Team To Deliver Becorporate Services</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/augmented-begroup-team-to-deliver-becorporate-services/</guid><description>In brief Getting the early funding for over 40M US dollar, beGroup focuses to roll out all 4 products by the end of 2018. By that time, there were only 6 months before the debut. beCorporate is a module to manage and optimize in-house business transports for employee.
They look to ship in short timeline. The current engineering team was working on the 1st release of ride-hailing app. Wrap-up beCorporate adds a step in perfecting their service.</description></item><item><title>Building Airwatt Apply Aiml For Iot Solutions To Optimize Electricity Usage</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/building-airwatt---apply-aiml-for-iot-solutions-to-optimize-electricity-usage/</guid><description>In brief AirWatt is an IoT solution that integrates and monitors electricity usage using AI/ML. AirWatt&amp;rsquo;s vision is to help businesses track electric usage status of electrical equipment. Hence, they can save electricity and money, even avoid disaster. They seek for product development support, with insight on business to provide suitable product design The MVP must be done fast to prove the product&amp;rsquo;s concept. We built Airwatt system from zero with other teams: Business, Hardware, and AI.</description></item><item><title>Bhd Cinema Redesign Bhds Booking Ticket App</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/bhd-cinema-redesign-bhds-booking-ticket-app/</guid><description>Introduction BHD is one of the biggest cinema chains in Vietnam with hundreds of thousands tickets sold monthly. However, its mobile application is a complete drawback; users cannot book tickets online, it feels and looks outdated, inconsistent and cluttered.
Mission BHD’s new app covers all the basic needs of movie-goers, in an intuitive and pleasant way. Meaning, users can easily scan screening schedules, view movie details and book tickets online.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 1</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-1/</guid><description>Introduction The following case study is my first app design project. In this project, I have gone through the design process, including interviews, analysis, user flows, wireframes, prototyping, and user testing.
The mobile app Sol is a travel app focused on some highlight features: planning trips, managing members and expenses, and tracking/sharing location. In facts, when traveling by groups, we often face some troubles: getting lost, confusing with plans, hard-communicating and the most challenging thing: managing expenses.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 3</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-3/</guid><description>Introduction Today we shall continue our series of designing “Sol-Travel Planning” app. As we mentioned our process on UX research and UI design in the last two articles, Sol’s target users are the young so keeping the app fun with interaction is a must.
Main Motions According to Issara Willenskomer from UxinMotion, motion implementation in UX design can greatly help improving usability in four noticeable ways: fulfilling expectation from the users, maintaining continuity among a set of scenes, inventing narrative — story-telling flow throughout the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Sol Travel Planning App Part 2</title><link>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@d.foundation (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://note.d.foundation/memo/sol-travel-planning-app---part-2/</guid><description>Following the previous article on UX case study of Sol — Travel App, an app that was tailored to meet the needs of groups on traveling days. In this article, we will describe our creative process of the UI for it. We choose iOS as our platform to be presented, considering that it is the more favored devices being used.
As we have gone through the UX research tasks in the last article, we started brainstorming about how the mobile application should look.</description></item></channel></rss>